<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Alex Guinman - Italy</title>
      <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au</link>
      <description>Personal blog</description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/italy/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Venezia</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-venezia/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-venezia/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-venezia/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;p1040894.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Me in Venice&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming into Venice was pretty exciting, especially when the train finally got past the mainland and we were on a bridge, heading out to sea and the island of Venice. My first impression wasn&amp;#39;t that great to be honest, I expected it to be cooler. The view from the train station wasn&amp;#39;t particularly dazzling and it wasn&amp;#39;t until a bit later that we got to see places that were more like my expectations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting around Venice sucks. It is in fact, not actually an island, but rather lots of little islands joined together by bridges. So while our Hotel wasn&amp;#39;t that far from the train station, it was still an effort to get there. When we finally get to the Hotel we find it closed, with a sign out the front saying that reception is only open until 2pm. It&amp;#39;s only 2.10 so we ring the doorbell a few times and eventually someone comes out, lets us in and gives us a key. The hotel itself was great (especially the view out the window of a canal), but the service was ... non-existent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After dumping our luggage, the stairs weren&amp;#39;t so frustrating and we got to explore the city. Unfortunately, there isn&amp;#39;t much too it. It&amp;#39;s just shops, shops and more shops. Oh and some B&amp;amp;B&amp;#39;s and Restaurants. Regardless, it&amp;#39;s such a different experience to be somewhere with canals instead of streets so we were content with walking around aimlessly and looking at abandoned buildings that had water lapping against the front doors.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;floating-door.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;P1040896.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We set out to find a supermarket, but after a lot of looking, we still couldn&amp;#39;t find one. We headed back to the train station in the hope there would be one there, and found a shop inside that had some very pricey pasta and pasta sauce, that would need to do. It was Italian pasta at least. We also bought a bottle of &amp;quot;Grappa&amp;quot; (looked like red wine but with some grapes still in the bottle of the bottle) that was 12 euro and 40% alcohol and came in an awesome looking bottle to go with our meal. We asked the cashier what it tasted like, but she was no help as didn&amp;#39;t speak English. Another lady told us it tasted nothing like red wine but that it was good.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;dinner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After cooking up our epic dinner, we discovered that trying the local cuisine isn&amp;#39;t always a good thing. The pasta was okay, nothing special, but the Grappa was absolutely disgusting. I managed to finish my glass for the sake of not wasting it, but Rachael couldn&amp;#39;t handle more than one sip. Even watering it down didn&amp;#39;t help. We talked to some people about it later, and it turns out that while a lot of Italians do drink it straight, most sane people only use it in cooking. Thanks lady at the shop that said it was nice. Rachael wanted to pour it all down the sink, but we ended it up leaving it in the room and told reception they could have it when we checked out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On DAY 2 we set out to find St. Marco Square, as we had a walking tour there in the afternoon and had no idea where it was. The city is like a maze, and eventually we found it after heading who knows where on the island. Luckily there was lots of cool things to see on the way, such as areas of the island that were flooded because it was high-tide. The actual square itself was flooded too when we found it, and it appeared like the church would be too, but when we went back that afternoon we saw that it was designed a bit better so the entrance was higher than the water level and acted as a barrier to stop it coming in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;flood1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;flood2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stumbled across a supermarket at last, and got some MUCH cheaper pasta and some wine that was in English and we knew we would like. Rachael was over the trying Italian wine phase until I showed her the prices, at which point she quickly changed her mind. It took ages to get home as the city really is a maze, and there is no such things as shortcuts because most streets come to dead-ends if there isn&amp;#39;t a bridge to let you cross at the end, making our attempt at shortcuts into massive detours.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our attempt at home-cooked Italian cuisine was much better this time, and the pasta was delicious. More walking BACK to the square afterwards for our walking tour made us pretty excited for the opportunity to sit and a Gondola and do nothing. The walking tour was fairly interesting, but there wasn&amp;#39;t a whole lot to see besides a cool looking spiral staircase building. We learnt a few things about the island though, most important being that basically nobody lives there anymore, it&amp;#39;s just full of tourists. All the locals moved out to neighboring islands and just come in for work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;staircase.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gondola ride at the end of our tour was great, it started off boring as we went along for a bit in the sea first, but once we were going through all the little canals it was really cool. We then had to walk back to our hotel yet again, and I think Rachael worked it out later that we did about 16km of walking that day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;gondola.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 16560337 &amp;gt;}}&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On DAY 3 we had to walk to the Square yet again to go on a Boat trip to 3 of the surrounding islands. While we were waiting they were setting up for the Venice marathon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first island we went to was Murano, where we got to see how glass was made. It was incredible to watch and I had no idea how much skill would be needed to do it. Check out the video of the guy making a horse sculpture.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 16560205 &amp;gt;}}&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop was to Burano, which is famous for lace making. Unlike glass making, lace is really boring. The island itself was still pretty cool though as all the houses were painted different bright colours. We saw a church tower that was leaning, and discovered that in the absence of having cars, the young hooligans put the fully sick sub-woofers in their boats. It was strange situation in which we heard the doof doof of a Kate Perry song as some young guy drove past in his tinny.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-venezia&#x2F;Burano.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third island was Torcello, which we had been warned by our walking tour guide the day before was a boring, ugly island... and indeed it was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we came back the marathon was on, but we didn&amp;#39;t have time to watch as we had to race back the hotel and grab our luggage. Luckily we got back just on 2, and were able to grab our stuff. I still think that it&amp;#39;s crazy that there would only be someone there until 2 in the afternoon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took our luggage to the train station and paid to have them stored there so we didn&amp;#39;t have to carry them around, and set out to find some food. We saw a sign for McDonalds and thought it would be a good place to spend a while without getting kicked out but spent ages looking and never found it. It then started to rain so we went to another restaurant, had some lunch then went back to the train station. It continued to rain and be freezing as we waited a few hours for our train. Our train was meant to leave at 7 but we stayed in the station for a good hour or so due to &amp;quot;technical difficulties&amp;quot; before finally leaving Italy behind and heading onward to Paris.....&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Firenze</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-firenze/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-firenze/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-firenze/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-firenze&#x2F;p1040846.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Florence&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We start our story of Florence at first with the train journey. We got to meet a diverse range of people during the trip. Immediately opposite Rachael and I was a British couple. I don&amp;#39;t think I heard the girl say a word during the whole journey. She sat there for the whole trip with headphones in ear, basically ignoring our existence. The guy was a polar opposite, extremely chatty and engaged us in conversation for the entire trip. They were headed to Venice so that he could compete in the Venice Marathon, and like us, where stopping at Florence on the way. It was a fairly interesting conversation, one point worth mentioning was &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.signonsandiego.com&#x2F;uniontrib&#x2F;20060917&#x2F;news_1t17castle.html&quot;&gt;a castle he told us&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about that is being built in France. Also on the train, was a bishop from Australia, who had been in Rome to see the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.abc.net.au&#x2F;news&#x2F;stories&#x2F;2010&#x2F;10&#x2F;18&#x2F;3040655.htm&quot;&gt;canonization of Mary MacKillop&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I think the fact that we were Australian&amp;#39;s in Rome in that week made him assume we were on a Pilgrimage or something, because he asked if we knew some priest-guy from Rocky (who Rachael actually did). We were also stumped by questions he had about Australian news, which I have only vaguely been keeping up with and Rachael had been busy studying for exams. As such we left a very bad impression of our awareness of current affairs. The countryside we went past was also lovely, so all in all it was a pleasant journey and we were glad to be leaving Rome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we arrived in Florence, we immediately agreed that the city was much nicer. The streets were cleaner, less crowded and there was just a generally better atmosphere. Our hostel was much nicer, and directly opposite the massive Cathedral in the centre of the city.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked around the city for a bit, and found ourselves at the massive &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Boboli_Gardens&quot;&gt;Boboli Gardens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. After Rachael eventually convinced me to part with 10 euro to get into the gardens we had a wonderful time exploring the absolutely massive grounds filled with random statues and trees that we had never seen before. There was some that looked like gum trees (but weren&amp;#39;t obviously), and we even found olive trees and a tree that had dropped walnuts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-firenze&#x2F;gardens.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For DAY 2 we had a walking tour booked, which was okay but nothing special. In the morning there was an absolutely freezing wind and so a lot of the tour was spent trying to find a spot in the sun along the way. We saw everything we had seen the day before again, but learnt a little bit of history about them this time. After seeing the replica of the Statue of David for the 2nd time on the tour, we didn&amp;#39;t see the need to pay to go inside and see the original when it finished, so we instead decided to pay to climb to the dome of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Florence_Cathedral&quot;&gt;the Duomo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-firenze&#x2F;statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-firenze&#x2F;bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The painting on the inside of the Dome was amazing, and it was incredible how much detail went into a painting so high off the floor. The parts of the painting in heaven was pretty boring but the drawings of what happened to people in hell was intense and pretty funny.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-firenze&#x2F;dome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Rachael may have some sort of heart condition, because she was basically dead by the time we got to the top (to be fair it was 463 stairs), but once she had recovered we got to take in the magnificent view of the city. The railing&#x2F;fence appeared to be a fairly new addition, so whoever built the cathedral was clearly crazy and had a death wish, as it is a long way up. Who knows how many people must have died to build it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-firenze&#x2F;view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, there wasn&amp;#39;t anything particularly exciting in Florence, but it had a nice atmosphere and cool buildings and we found it to be much more enjoyable than Rome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning were back at the train station, waiting to head onwards to Venice.......&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Milano</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-milano/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-milano/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-milano/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-milano&#x2F;p1040765.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Milan&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Euro Trip started in Turgi on Saturday morning... and it was raining and cold. Got a train to Zürich where it was also raining, and waited for my train to Milan.
Once on the train things got better, and eventually we got away from the rain and up into the Alps. I was sitting next to a lady from Berlin and her daughter and they were pretty cool to talk to. The girl didn&amp;#39;t speak very good English, and I don&amp;#39;t speak very good German so we got to have some not very good conversations, but it was pretty fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to see the second Swiss person give the finger in my travels. This guy on the train didn&amp;#39;t have a ticket (I think that&amp;#39;s what was happening - they were arguing in Italian) so the ticket lady had this argument with him, which really escalated and I&amp;#39;m pretty sure she told him she had called the police to get him at the next station. Then at the next station they both got off and she gave him the finger and he walked away. I think it was the first sort of argument&#x2F;fight I have seen in Switzerland, although we were basically in Italy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also crazy was the noticeable difference from the Swiss side of the border to the Italian side. Basically on the Swiss side there was small, quaint, neat houses and then 3 mins later as we crossed the border there was derelict rundown Italian buildings covered in graffiti that appeared to have been neglected for the last 10 years or so. It was just so striking how close the two towns were but how different they looked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same can&amp;#39;t be said for Milan. The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Milano_Centrale_railway_station&quot;&gt;train station&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Milan was epic. It had massive ceilings with large stone columns, and was just generally an impressive building.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside the train station was a different matter, and stepping outside you could see that Milan was a modern city. It was basically like the city centre of Brisbane, lots of skyrises and nothing particularly cool to see. After spending what was probably a good hour or so finding a map, I worked out which way the Duomo was and headed towards it. It wasn&amp;#39;t that far to walk, but with luggage with me it was a very annoying walk. I hadn&amp;#39;t done any research on Milan so didn&amp;#39;t really know what I was looking for, but walked into the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Galleria_Vittorio_Emanuele_II&quot;&gt;Galleria Vittorio Emanuele II&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&amp;quot; which had a massive glass dome roof. Then out into the plaza which had the craziest looking church, the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Milan_Cathedral&quot;&gt;Duomo di Milano&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Again, having luggage ruined the experience because I wasn&amp;#39;t allowed inside the church with it. But it was still cool to see from the outside. Then I went for a further walk and found the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Castello_Sforzesco&quot;&gt;Castello Sforzesco&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&amp;quot; which was pretty cool, but again it was hard to explore and look around too much with a suitcase with me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage it looked like it was going to rain and would get dark soon, so I started heading back to the train station. At one point a police chase went past, maybe they were chasing the mafia... there was about 4 or 5 cop cars with sirens blaring. It started raining basically as I got there at about 6.30pm, and then later on started pouring. It then got really cold once it got dark and I had to put on my new ski jacket that I bought, but even then it was still freezing. So then I had to wait in the cold train station for 6 hours or so for my train to Rome and the train station seemed a lot less awesome then when I first got there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One interesting thing happened at about 10. I&amp;#39;m not sure what exactly was going on, but I walked past this homeless guy on the ground that was going crazy on an umbrella, bending all the metal rods and snapping them. Everybody nearby then grabbed there umbrellas and left. So I&amp;#39;m not sure if it was his or someone else&amp;#39;s. Was bizarre to watch, but I then left as well because this guy was clearly one angry homeless dude.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the train finally boarded, I was pretty impressed that we actually got a sort of bed. The seat rests had been folded back and a sheet put down so the 3 seats became a bed, and another bed was folded down up top. Then some creepy looking Mexican guy came in and I was reminded of the scene on the train in the movie Euro Trip and got a little concerned. But then I think he either was in the wrong compartment or didn&amp;#39;t have a ticket because when the ticket inspector came around he left (they were talking in Spanish or Italian so I didn&amp;#39;t know what exactly was going on). Then a young Swiss&#x2F;Italian guy came in who was pretty cool and I had a chat to him. The actual trip itself was okay, not amazing because it&amp;#39;s hard to sleep on a train when it bumps around and makes so much noise, but was certainly a good way to travel that saves on accommodation and time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then basically slept until I got to Rome........&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Roma</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-roma/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-roma/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-roma/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-roma&#x2F;p1040803.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rome&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after waking up and waiting for the train to arrive, we stopped at Roma Tiburtina Station. It was not what I was expecting at all for the capital city of Italy.
The train station had several homeless inhabitants, and smelt a bit funky. My plan had been to walk to Roma Termini Station to meet Rachael about an hour later, but there was no signage as to what direction anything was. After looking around aimlessly the sun finally came up a bit higher, and now knowing which direction was North, I started to head in the general direction of Rachael&amp;#39;s train station.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once away from the train station a bit, I got a better idea of where I was (had a map on my iPod) and managed to find my way to the station with plenty of time to meet Rachael. Once we were reunited, I next task was to find our Hostel. Neither Rachael or I had brought directions, so we were forced to go off my very vague memory that it was only 2 streets from the station, although which streets I couldn&amp;#39;t remember. After walking through several streets with luggage in tow, we FINALLY found our Hostel and were able to dump our gear. By the time we had carried our luggage up the two flights of stairs to reception, Rachael had almost had a heart attack and died. We used the lift from then on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our luggage no longer in the way, we set out to explore the city. Around each new corner we would find something interesting and old-looking to discover and after walking past a couple of ruins we made our way towards the Colosseum and the forum. After a quick look, we decided to come back another day and continued exploring the city on foot, heading towards a field that we later found out was the place where chariot races were held, were there was a festival taking place in which people were re-enacting something and in old-time Roman gear.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stumbled into some &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Santa_Maria_in_Aracoeli&quot;&gt;amazing church&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that was basically all gold (maybe not but it blinded you with extravagance). I wish I could have filmed Rachael&amp;#39;s face as her jaw just dropped and stayed dropped for about 5mins. Then we got an elevator up to the top of the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Monument_to_Vittorio_Emanuele_II&quot;&gt;Giant White Monstrosity&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&amp;quot; which was next door.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-roma&#x2F;church.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More walking around the city, we found somewhere to have lunch. 2 shitty overpriced pizzas later and we continued on our journey, this time walking to the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Trevi_Fountain&quot;&gt;Trevi Fountain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which was a pretty rad fountain that I had never heard of, much to Rachael&amp;#39;s dismay. Apparently it&amp;#39;s in &amp;quot;a million different movies&amp;quot; but I imagine they are mostly all chick-flicks. The area itself was packed with other tourists, and so we left as soon as possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found near the train station an area where artists were selling paintings, most of which were incredible and we got to see some art for free that was better than most of the stuff we saw in museums.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went back to our semi-dodgy hostel for some sleep. The room itself was nice, just the fact that the the shower and toilet was in the same cubicle and there idea of &amp;quot;breakfast included&amp;quot; means providing bread and jam every day was dodgy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAY 2 in Rome, we went on a &amp;quot;Hop-on Hop-off Tour&amp;quot; which is a open top bus that drives you around the city. We also took a boat up the river as part of the deal, but it was a pretty boring river really. After getting a glimpse of the front of the Vatican, which still had posters and stuff up from the canonization the day before, we headed back on the bus to visit the Colosseum.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-roma&#x2F;bus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Colosseum, some lady offered us a skip-the-line tour which we paid for and went on. Our guide was really good and told us all kinds of facts about the games, and related it back to modern times. The actual Colosseum itself is much smaller than I expected, but was still a pretty cool building and must have been incredible back when it was built.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our tour we also got to see the forum, this time with a different guide, who was also good. We learnt that after the Roman Empire fell, the city dropped back to a tiny population and most of the ancient city was used as a dump and buried. When Napoleon came along a few hundred years ago, he saw the top of an arc of triumph that had &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;File:Roman.forum.%26.arch.of.septimius.rome.arp.jpg&quot;&gt;a door cut into it&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a guy doing haircuts inside. He thought that it was disgusting that the former greatest city in the world had been turned into a dump, and after that they started digging up the city, and what we saw was only 2% of the original city. Most of it is still underground but because they have built on top of it they aren&amp;#39;t allowed to boot people out of their homes on the off chance there is some epic statue underneath it. There was also a church with a floating door that you couldn&amp;#39;t enter, because they built the church on top of an older building and when they dug everything back to the original height and uncovered the building below the door of the church is way higher.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-roma&#x2F;forum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end the guide told us about a night tour that he was doing, but when we went to the meeting point later he never showed up. So then we just went home. On the way we had another go and trying to get some authentic Italian cuisine and found a nicer looking restaurant where we got some Angry Spaghetti and Quattro Fromage Pizza. Unlike the day before, these tasted pretty amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-roma&#x2F;map.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also got the bus past some sort of movie premier for an Italian movie that we had seen lots of posters for, but we didn&amp;#39;t know any of the actors so we didn&amp;#39;t really care.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAY 3 saw us leaving Italy for the morning and entering the Vatican City, which I didn&amp;#39;t realise is actually a country to itself. The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Vatican_Museum&quot;&gt;Vatican museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was simply incredible, and the reason is that everything cool in Rome was stolen by the church and is in that museum. St Peter&amp;#39;s Basilica is basically ancient Rome because they stole all the expensive marble and gold etc. from the Colosseum and pantheon and what not to build it, which is why the city is now ruins and the forum was turned into a dump. There was rooms and rooms of statues and tapestries and everything you could think of, and every room had incredible artworks on the walls and ceilings, with intricate tile mosaics on the floor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A special type of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Porphyry_%28geology%29&quot;&gt;purple marble&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was used for a tonne of Statues, and our guide told us that the Vatican owns something like 90% of of this marble in existence. By far my favourite part of the museum was the Raphael Rooms and in particular, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_School_of_Athens&quot;&gt;this painting&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-roma&#x2F;vatican.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By DAY 4 we were ready to leave Rome behind, and so after checking out of the Hostel we basically just waited at the train station for 2 hours for our train to Florence...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
