<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Alex Guinman - Germany</title>
    <subtitle>Personal blog</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/germany/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2017-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/germany/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>München</title>
        <published>2017-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2017-04-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/munich/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/munich/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/munich/">&lt;p&gt;We arrived and it was raining, so we quickly dropped out bags at the hostel and went to get lunch. We went to Augustine Keller and got pork knuckle since I had it last time I was in Munich and thought it was great. It was super fatty and wasn&#x27;t as nice as last time, which I expect was mostly because I wasn&#x27;t massively hungover from Oktoberfest. Rachael loved the building though and her spinach and mountain cheese soup.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;munich&#x2F;Schweinshaxe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We quickly visited Marienplatz and then back to hostel to check in. Next we went to Theresienwiese so I could show Rachael where Oktoberfest is held and the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Bavaria_statue&quot;&gt;Bavaria statue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I had no idea you can go inside it (we didn&amp;#39;t though) as I assume it was closed during Oktoberfest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;munich&#x2F;Bavaria_statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I tried to show Rachael a recreation of the walking tour I did &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&quot;&gt;last time&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which went okay except everything was closed for winter and it was raining. We went to see the May Pole but it was missing, and the churches were all closed for services. We went to Hofgarden, which would have been great if the weather was nicer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;munich&#x2F;Hofgarten.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that I really wished I&amp;#39;d seen last time was the Eisbachwelle surfing spot in the Englischer Garten, so we went there and despite Rachael saying nobody would be surfing in the freezing rain, there was heaps of people out. It was fun to watch, but eventually the cold rain got to use so we headed back to the hostel.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;munich&#x2F;surfer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;munich&#x2F;surf_sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a free beer for checking in, it was massive!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;munich&#x2F;free_beer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For breakfast in the morning they coloured in the eggs though, which was cool. Also we ran into a girl in the lobby that Rachael and I both knew from Rocky who now lives in London.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;munich&#x2F;easter_eggs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Church bells rang like crazy the whole time we were there, was really strange as they weren&amp;#39;t on the hour just at random times. Nearly all the shops were closed for Easter which combined with the cold rain meant the next day wasn&amp;#39;t particularly great.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked in English garden in the morning but then it started to rain heavy again so we just hung out in the hostel lobby for the rest of the day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked to church during a break in the rain at lunch time, and managed to get in between services.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;munich&#x2F;church.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we went to the bus station to wait for our overnight bus to Paris. We went to Vapianos for dinner, and had a really grumpy pizza maker and generally bad service compared to the one in Brisbane. We stayed there for a while as it was still pouring rain and freezing cold (I think it snowed later that night).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our bus ended up getting delayed several times, and they had terrible signage and changed which bay we were meant to wait at repeatedly. Then when the bus arrived no one seemed to have any idea about how to queue and just rushed onto the bus to get good seats. Since we waited to ask where to put out luggage we ended up having to split up. Eventually the guy next to Rachael got off at at one of the stops and so we were able to sleep. I was expecting a night bus to have much comfier seats that reclined (like the different set up for night trains), but no such luck - it was just a normal bus. After the airport in Berlin, we were left with the impression that while Germany has a good train system, bus stops and airports are terrible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Berlin</title>
        <published>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2017-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/berlin/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/berlin/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/berlin/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;roomview.jpg&quot; title=&quot;View%20from%20our%20AirBnB&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got in to Berlin quite late, but got up early the next day to do the free walking tour.
We learnt heaps of history about the war, and the berlin wall and cold war.
One of the first stops was the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Memorial_to_the_Murdered_Jews_of_Europe&quot;&gt;Jew Memorial&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which when we saw it was really familiar as I&amp;#39;d seen it on TV and the internet. The designer did a great job, as when you walk through it, it&amp;#39;s nothing like what you expect. All the blocks are slightly different and in the middle it goes really deep and some are really tall. The guide said the designer refused to explain what it represented, and it was up to everyone that visited to interpret it for themselves. Reading the wiki article though, it says it was &amp;quot;designed to produce an uneasy, confusing atmosphere, and the whole sculpture aims to represent a supposedly ordered system that has lost touch with human reason&amp;quot; which actually describes it really well. Each of the minorities that were persecuted got their own memorial, rather then grouping them all together, which is a nice thought. Our guide also pointed out how great it is that the Germans are so open about the past, to ensure it doesn&amp;#39;t happen again with the memorials in the middle of the city on prime real estate. Pretty much all the ex-colonies (like Australia) have a terrible history where they invaded, but that&amp;#39;s mostly ignored so I think it&amp;#39;s really great that they acknowledge it. The German parliament was also a cool building, with a see through viewing platform above it so you can look down on the politicians and they can always look up to see who they represent (the tour guide pointed out mostly tourists). You need to book an appointment ages in advance though, so unfortunately we couldn&amp;#39;t go up. Thinking about it also reminded me of a comment Jan said to me when he visited on Australia Day, and about how great he thought it was to have a day where we could celebrate your nationality and that they can&amp;#39;t really have that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;brandenburggate.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Brandenburg%20Gate&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;jewmemorial.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Memorial%20to%20the%20Murdered%20Jews%20of%20Europe&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also visited the car park which was built on top of the bunker where Hitler shot himself, and saw parts of the Berlin Wall and Checkpoint Charlie. The tour stopped at a cafe for lunch which actually had cheap but amazing chicken schnitzel bagels. The final stop was wear a large book burning took place, and the square had an underground room which you could look down into, that had bookshelves with no books on them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the tour, we walked to museum island, and there appeared to be some sort of political rally going on. When we got closer we saw that they were filming movie. All the museums had awesome architecture, but were expensive so we didn&amp;#39;t go in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;movie.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Movie%20filming%20on%20museum%20island&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we went to the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.memu.berlin&#x2F;en&#x2F;exhibition&#x2F;menschen-museum&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Menschen Museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which was the thing that Rachael was most looking forward to in Berlin. It was okay, I was expecting it to be more about science but it was presented more like an art gallery. Seeing a real spinal cord and the tiny bone in your ear were pretty cool though. Afterwards we had lunch at an amazing Vietnamese restaurant. Germany was great for having amazing cheap food after being in the Scandinavian countries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we walked along the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;East_Side_Gallery&quot;&gt;East Side Gallery&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which is a section of the Berlin Wall near where we were staying with murals. Apparently it&amp;#39;s the hipster part of town and their are clubs that are open 24&#x2F;7 (haven&amp;#39;t closed in like 7 years) and a club that you have to wait in line for like 4 hours only to probably get told that you are dressed wrong and can&amp;#39;t come in. it was weird to think about something like that happening so recently in history (when I was a baby as opposed to before I was born anyway). On the other side of the river there were definitely lots of hipster restaurants and we went to a park that actually seemed like American parks you see in the movies.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;berlinwall.jpg&quot; title=&quot;East%20Side%20Gallery&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Sachsenhausen_concentration_camp&quot;&gt;Sachsenhausen Concentration Camp&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which was as miserable as you would imagine but worth the visit. The weather was very appropriate with a bitter cold wind making it horrible to stand outside in our jackets (in Spring), while we were told that prisoners had to stand out basically wearing nothing for hours on end in the middle of winter. Given the prisoners were essentially worked to death in -20, we couldn&amp;#39;t complain too much.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;Sachsenhausen.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Sachsenhausen&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We decided to go to a a German pub for dinner to lighten the mood and had some good beer, and okay food. Afterwards we popped in for a drink at Hofbraü Berlin so Rachael could get a small taste of what Oktoberfest was like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;hofbrauhaus.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Hofbra%C3%BC&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day we caught a train to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Kaiser_Wilhelm_Memorial_Church&quot;&gt;a church&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that was destroyed in the war and left up as a memorial. Was pretty crazy seeing all the artillery holes in the side of the walls, and the damage inside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;MemorialChurch1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;MemorialChurch2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then got a bus to the Tiergarten and climb up the victory column (which I had never heard of). It also had bullet holes on it, was a good view from the top but very crowded. They should limit number of people at a time, as it ruined the experience a bit and we wouldn&amp;#39;t have minded a small wait. It was a very long staircase climb to the top. There was a cool underpass system under the roundabout, and there was a busker playing guitar that found the perfect spot to play so that it echoed all over the square and sounded awesome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;VictoryColumn1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Tiergarten&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;VictoryColumn2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Tiergarten&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For lunch we got amazing kebabs that had chips in them, and Rachael had a Halloumi one which was equally awesome. Berlin really does have great street food.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we went to the gardens at Schloss Charlottenburg, which were good but not super amazing.
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;berlin&#x2F;CharlotteCastle.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Charlottenburg%20Grounds&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to get up really early for our flight, and then when we got there it was closed until 2 hours before our flight. When they did eventually open there was huge lines and security was super tedious and badly organised, it seemed very un-german compared to their rail system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Schloss Neuschwanstein</title>
        <published>2010-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein/">&lt;p&gt;After a few quick hours of sleep in Munich, we were checking out again. At the train station we waited for the tour to start, and then after seeing a sign for the Neuschwanstein Tour, signed up. Turns out it was the wrong one, and not the Sandeman&#x27;s one that we had to planned to go on. Our guide was perfectly good though, and in fact probably needed the money more as the other group was much bigger and there was only 2 other people with us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to get our train to Füssen only to find that the train had been cancelled, so instead we had to get a bus. So we got a bus, changed to a train, changed to another train then another train, then another bus until finally we were there only one hour later than planned. The view on the way was great, lots of green countryside and forests with random patches of snow the closer we got.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein&#x2F;train.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the woman at the tourist office was nice enough to let us leave our luggage, we journeyed onward to look up at Hohenschwangau Castle, which was the original royal castle &#x2F; holiday house.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein&#x2F;hohenschwangau.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Rachael got to play in the snow a bit, and throw some snowballs (strangely she didn&amp;#39;t throw any at me, was totally expecting it and would have been fine with it - you missed your chance!) we got a bus up to Marys Bridge. From here we got to see the waterfall and the castle.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein&#x2F;waterfall.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein&#x2F;castle1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein&#x2F;castle2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein&#x2F;castle3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The castle was epic in every sense of the word. Ludwig was clearly a crazy maniac, he had a room dedicated to the swan and there was a room that was a man-made cave. It actually felt like you were in a cave and the doors had rocks on the back so you really wouldn&amp;#39;t know otherwise. What a nutter. Wikipedia has a good article on the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Neuschwanstein_Castle&quot;&gt;Neuschwanstein Castle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because we were an hour late coming in, we didn&amp;#39;t get to go down to the lake which was a shame but better than missing our train home. Apparently one of the lakes was the lake that the opera &amp;quot;Swan Lake&amp;quot; is named after.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-schloss-neuschwanstein&#x2F;lake.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the train back to Buchloe heard the various story&amp;#39;s of Ludwig&amp;#39;s death, because he died under &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ludwig_II_of_Bavaria#Mysterious_death&quot;&gt;Mysterious Circumstances&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&amp;quot;. We asked our guide what they do in Buchloe and he said &amp;quot;make supercars&amp;quot;. Apparently he was hitch-hiking from Berlin and the CEO of the company picked him up in one of the cars and offered to take him to Munich. He said it&amp;#39;s normally like an 8 hours journey, but they did it in 3. No speed limit on the autobahn means they were travelling 300km&#x2F;h or so for most of the journey.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our train home was okay, we got to talk to a girl from America that was a screenwriter and was writing a movie. We had a pretty interesting conversation to say the least, and she had a very different personality to anyone I&amp;#39;ve met before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also on the way into Switzerland, two guys from customs came through with a sniffer dog and spent ages going through this lady&amp;#39;s bag. He then checked our passports and such and I think Rachael was a little freaked out because she didn&amp;#39;t know what was going (they were mostly speaking in German and were in street clothes). We changed trains at Winterthur and met some Aussie students, one of them was doing engineering. The train also started to fill with people coming and going from the clubs in Zürich, as it was a Saturday night which always makes for an interesting train ride. At long last we made it home (or to Switzerland in Rachael&amp;#39;s case) and got some sleep before yet more travel the next day. Oh and because I didn&amp;#39;t have any food at home except Chocolate, and the shops are closed at that time, we got to have that for tea. Rachael very much approved of the chocolate, but I think not so much about having it as a meal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Oktoberfest</title>
        <published>2010-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/oktoberfest/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/oktoberfest/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/oktoberfest/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;p1040660.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oktoberfest&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;FRIDAY&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the trip to Oktoberfest started with a long train ride from Zürich to München. It went fairly quickly but, as someone brought cards, so we played a Canadian variation of Presidents and Assholes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the train station it was clear that we had arrived at Oktoberfest, as people were walking around in &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Lederhosen&quot;&gt;Lederhosen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Dirndl&quot;&gt;Dirndl&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and there was massive Pretzels for sale everywhere. Also a big clue was the fact that many people were staggering around and one guy (who looked to be in his 40&amp;#39;s) even fell over when he got on an escalator and only just managed to stand up again before the top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually (after much waiting around for the rest of the group) we got Tram 17 to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;the-tent.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Tent&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. As we walked in it looked really cool, there was a massive bonfire with people chatting and fairy lights hung everywhere and a huge tent with the beds in it. But while it looked cool, trying to get to sleep was another story as when there was so many people in such a big tent you can hear conversations constantly throughout the night. Most of the people staying there seemed to be Australians, and while it was good to hear a familiar accent, it was quite annoying listening to people to talk about the AFL at 1:00am when I had to wake up at 7 to head to the festival. As well as that, the night was absolutely freezing, and I woke up cold through the night despite wearing my jumper to bed, being in a sleeping bag and having a blanket. The morning was just as bad and it was even colder outside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;thetent.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Tent&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;SATURDAY&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught the tram at 7.30 and made our way to the Oktoberfest grounds, where there was already a lot of people heading towards the grounds. We were headed for the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Hofbr%C3%A4u-Festzelt&quot;&gt;Hofbräu-Festzelt&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; tent, which was basically the first tent as we walked in. Despite getting there a little bit before 8, there was already a massive line. By the time they started letting people in at about 8.30 there was an even bigger line behind us. When they opened the doors it was like a stampede, but we managed to get a table up the top of the tent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;oktoberfest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Willkommen&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;line.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stampede to get in&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tent was pretty cool, was basically just a huge hall with tables and tables of people waiting for beer. The first beers arrived at about 9, but our table was one of the last tables to be served so we didn&amp;#39;t get our first beer until about 9.40. Inside the tent was great fun, with lots of chanting but mostly just drinking. For some reason people were chanting the tune to Seven Nation Army most of the day, which is just strange because they weren&amp;#39;t even singing the lyrics, just the riff. But we didn&amp;#39;t get to stay in the tent long, because everyone upstairs got kicked out at about 11, because the tables had been reserved for a big group or something. At this stage we were still waiting for another beer to arrive but it never did. After we got kicked out, we were moved down to the beer garden outside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;at-the-table.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;At the table&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day was spent talking to various people from all over the world. One guy who was particularly funny was from England, but was pretending to be South African by putting on a pretty bad accent. I had four &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Ma%C3%9F&quot;&gt;Maß&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (1L Beer Stein) during the day, so from around 3ish when I left the tent my memory isn&amp;#39;t super detailed. I started making my way to find The Cat Empire concert that was on that night, and headed into the Oktoberfest grounds. There was a huge big statue which was really impressive, but while I thought it was cool at the time, I didn&amp;#39;t take as much notice until we came back the next day. I ventured into town and found a supermarket and bought some food. At this point I didn&amp;#39;t even want to go to The Cat Empire anymore, all I wanted to do was sleep. But I knew I would regret it the next day if I didn&amp;#39;t go, so from here I randomly found my way to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Feldherrnhalle&quot;&gt;Feldherrnhalle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; looked around for a bit at all the cool statues and buildings and then got a bus to Ostbahnof. From here I started trying out my German speaking skills by asking everyone where TonHalle was. Nobody seemed to know where it was, except for one lady who sent me in the general direction, but eventually I found some people that were heading to the concert as well so followed them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;lost.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lost&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual gig itself was epic. Despite having a massive headache by this stage and struggling to keep my eyes open I was that tired, it would put it up there as possibly the best live show I have ever seen. It&amp;#39;s a tough call to say whether it was better than Xavier, but I think it just makes it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The support band Tinpan Orange was pretty good, and Harry Angus played trumpet and keyboard for them (he must be in like 4 bands). The cat empire where everything I expected though, they had so many improvised solos with perfect timing. Harry did this massive scat solo thing that you could tell was all improvised, and you could see how much the band was concentrating to match his timing, which was perfect for every beat. There encore was the Wine Song and the Chariot both of which were also incredible live.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;catempire.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Cat Empire&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding my way home after the gig was horrible. I had a massive headache, didn&amp;#39;t know what bus to get and was basically falling asleep as I walked. After staring at a map for a while and still having no idea, I decided to backtrack and head to the Haftbanhof and then get Tram 17.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tram 17 I was really struggling to stay awake and started dozing in and out of sleep. The night before, our group had been arguing about whether we hopped off at Romanplatz or the Botanical Gardens. I opened my eyes at one point of my half-sleep and saw I was at Romanplatz, so I quickly jumped of the train because I didn&amp;#39;t want to miss my stop. It was actually two stops early, so I had a further 10min walk or so to get to The Tent. But eventually, I made it back and went straight to bed. Unlike the previous night, getting to sleep was no problem and I had the best nights sleep you could imagine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;SUNDAY&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I felt great, but was I no way keen for heading back to the beer tents. No body else was in the mood for more drinking either, so we decided to go on the free walking tour of Munich.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The walking tour was so good, and so much better than just wandering around the city like I have been doing. So many things we saw that we would not have known the significance of otherwise.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw the outside of the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Munich_Frauenkirche&quot;&gt;Devil&amp;#39;s Church&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but couldn&amp;#39;t go inside because there was a service on. But, we did get pointed out to us the solid gold brick that was in one of the towers, which was put there to show how lucky it was, as the church was hit by a bomb during the war that bounced off and didn&amp;#39;t detonate.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked along the route that the Nazi party took when they first tried to seize power and saw the spot where Hitler was shot at. His body guard took 11 bullets, and saved him and now (according to our guide anyway) there is a storm water drain there to signify the spot. To demonstrate how much better having a tour guide is then just wandering around yourself, we were shown a spot on the wall where you could make out where a plaque used to be, but it had been concreted over. I would never have noticed this, but we were told what used to be there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.scrapbookpages.com&#x2F;Munich&#x2F;Feldherrenhalle.html&quot;&gt;this site&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that explains it, here&amp;#39;s a quick excerpt:
&amp;quot;The Bürgerbräukeller was torn down years ago, but tourists can still see where the Nazis put a plaque on the Feldherrenhalle to honor the men who were killed there by the police. During the Nazi era, Munich residents were required to do a Nazi salute as they passed the plaque, which has since been removed. Those who did not want to give a salute to the fallen heroes would use Viscardigasse, a back alley which was nicknamed &amp;quot;Evaders&amp;#39; Alley.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also walked down Evader&amp;#39;s Alley, where the stone&amp;#39;s had been painted gold to recognise the people that stood up to the Nazi&amp;#39;s. If the guards saw you walk down this street then they would send you off to a concentration camp because they knew you opposed them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the most interesting two stories were these:
The opera house was the first building ever to have a sprinkler system in case of a fire, but as it was the first time someone had invented it, they didn&amp;#39;t think about what would happen if there was a fire in winter, when all the water was frozen. So when a fire broke out, they went to use it and it didn&amp;#39;t work so they had to come up with a Plan B. So they ordered everyone to stand in a chain and pass down kegs of beer from the Hofbräuhaus down the street to poor on the fire. I should point out at this point that most of the breweries in Germany are owned by the government. But the problem with the plan was that out of the 120 or so kegs that were passed down only 20 made it to the fire. So the opera house burnt down. The king was pretty angry about the townspeople stealing his beer AND his opera house burning down, so he raised the price of beer as punishment and to pay for the damages. Except they all get angry about that and had a mini revolution, and so the tax was dropped. And now in Germany beer is classed as &amp;quot;food&amp;quot; for tax purposes so basically they don&amp;#39;t charge any tax. But then again the government owns all the beer anyway, so you kind of do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now for what I thought was the coolest story. For the last stop on our tour we went to see Munich&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Maypole#Germany_and_Austria&quot;&gt;Maypole&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It wasn&amp;#39;t particularly exciting, but we were told that if you steal a maypole (these things are huge) you can hold it up to ransom to the town, and dictate the terms of it&amp;#39;s return. Found some more info on stealing them &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lewrockwell.com&#x2F;barnhart&#x2F;barnhart11.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. People would steal the maypole of another town and then demand they throw them a party before they will give it back, or demand a certain amount of beer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the really cool part of the story is this: &amp;quot;the theft in broad daylight of the Viktualienmarkt&amp;#39;s maypole in 1964. As a ransom, the brothers Schorsch und Valentin Bauer demanded, and received, the lifelong right to a box at the Oktoberfest, since which time Box 7 in the Augustiner tent has been called the Maibaumräuber (maypole thieves) box.&amp;quot; And not only that but they demanded free beer for life as well which they get.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the tour we went to the Augistiner pub for lunch and got a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Schweinshaxe&quot;&gt;Schweinshaxe&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (Pork-knuckle) and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Kn%C3%B6del&quot;&gt;Kartoffelknödel&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (Potato Dumpling) to eat and an Augistiner &amp;quot;Oktoberfest&amp;quot; beer. I hadn&amp;#39;t tried either of these foods before, but they were both amazing. Especially the Schweinshaxe which was basically just a huge chunk of pork with crackling and fat throughout. The beer was less enjoyable, as I think my body was still processing the one&amp;#39;s from the day before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;pub.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Schweinshaxe&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some food, we headed back to Oktoberfest. This was a very different Oktoberfest to the one I experienced the day before, because this time we walked around outside the tents, and didn&amp;#39;t go inside. It was basically exactly the same as the show, but on a truly massive scale. The amount of people there was ridiculous. I managed to get in some photobombing practice, and even some boneheading that might make it on the German news.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found our way to the hill with the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Bavaria_statue&quot;&gt;massive statue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to sit down for a while, and got to see all the people that had been drinking all morning passed out on the grass. I had found out that morning that most of the Canadians had slept on the hill at about the time when I left to find The Cat Empire concert. I was that tired, that if I hadn&amp;#39;t of had a concert to go to, I would have probably done the same.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;oktoberfest&#x2F;statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Schweinshaxe&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point, a guy at the top of the hill accidentally dropped a mug, and it rolled down the hill, hitting two of the passed out guys on the head on the way down. Even that didn&amp;#39;t wake them up. We stayed there for a fair while and just watched various crazy stuff go down around us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day we had a long train home, which was even longer due to the fact that it was delayed by 40mins in Austria. Eventually though I was back in Turgi for a few hours sleep before work the next day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Prost</title>
        <published>2010-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/prost/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/prost/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/prost/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;prost&#x2F;p1040438.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1040438&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night we went to Germany for some drinks for Steven&amp;#39;s birthday and also because some people are going home soon. The bar in Waldshut that Steven and I found is even better than we first thought. Not only are beers only 2€, but if you start singing happy birthday then the bartender will come over with some free Jägermeister shots. Oh and rather than stealing the beer glass, Steven ASKED if he could keep it, and they even got him a clean one to take home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the best saying to learn in each language is &amp;quot;Cheers&amp;quot;. Two important ones for Switzerland are Prost (German) and Santé (French). I haven&amp;#39;t actually heard the Italian one yet, but apperntly it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Salute&amp;quot;. That&amp;#39;s according to this site: &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.omniglot.com&#x2F;language&#x2F;phrases&#x2F;cheers.htm&quot;&gt;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.omniglot.com&#x2F;language&#x2F;phrases&#x2F;cheers.htm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other cool one&amp;#39;s I have learnt from IAESTE people:
Na zdraví (Czech) Kippis (Finnish) Skål (Norwegian)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthony told me the Irish one last night as well, but I already forgot it. Possibly it was Sláinte as it says on the site. Have a look at how many different sayings they have listed for Irish. It&amp;#39;s pretty clear it&amp;#39;s not just a stereotype that they like to drink.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
