<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Alex Guinman - IAESTE</title>
    <subtitle>Personal blog</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/iaeste/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2010-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/iaeste/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Ski Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ski-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ski-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ski-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ski-weekend&#x2F;p1050930.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ski Weekend&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this weekend was the much-anticipated IAESTE Ski Weekend.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing work on Friday, I went to Karla&amp;#39;s Goodbye Apero for a little while and then had to get a train to Les Diablerets. The journey takes 3 hours and 40 minutes, and after each subsequent train change there were more and more IAESTE peeps. At about 10 we finally got to our destination, and upon arriving to the chalet we got some Glühwein, or rather Vin Chaud because we were in the French-speaking part. It tasted different to the one I had in Zürich but it was also really nice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday night I had not got much sleep because I went to the work Christmas party in Zürich, and Friday night we stayed up late as well, considering we had to get up early the next day. I think our room was one of the first to go to bed at about 1, and I could still hear music blaring when I went to sleep. The best thing about staying in a chalet and not a hostel like all the other weekends was that we were allowed to make us much noise as we wanted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning we split up, and those without their own gear had to go to the rental store. I was convinced into renting a helmet for the weekend by the fact that everyone else had one, unlike in Davos where Maciek and I went without.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to get a bus from the town up to the gondola, and then headed up to the glacier. I had a pretty horrible morning as the board felt weird for some reason and I was uncomfortable with the turns. After lunch I realised that my bindings were a bit loose, and thought that maybe it was that, but wasn&amp;#39;t really sure how to fix them or where to get the tools, so I soldiered on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before lunch we had stayed close to the restaraunt. There was only one really short red (blue) run and to use another run you had to walk (or get lots of speed to get past the flat part) over to the T-bars. After lunch we walked across, but I did two more runs and decided that it wasn&amp;#39;t me that sucked and that it was definitely the bindings. So then I had to hike back again to the restaraunt and was able to find a table where they had tools and tighten my bindings. It was instantly better, and so I was pretty annoyed that the rental company was such a failure and didn&amp;#39;t tighten them properly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ski-weekend&#x2F;P1050977.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back over to the t-bar section again and did a long blue run which was insanely fun. The resort was fairly small and was basically all blue (green) runs because the black runs were closed. But even so, I found it much better than Davos as the snow was softer and the runs more interesting. There was a bank of fresh snow on the sides of this run which allowed you to get air and land in fresh powder. I landed some of my attempts at jumps and failed hard on others but only got to do one run before it was basically time to head back up to catch the Gondola.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the flat section where you needed to un-clip, they had dog sleds, and at the end of the day the dogs pulled the sled up this massively steep hill back up to the restaurant - which was pretty crazy to see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the chalet, we had Fondue for dinner. The punishment for dropping the bread into the cheese was that you had to go out into the snow and make a snow angel. But nobody did that, so either nobody dropped it (unlikely) or they didn&amp;#39;t follow the rules.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chalet had really small ceilings (as seems to be the case all over Switzerland) and I hit my head several times. But not as bad as Curran, who bumped his head so hard that he started bleeding and had to go to the doctor because he got a concussion. After that I was much more careful and didn&amp;#39;t hit my head once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After dinner we had a trivia night, with drinking games in-between rounds. I had not seen a few of the games before, so I can enlighten everyone when I return with lots of new games.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my bindings were tight now, Sunday was probably my most enjoyable day on snowboarding to date. The weather was really good (for most of the day) and the snow was reasonably fresh and so pretty soft. I headed straight over to the slope from the afternoon before, and this time managed to &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; land a 180 air. I say mostly because I landed it but didn&amp;#39;t stay upright for long afterwards. It was a good thing that I rented a helmet because my second attempt ended even worse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things got more adventurous from there and I went to the Terrain Park with an English guy called Pete. Unlike the previous run, the terrain park was not soft snow and hurt a fair bit when I fell. The jumps weren&amp;#39;t too scary though and I managed to get a fair bit of air off them although didn&amp;#39;t try any tricks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to have a go at the grind rail, and got about half way along before jumping off. On the 2nd run, I did a wider rail and was able to make it all the way to the end and do a jump off the end. This made me a bit too cocky though I think, as I tried the thin one again immediately after it and failed epicly. Again I was glad I had rented the helmet as I hit my head pretty hard on the ice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then later still, I did another epic stack. I hit the biggest jump with tonnes of speed and without meaning to attempted to do a backflip - or at least that&amp;#39;s what I was told it looked like by Pete. I basically landed on my back so it I landed pretty hard and got the wind knocked out of me a bit. After a short breather I was okay, see the video below for footage that I took directly after (in the middle of the video somewhere). I had planned on doing the rail again but didn&amp;#39;t want to try it with the camera in my hand. We went back one more time though and I successfully made it to the end of the grind rail again, again landing the jump off the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 17814190 &amp;gt;}}&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went back to the nice soft runs after that and tried doing Indie grabs. All and all it was an epic day, and was a much better ski resort than Davos. The one problem that I had was that the T-bars were so long and steep that it was really quite painful by the time you go to the top of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ski-weekend&#x2F;P1050981.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day we went back to the chalet for some hot soup and then started the long train journey home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Technorama</title>
        <published>2010-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/technorama/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/technorama/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/technorama/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;technorama&#x2F;technorama.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;technorama&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday I went to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technorama.ch&quot;&gt;Technorama&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;plus.google.com&#x2F;105054703111621531697&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winterthur&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on an IAESTE event. It was sort of like the Swiss version of Questacon. Check out the video below for some of the random things that I filmed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 17339544 &amp;gt;}}&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lightning display was a fairly big let-down for the most part (it went for about 30mins but the only cool bits were in that video). But the Tesla coils were definitely worth the wait. After Ode to Joy they also played Smoke on the Water - the frequency is changed by increasing how many times it arcs in a second.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Mindball&quot;&gt;Mindball&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; game had me really excited when I first saw it. It was pretty impressive. Until I won about 5 games in a row so we started testing the system to see how it works. Turns out the game still runs with nobody hooked up to it and the &amp;quot;brain waves&amp;quot; are just as random.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a transparent gearbox which was pretty cool to see how it physically worked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a electic bike set-up similar to one we designed for a group project at uni. Except we never made ours and it wasn&amp;#39;t as good. They had several different applicances hooked up so you could see how fast you needed to pedal to produce enough power for them to work. The LCD TV was suprisingly easy to power, boiling water and powering some LED floodlights was much more difficult.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also had a table full of gas in which you could see particle collisions taking place, which were like little minature explosions, was pretty impressive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a an educational and interesting day. At the end of the day we had a bloody freezing walk to the train station, and froze on the platform waiting for a train. I can understand why people don&amp;#39;t like Winter here, but so far I still love the snow :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Hiking Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-hiking-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-hiking-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-hiking-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;P1040232.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hiking weekend began with the steepest bus ride in Europe. It really was quite steep in places, made the bus ride up to the Remarkables in New Zealand tame in comparison. Because it was only one lane the bus driver was constantly hitting the horn to let cars know we were coming round the corner. The swiss post buses have a REALLY loud and long horn tune.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then began the hiking. The first stage was about on par with the Jura weekend hike. Quite steep and energy draining but a pleasant stroll in comparison to what came later.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;lowerhike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about an hour hike we made it to a restaurant and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Transhumance#The_Alps&quot;&gt;alpine cheese factory&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We got to see how they made the cheese, and how it is aged. To be able to market as Alpine cheese, the cows have to live and the cheese has to be made at a certain altitude (I forget what). In the winter they move everything down into the valley though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;cheese.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got to try some. It tasted like cheese.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the hiking continued, this was the hardest part of the weekend. It was incredibly steep and in many places slippery. Incredible views though. Eventually we all made it to the top - well as high as you could go without climbing gear - to the cottage that we were staying at. The only was to get supplies there is by helicopter (or by carting it up the massive hike). We had some beers when we got there and it reminded me so much of beers in Lake Tekapo on the NZ Ski Trip last year. For Comparison (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;picasaweb.google.com&#x2F;alexguinane&#x2F;SkiTrip09#5516776164870888626&quot;&gt;NZ&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;picasaweb.google.com&#x2F;alexguinane&#x2F;IAESTEHikingWeekend#5516411549420267634&quot;&gt;Schwiez&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) Then we went down for a bit of a walk on the glacier, which was
fun although quickly turned into everyone throwing chunks of ice at each other. There was an Aussie guy from Adelaide on the glacier that took a group photo for us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;P1040181.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;P1040203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;finalstairs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;hut.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;groupshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed the night in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;plus.google.com&#x2F;110740992425167130852&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Blüemlisalphütte&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; alpine cottage. Our room had a top and bottom bunk, but they are all joined so it&amp;#39;s about 20 mattresses up the top and 20 down the bottom so you all sleep close together. As such we got to hear some nice snoring through the night. It wasn&amp;#39;t too bad though. Also you weren&amp;#39;t allowed hiking boots inside so you had to
wear sandals. The Swiss sure love socks and sandals. I should mention that even at work you see people wearing socks and sandals. Dinner was really nice, they do pretty well for somewhere so remote. Even the beer wasn&amp;#39;t too expensive (6.50CHF for 5dl). That&amp;#39;s another thing that is stange here. They don&amp;#39;t use mL. They use cL and dL. I have no idea
why, it seems to be a Europe thing but it doesn&amp;#39;t make much sense.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;beers1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;beers2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;clogs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunset was particularly amazing, the view of the various peaks of the alps was spectacular. Once it got dark, it got really cold. But I still ventured outside with a few other keen people and we did a bit of stargazing. There was no light pollution or clouds, so you could see everything perfect. It was also interesting to see all the different constellations of the northern hemisphere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we started the long hike down the other side to Oeschinen Lake and Kandersteg. Along the way Andreas found some Edelweiss, which is apparently a really rare flower. Also on a creek there was a salamander, which was quite cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;glacier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;hikedown1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;flower1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;flower2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;salamander.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;Oeschinensee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;Oeschinensee2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having lunch by the lake we went tobogganing! YAY! It was quite lame I thought, was way too slow and much less fun than I was expecting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More hiking down to Kandersteg, by this stage the trail was mostly meadows, so I could finally take of the Swiss Army boots I had been wearing all weekend and get some relief from the many, many blisters that had formed. Although the boots were quite heavy to carry and I had to pay close attention to where I was walking so I didn&amp;#39;t stand in
sheep poo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of us under 25 paid for a train to Bern and then walked around for a bit while we waited for the Gleis7 to kick in. Was a great weekend, but even today (2 days later) every step is difficult and walking up stairs is horrible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;trainhome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Jura Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-jura-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-jura-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-jura-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;P1040064.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been very busy lately with assignments, German lessons and traveling, so haven&amp;#39;t had time to update this in a while. On the weekend before last, I went to the Jura region, which is in the French-speaking part of Switzerland.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, we went to the underground mills in Le Locle. They were used in the 1800s to make flour, and used the water that flowed through the cave to turn the mill. But for some strange reason Le Locle was built in the way of the river and it would often flood during the spring when the snow melted. So they bought out the mill and closed it down
because they then redirected the river away from the town and it dried it up. The mill was then used as an abattoir and the owners dumped all of the animal waste down into the caves (don&amp;#39;t know how that was allowed...). Then about 30 years ago (I think) some crazy historians decided they would take all the dumped waste out and make a museum. I have already forgotten most of the facts the tour guide told us, as it was 2 weeks ago now. There is more info here -
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lesmoulins.ch&#x2F;&quot;&gt;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lesmoulins.ch&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - but it&amp;#39;s in french. It was a fairly interesting tour though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;mill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we jumped on a train to ?somewhere? and visited an Absinthe factory. Well on the itinerary it said it was a factory, but it was more like some guy that made lots of it in his basement and sells it. The house alone was pretty cool. It used to be a drug store, and upstairs all the old chemicals and stuff were still there in this really cool, old cabinet. We found things like Cyanide and Chloroform, but the bottles of those two were empty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;museum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then downstairs there was boxes with the herbs he uses to make the Absinth. There was 10 herbs, and one secret one that we weren&amp;#39;t allowed to see. I didn&amp;#39;t realise there was an actual absinthe plant, but there is. Also there was a one plant that you could easily smell straight away that it is what they use to make liquorice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy had been making it for 30 years or something, but it has only been legal for the last 5. Apparently the region was renown for it&amp;#39;s underground Absinth brewers, and there are still lots of them around (I guess to avoid tax).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual brewing itself was done in this steamer thing (I think with basically pure ethanol), and the end product is 75% alcohol. It is then diluted down to 55%, and the name of the product is Absinthe 55degrees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;boiler.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then had an apèro and got to try some. It was not what I was expecting having had it only as shots. They mix it with water, and it goes all cloudy. It then tastes a bit like liquorice and doesn&amp;#39;t burn as much. It is still very strong, but actually tasted like a drink rather than a shot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;absinth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;cheers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and we were told that the green fairy is a myth. The only difference is food colouring. The stories of hallucinations came about because the company that made the green fairy had a bad batch of really bad quality that was causing people to go a bit crazy. But not in a good way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we went to the hostel by the lake, and had a bit of a BBQ before dinner. The dinner wasn&amp;#39;t all that great and the waitress seemed pretty angry that we didn&amp;#39;t know french. The french breakfast was pretty basic too, and they have portions that are way too small.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;dinner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday was the hike up to the Creux-du-Van which was a very steep hike, but an amazing view from the top. Photo&amp;#39;s will do a better job of explaining it, so look on the Picasa web album.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;IMG_5449_corr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;P1040033.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;IMG_5441_corr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hiked down to the other side where there was a gorge, and then walked along the creek&#x2F;river for a few hours to the train station and then went home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;gorge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw my first Swiss Person give the finger at the train station, as Michael decided to run across the tracks when there was a train coming instead of using the underpass. The train driver was not happy as you can imagine so it was undertanable. Still strange that none of us had seen anyone give the finger until now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also funnny was that there was some girls at the other side of the train station dancing, that didn&amp;#39;t realise we could see them. When they turned around I waved and they ran away embarrassed. Then they decided they liked the attention after all and came back and continued. I think Petr enjoyed it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught some more delayed trains on the way home, the reputation of always being on time has been wrong nearly every train this last month, SBB needs to pick up there game.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Zermatt Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-zermatt-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-zermatt-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-zermatt-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;Saturday I got the train to Visp to begin the IAESTE Zermatt Weekend, which very unusally for a swiss train arrived about 5 mins late. From Visp we went on a cog train up to Zermatt, which was a lovely town at the foot of the Matterhorn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;zermatt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a cable car up to the top of the Klein Matterhorn which must be an epic ski resort in winter because they had runs open in the middle of Summer and there was a fair few people up there skiing. The side of the Matterhorn visible from up the top was covered in cloud, so we couldn&amp;#39;t see it, which sucked. The snow up the top was somewhat fresh, so we were able to make snowballs and people started putting snow down everyone&amp;#39;s back. One really cool thing is that from the top you can ski across to Italy (but you need an international ski pass).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;ski.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;grouppicture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the top we got an elevator back down into the mountain to the ice palace. It was pretty nice but not too impressive. One thing that was just crazy was they had a display about &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Glacier_flea&quot;&gt;glacial fleas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and a microscope to see these fleas that can live in the ice. There was a part that looked like a slide exit, but we couldn&amp;#39;t find the start of the slide so we climbed up the ice slide and found like a service room where the power boards and such were. So obviously it wasn&amp;#39;t a slide, and it wasn&amp;#39;t as easy to slide down it as it looked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;slide.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we got the cable down below the snow line and went into the gorge. It wasn&amp;#39;t particularly exciting although the wooden walkway along the gorge was quite cool, if a bit unsafe looking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;gorge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Saturday afternoon there was like a choir singing in the street at Zermatt, and the next morning there was a band of 5 alpine horns players which was amazing to listen to. Also on the Saturday night there was fireworks. I&amp;#39;m not sure if there was a festival on or something or if they always have things like that for the tourists but there was some sort of fun run or marathon on the Sunday morning as well, so perhaps it had something to do with that. After the fireworks on the Saturday night, we went down into the city and went to a bar which was also quite busy and fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;matterhorn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday we got a train to Brig, then a cable car up the mountain to what was clearly another ski resort (in the winter). From here we split into three groups. Option 1 was a way too easy walk, Option 2 was a medium hike around the mountain&#x2F;glacier. Option 3 was to hike up the top of one mountain peak then hike to the next mountain peak, which is what I chose because I wanted to go to the top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Map of hiking trails:
http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eggishorn.ch&#x2F;jwa&#x2F;VFS-DFA-217653-Aletsch_Arena_DF.pdf&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first peak we climbed was awesome and the hike up was really fun. It was such a strange mountain in that it was essentially just a pile of lots of small rocks, but made hiking up it a very cool experience. From here we hiked down the mountain on the other side then across and up to the peak of the next mountain Eggishorn (2926m). From here there was a magnificent view of the glacier and of the Jungfrau.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;glacier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Glacier&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this stage we had taken about an hour longer than they (IAESTE organisers) had expected it to take, and we were supposed to have met group 2 at a lake down the bottom by 3:00, when it was now 4.00 and we were still at the top. We could try and catch them up, or walk back a little bit to a chair lift and beat them back, but miss the walk past the glacier. Thinking of the stories, we went down from this peak to the bottom at the lake, or at least were supposed to but it wasn&amp;#39;t actually a path so we spent ages descending down this mountain and didn&amp;#39;t get to the path at the bottom until about 5:20.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;notapath.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last gondalla down the mountain back to Fiesch was at 6:00 and we still had to walk what we were told was 4km past the lake, through a tunnel and then to the gondalla. With only 40mins until the last trip we needed to run to make it, so I ran most of the way, so didn&amp;#39;t get a great look at the glacier but the path was beatuifal so I did stop a few times to look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;glacier-bottom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running at such a high altitude was really hard and tiring. I got to the end of the tunnel at about 5:55 so thought I had made it in time, but the cable car was nowhere to be seen once I emerged from the tunnel, and after running around the bend in the track I realised I&amp;#39;d missed it so then gave up. The view from that side of the tunnel was nowhere near as good which was a bit of a bummer, because I could have taken my time more on the other side. So I waited for a few more people to catch up and we were resigned to the fact we would have to walk down the mountain and probably would be sleeping at a train station. We talked to a local lady who walked past, who had also not realised the last car was at 6:00 until it was too late (they changed the timetable that day).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our choices were to hike down the mountain, which would take about 1.5 hours according to the local lady, or she was going to walk along the path for another 1.5 hours to the next cable car station which was open until 10. So we waited for about 20mins for the rest of group to catch up, then continued to the gondolla station because there was 3 guys ahead of me that were probably waiting there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One guy actually made it there by 6.05 or something after running non-stop for the whole 40mins which is amazing. So he made the last gondolla. But the other 2 in front of me where waiting still, as didn&amp;#39;t make it to the cable car until 6:20. Luckily for us, the guy working there had agreed to take everyone down
with him when he finished, because as well as our group there was about 10 other people (including the lady we talked to) had not made it or not known that 6.00 was the last trip. So we were really lucky and happy that we didn&amp;#39;t have to hike down, and that we didn&amp;#39;t try before checking at the cable car station.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made it in time to catch trains home, and I arrived in Turgi at about 11:50, which wasn&amp;#39;t too bad considering we thought we wouldn&amp;#39;t make it back. Most the trains we got were late, and we had to run to make the next connection at each station. I don&amp;#39;t know why there were all so late yersterday, normally trains arrive on the dot in Switzerland.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite putting sunscreen on twice during the hike, I am massively burnt all over today, as it was a really hot day yesterday and the sun was really bright. I didn&amp;#39;t think it was possible to get burnt here, after spending a few days walking round cities in the sun with no suncreen and hat and not getting burnt at all, but now I know it definitely is. It was only something like 20SPF suncreen that I could find here, so that could have had something to do with it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, a great weekend, but I would have liked some more sleep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Liechtenstein Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;This weekend I went on an IAESTE trip to Lichtenstein. It was a hard decision this weekend whether or not to go to Lichtenstein or stay and go the the street parade in Zurich on Saturday night. In the end I&#x27;m glad I went away for the weekend, although the street parade would still have been a sight to see, but I had a great time in Lichtenstein. As we waited for the train to Sargans on Saturday morning, we even saw a few people that were in dressed in costumes for that night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our train carriage there was a group of guys having a buck&#x27;s party, with the groom to be in a cow suit. His friends set him the challenge of climbing into the luggage rack and pulling himself along the entire length of the carriage (we took our bags down so he could do this) and then he had to do a shot at the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;buck.jpg&quot; title=&quot;The%20buck&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then got a bus from Sarrgans to Vaduz, Lichtenstein. We went for a walk along the Rhein, which was quite unimpressive, it wasn&amp;#39;t a particularly exciting river, but it marks the border between the two countries. We then got a bus up to the town of Malbun which was much more scenic. From here we went for a hike (well Steven and I) up a small creek that fell had been lined with logs, and kind of looked like a staircase.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;P1030302.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to a falcon show in the afternoon where a man showed us many huge birds, and explained interesting facts about them in German. He did translate some to English for us though when he brought them over towards our table. One falcon in particular was huge (15kg), and it was cool to see the hawk death strike a fake bird on a string. There was also a raven which once let out went crazy flying onto everyone&amp;#39;s table and stealing their food. One table had some ice cream which it ate and had ice cream on it&amp;#39;s beak which looked hilarious.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;IMG_4813_corr.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Falconry&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went for another hike, but at this stage some fog had appeared so we couldn&amp;#39;t see much which was a shame. I sure the view would have been spectacular but it just looked like cloud to us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;IMG_5001_corr.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Foggy&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then got a bus back to the city, ran back along the river to the hostel, went to dinner at a restaurant, then decided we should make our own street parade. So we found a service station to buy some beer then explored the streets of Vaduz. We found a band that was playing (no doubt because of the festival the next day) that sounded descent. I think every song they played was in English, but the banter was in Swiss-German. As the night went on we knew more and more songs. They were actually really good and had various singers throughout the night who were all very good. A girl came round and gave out sparklers, which we lit and then got told we were children and that we were supposed to wait for &amp;quot;the song&amp;quot;. So she gave us new ones to hold in the air during some song later on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;P1030322.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Band&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday was Lichtenstein&amp;#39;s national holiday, and the prince holds an aperitif in his garden that is open to the public. First there was some sort of mass on a field by &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Vaduz_Castle&quot;&gt;Vaduz Castle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It was kind of eerie at one stage when they all chanted the Lord&amp;#39;s prayer or something in German. People all speaking in unison in a foreign language felt like we had stumbled upon some sort of cult ritual.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;P1030343.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Service&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the mass, the prince&amp;#39;s son gave some speech about politics and stuff and then they all marched up to the castle. Also the band played God Save The Queen at the end which was just strange because they aren&amp;#39;t part of the Commonwealth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;garden.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;royals.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;royal_band.jpg&quot; title=&quot;With%20the%20royal%20band&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aperitif was awesome. There was free food and beer, and we got got to explore the garden of the castle. Also we met the Princess, the Prince and the Prince&amp;#39;s son and got photos of them all with us and the IAESTE flag. They seemed like a nice family and it was cool that they spend the morning talking to everyone. I also got to have a go of an alpine horn, which they had set up on a hill.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;P1030359.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Free%20Bier&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then walked down the mountain to the city, where there is a festival for the national holiday. All museums and buses are free on the day. I learnt that I don&amp;#39;t understand modern &amp;quot;art&amp;quot; as some of the stuff in the museum was just silly and anyone could do it. There was a cool quilt thing though that was a map of the world with each country shown as the national flag. But mostly it was silly things like a pile of coal, or a canvas that someone had put a stripe of black paint on with a paint roller.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;IMG_5076_corr.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Vaduz&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;IMG_4785_corr.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Vaduz&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bands and entertainment didn&amp;#39;t start until like 6.30, and about 5.30 it started to rain and got very miserable so we decided just to head home, as nothing particularly exciting was happening.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-liechtenstein-weekend&#x2F;P1030387.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Fu%C3%9Fball&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all it was a fun weekend, and it&amp;#39;s not every day you get to meet royalty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>007 Bungee Jump - Verzasca Dam</title>
        <published>2010-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p10301091.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;p1030109&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday afternoon I did the 007 Bungee Jump off the Verzasca Dam.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught a train to Tenero then hiked up towards the Dam. When I first saw it way in the background I thought - that is huge. But once we got close the nerves dissapeared and I was just excited mostly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to wait for a fair while before we could do our jump because there was a film crew filming for a German travel show. But at least we got to see someone do the jump before any of us did it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 220m from the platform to the ground, and the actual jump is like 180m I was told. And it is the same jump as from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=eBq8K-Y2B4g&quot;&gt;the opening scene&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the movie Goldeneye, hence the name.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was chatting to the guy at the top of the platform and he had been living in Noosa for a while. He asks everyone how they are feeling and when I told him I wasn&amp;#39;t nervous but felt like I should be, he told me it was his first day working there to try and help me out. I assume it was a joke but you never know, I suppose it always has to be your first day once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a looooooong way to the bottom but it didn&amp;#39;t feel like it. When I jump at first I just felt shock at not touching anything, then a feeling sort of like you get from the Giant Drop, then by the time I started to enjoy the fact that I was free-falling it was over. I think the freefall is 4 seconds, and it&amp;#39;s over way too fast to fully appreciate it. Skydiving next time for sure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jerk of the rope was quite a shock and not as smooth as I thought it would be, but doesn&amp;#39;t hurt. I then started to think &amp;quot;Oh it&amp;#39;s over...&amp;quot; before you bounce back up again and get to experience zero-gravity at the top of the bounce where it feels like you are floating. Definitely the coolest part of the jump in my opinion. The bounce back down again you feel all the blood rush to your head, and then it&amp;#39;s pretty much over because the next couple of bounces are way smaller.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the guys yell out to pull yourself up (it&amp;#39;s surprising how well you can hear them considering how far up they are). And you have to pull on a rope to flip yourself up the right way. That bit was a little bit scary trying to work out which is the right rope to pull while upside down.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then they lower down a winch cable, pull you up and it&amp;#39;s all over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely an amazing experience, and I would go again. Although it wasn&amp;#39;t quite as exhilarating as I thought it would be, and the adrenalin didn&amp;#39;t last very long afterwards. After seeing how pumped Adrian still was a few hours after I was expecting it to last longer than 5mins or so, but that&amp;#39;s about all it lasted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some photos below, but more photos and some videos that other people took on facebook as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 Stars.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Everyone in Aus should watch the show Review, it started a new series a few weeks ago but I can&amp;#39;t watch it from here due to the ABC blocking out people from Switzerland).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030102.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel show filming and jump&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030105.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;IMG_4568_corr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030117.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030123.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Ticino Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ticino-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ticino-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ticino-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;We caught a train from Zurich to Airolo, which took a few hours. Along the way we played Chinese Whist (what we just called hearts at Ergon) whilst going though the Swiss Alps. Some of the views were pretty cool, but there was lots of tunnels, and tunnels are boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Airolo we got rental bikes and started a 40km (something like that) bike ride to Biasca. It was mostly downhill through the Swiss Alps but was still tiring by the end. At lunch we stopped at Faido and there was an awesome waterfall. Continued riding along the river and huge mountains, and then another stop later at the mining exhibit. They are building a train tunnel underneath the swiss alps, and had an exhibition showing all the mining equipment and how they blow the rock up and such. Then more riding until we got to Biasca and caught the train to Lugano.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;ride0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;ride1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;ride2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;faido1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;faido2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;faido3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Lugano we were staying at a very cool Hostel, which was also a Hotel so it had a pool and lots of palm trees and other nice stuff. We went to dinner at some restaurant next to the Hostel with Astin Martin car posters all over the wall and had what looked like Fish and Chips with Veggies, but was actually chicken.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to the shop and bought a &amp;quot;Swiss Beer&amp;quot; then went down and explored the town and lake. Looking across the lake someone thought that Italy was on the other side, so we looked it up on google maps to find that it was indeed Italy.... but then it went back into Switzerland again. Have a look on a map and it&amp;#39;s quite strange. It&amp;#39;s called an &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Enclave_and_exclave&quot;&gt;enclave&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; apparently. See &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;maps.google.ch&#x2F;maps?q=lugano&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Lugano,+Ticino&amp;amp;gl=ch&amp;amp;ei=oZJZTIPUBpeHOPePrOAI&amp;amp;ved=0CBsQ8gEwAA&amp;amp;ll=45.973583,8.9748&amp;amp;spn=0.028871,0.084543&amp;amp;z=14&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on google maps to see what I&amp;#39;m on about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;swiss_beer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we went out on paddle boats on the lake. Not something I would have chosen to do normally but it ended up being really fun. At first we played pirates and hi-jacked each others boats. In the process of which I lost my sunglasses into the lake, and also Ben (from Canada) broke a seat of the boat trying to throw me overboard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boat I ended up on (not my original boat) went for a 30min paddle to the other side of the lake (but not to Italy as we were told we weren&amp;#39;t allowed to) to try and paddle under a huge fountain... which we did. And it was cold. Also really fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where we were paddling they were also setting up the fireworks on a boat for that night&amp;#39;s firework show (as it was Swiss National Day).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ate lunch in the park then a few of us went for a walk along the lake to see how far it went around the headland, and saw some guys jumping off a bridge. One guy was crazy and jumped off a rock that was about 3m in from the water and had to dodge all these tree branches to get though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lakehouse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we got the funicular (like a cable car train) to the top of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Monte_San_Salvatore&quot;&gt;Monte San Salvatore&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and got a 360 view of the area. There was a fairly (there was a plaque thing from the 1800&amp;#39;s on the wall) old church at the top, which is a long way to go if you live at the bottom of the mountain (there was no houses on the way up).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;funicular1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;funicular2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;monte1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;monte2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;monte3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then back down and to an Italian Pizzeria for dinner. The pizza I got was a Calzone something which was basically just salami and cheese, but tasted very nice. They had like 3 different types of cheeses in it and it worked well. Also because it was a Calzone it was like folded in half and cooked that way, which I&amp;#39;d never heard of but looked pretty cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then fireworks afterwards, we jumped the fence to the park which was locked and watched from in there, so got to sit down and have front row seats. Was very different to the fireworks in Zurich but still incredible. Afterwards one of the boats was on fire (probably the fireworks boat) so we watched the police boats try and put it out (took them a while).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;fireworks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when it was finished it was cool to watch the lake as hundreds of boats all left at once and  you could see all the lights. They were all honking there horns and letting of their own fireworks as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day was bungee, then swimming in the Verzasca River afterwards, which reminded me of stoney creek but was much much prettier and also way colder. There was a 13m high &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Lavertezzo&quot;&gt;bridge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that people were jumping off but I was happy jumping off a rock next to it, that was probably only 7m high.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently the water was 10m deep just below the bridge, and as we were leaving some guys started scuba diving in the water, so it must have been. The water was so clear you could still see the bottom though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;verzasca.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;verzasca2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;verzasca3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a bus to the bottom to the mountain, a train to some other town that had a huge castle on the hill that we didn&amp;#39;t have time to look at then back to Zurich and then Turgi by about 10.30 that night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Rafting Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-rafting-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-rafting-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-rafting-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;dsc_1714.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rafting&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whitewater rafting was really fun, but I must say it would have to be better in Australia purely because the river we rafted down consisted of 4 degree glacial water.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wet-suiting up, we caught a bus up into the mountains where we were told about all the safety rules and told what to do for each of the commands from our guide. Our guide &amp;quot;Dougie&amp;quot; was from NZ and quite a funny lad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water was absolutely freezing. Our hands all went numb within a minute or so. After a few minutes it wasn&amp;#39;t so bad as you could no longer feel anything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first rapids were quite intense and lots of fun, and by the time we had to hop out (because there was a section that is Class 5) I was used to the water. The first section was down the Black Lütschine, and we had to hop out just after this river joined with the White Lütschine, which was just awesome when they met. Something to do with the rocks that the glaciers are on, one river is white(ish) and one is black(ish - more grey) but when they meet there is a distinct colour difference down the middle of the river until they slowly merge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first leg was Class 3, and the last section was Class 4, which was just insane fun. It didn&amp;#39;t last too long though and then the last bit was just cruising down the river towards the lake. Because the water level was so high we had to limbo under a few bridges which was cool, some were like 50cm between the bottom of the bridge and the water.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all hopped out for a bit for a swim, which was fun for like 2 seconds and then just like going for a swim in ice. But being pushed by rapids felt cool, but we all hopped back in the raft as quick as we could.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up coming out into one of the lakes, which is like 850m deep according to our guide. We put our hands in the water and you could feel an immediate change in temperature once we paddled out of the way of the river mouth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where we loaded the rafts back on there was a family of swans, with the parent swans trying to attack anyone that came too close. Was amazing to see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went back to the rafting place for a free beer and some cheese.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After rafting we went back to the hostel for dinner, then to the coop (like Woolworths or Coles) to buy beer (in single cans). It feels so weird being able to drink in the street, especially as one stage there was a big group of us walking past some police with beers in hand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went to some lobby&#x2F;bar thing that I&amp;#39;m not really sure what it was, and there was a St.Bernard at the front. There was also a dog inside at the bar that was walking around looking for pats. Was quite strange to see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on we heard some loud noise and everyone stopped talking to witness some random people walk in with giant cowbells - video on Facebook. We then realised that there was a wedding going on in one of the function rooms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we got a train up into the mountains to see a waterfall. The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tr%C3%BCmmelbach_Falls&quot;&gt;Trümmelbach Gletscherwasserfälle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was easily one of the coolest things I&amp;#39;ve seen in my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is where the water comes from for the white river that joined the river we rafted, and is 2 degrees, it comes from a glacier way up above although we couldn&amp;#39;t even see it from down the bottom. I think most of it comes from the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Jungfrau&quot;&gt;Jungfrau&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;p1020522.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;cave.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;cave_outside.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the waterfall, we went up to Mürren via cable car, and then hiked back down. It was a very cool walking track with random waterfalls the whole way down, but had very sore knees by the time I got to the bottom. It was also weird that at the bottom of the mountain it was 25 degrees, and when we hopped out of the cable car at the top it was like 17 degrees - felt like walking into air-con but outside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;jump.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;forest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;valley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;valley2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
