<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Alex Guinman - Vietnam</title>
    <subtitle>Personal blog</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/vietnam/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/vietnam/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Halong Bay</title>
        <published>2011-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2011-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/halong-bay/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/halong-bay/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/halong-bay/">&lt;p&gt;images: 2011-08-02-halong-bay&#x2F;P1080464.jpg&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a bus from Hanoi to Halong, and were joined by some other travellers, most of which were from Australia except for 3 people from New Zealand. Our guide Viet informed us that if we were lucky we might still be able to stay the night on the bay, and that they were making some calls, but that it was up to the government as they had closed the bay to all boats as a safety precaution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visited some rice paddies and another marble factory on the way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080367.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started to pour rain while we were at the marble factory and so we didn&amp;#39;t have high hopes of being allowed on the boat, but our guide gave us good news when we were back on the bus that we would not only be allowed out on the boat, but they we would be staying the night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Halong to find that the weather was perfect.
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080384.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we got to go inside a small cave that opened up inside one of the islands. We were told that there was monkeys living on the island, but we didn&amp;#39;t see any. Then in the afternoon, we got to go for a swim - jumping off the boat into the water. I had two attempts at a front flip - both of which ended in immense pain from me doing a backflop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080418.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080423.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The food was excellent, we got course after course of delicious seafood. At night we stayed up on deck drinking beer and talking to the ship crew and the captain even challenged me to a game of chess. The crew was really young and cool to talk to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080435.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following day we anchored at a beach, and found a track that took us to the top of the island from which there was a magnificent view - probably one of the highlights of the whole trip for me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080461.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080464.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080466.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080469.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080483.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we were back on the mainland and on our way home, Viet informed us that they never actually did open the bay back up to boats and that in fact they had basically bribed the port authority to allow us to go out. It was super dodgy and so they hadn&amp;#39;t told us in advance in case it made us worried. It explained why there was so little boats out on the water. It made the trip even more special as we basically had the bay all to ourselves with the exception of the local fisherman that lived out on the water. I don&amp;#39;t think many people would have had the same experience, and when we talked to the guys that went the week before us, they told us of how there had been tonnes of boats on the water with people coming up to your boat peddling goods.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus ride back to Hanoi was fairly uneventful, with the exception of some really intense near-misses with oncoming traffic and some cows that were wandering on the road.
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080516.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our last night we went to dinner with our kiwi buddies, and had some awesome Prawn Hot Pot.
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;halong-bay&#x2F;P1080527.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vietnam was an awesome country, much better than I was expecting and I would love to go back some time and see some more of the rural areas as opposed to the cities.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hanoi</title>
        <published>2011-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2011-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hanoi-and-halong-bay/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hanoi-and-halong-bay/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hanoi-and-halong-bay/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hanoi-and-halong-bay&#x2F;p1080297.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hanoi Street&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really hated Hanoi. It was so cramped, dirty, smelly and hot. So hot in fact that Tom and I even came back to the hotel for the middle of the day to get out of the heat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hanoi-and-halong-bay&#x2F;rubbish.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hanoi-and-halong-bay&#x2F;P1080300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike the other cities we visited, we spent ages on the first day trying to find a cheap place to find some descent food. We expected it to be much like Saigon, but prices were a lot higher here. We had also planned to do our souvineer shopping in Hanoi so we didn&amp;#39;t have to lug our stuff around the country, but were dissapointed to find that there was a much smaller range of things for sale and people weren&amp;#39;t as eager to barter.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hanoi-and-halong-bay&#x2F;P1080344.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went exploring and visited the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Temple_of_Literature,_Hanoi&quot;&gt;Temple of Literature&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which was a university dedicated to the teachings of Confucius.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that we went to see the Ho Chi Min Mausoleum. Apparently he was mummified (against his wishes) and you can go see the body. Only on certain days though, and when we visited it was closed up with some very serious security patrolling the building ensuring nobody got close.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hanoi-and-halong-bay&#x2F;P1080327.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near the mauseleum is the Ho Chi Mihn Museum, which is a really bizarre museum that didn&amp;#39;t make much sense. We had no idea what most of the displays were meant to represent, but it was good to be inside the air con. Outside the museum was the one-pillar pagolla, which was pretty awesome but bizarelly had some trippy rave lights inside which I thought cheapened it a bit but also made it awesome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after our big day in the heat, we headed back to hotel to find out that we had a missed call from Travel Indochina to say that there was a cyclone coming and so our trip to Halong Bay had been cancelled. Needless to say, we were pretty bummed. We were offered an alternative trip to Sapa, but neither of us were keen for a massive train ride and the potential of catching malaria. We organised to stay another night in Hanoi, and hope that the weather cleared up enough that we could still at least see Halong Bay, even if the bay itself was closed to boats.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not looking forward to another day in Hanoi, but that night it rained and it became a whole new city for me. The air was fresher, the streets cleaner and most the pollution and smell washed away. We went to some markets and otherwise just walked around the city and it was a huge improvement on the day before.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hai Van Pass</title>
        <published>2011-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2011-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hai-van-pass/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hai-van-pass/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hai-van-pass/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;img_1921.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Marble Mountains&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next destination was to be Hue, but this time we got to take the scenic route rather than fly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, we were taken to the marble mountains which had a massive stone staircase to the top, at which there was various temples and Buddhist shrines.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;IMG_1934.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a massive cave which was used in the war to hide from the American troops. There was a hole in the ceiling where it had been bombed during the war.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;IMG_1959.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was lots of tourists at the mountains, but unlike the places we had been previously, a lot of them were Vietnamese. Lots of families asked us to get photos with them. It was as if we were celebrities - very weird.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the base of the mountain were various stores at which marble sculptures were sold. They used to use marble from the mountains, but now it is imported. The sculptures were very impressive and the amount of work that must go into them is insane.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;P1080028.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;P1080032.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped quickly at China Beach for a photo. It was scorching hot on that day, so we tried not to stay in the sun too long and left pretty quickly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;IMG_1988.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stopped at a museum at which there was various Hindu statues. These were taken from various ancient temples and yet it was all there with no security. It was a pretty different experience to say the Louvre where everything is behind glass.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;IMG_1998.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;IMG_2006.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get to Hue from Danang we travelled along the Hoi Van Pass, which had a magnificent view but was a pretty dangerous road. We overtook a petrol tanker at one stage around a blind corner and nearly hit a bus.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;IMG_2027.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, the road to Hue was quite uneventful. We were pretty sad to be leaving our tour guide and driver behind, as they had been super friendly guys and great to have with us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hai-van-pass&#x2F;P1080059.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hue</title>
        <published>2011-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2011-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hue/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hue/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hue/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;p1080207.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Imperial City&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving in Hue, we had a quick walk around the city in the afternoon to see what there was to do, and made our way to the markets. They were rank, they really even worse than the one at Hoi An, which is saying a lot. We really couldn&amp;#39;t find anything interesting to see, so we booked a tour for the next day to the outlying areas, as we hadn&amp;#39;t planned anything and didn&amp;#39;t no what else there was to do.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080066.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom was really keen to get a cheap massage while we were in Vietnam and as we had nothing else planned it seemed the best opportunity. I had never had a professional massage before so was up for it, but we both agreed we didn&amp;#39;t want to go to any dodgy places where they might &amp;quot;love you long time&amp;quot;, so we just went to the one at the hotel. Turns out it was a bit dodgy after all and we had to make it clear that we weren&amp;#39;t looking for &amp;#39;extras&amp;#39;. There was a Thai dance school there that night performing as well, and they made us (everyone) dance with them for a bit at the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we went on our Hue tour. It didn&amp;#39;t get off to a great start, as the air-con on the bus was broken and it was another scorcher of a day. First up was the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.vietnamtourism.com&#x2F;hue&#x2F;e_pages&#x2F;lt_lminhmang.htm&quot;&gt;Minh Mang Tomb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. There was hardly anyone there and it was nice and peaceful compared to everywhere else we had been on this trip. There was a few cool temples but mostly it was just a huge garden.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080090.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080096.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080104.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next tomb, the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tomb_of_Khai_Dinh&quot;&gt;Tomb of Khai Dinh&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, was completely different, with no plants at all. There was some cool looking statues and the building had some incredible artwork inside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080163.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080169.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went to see a Kung Fu show, which was super impressive. A kid did the break bricks with your head trick, and while he managed it, it clearly hurt like hell as he was rubbing his head for ages afterwards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080175.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also went to a village where they make Conical Hats and Incense. There was some paintings there as well, as there is all over Vietnam but I thought this one looked especially cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080182.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final tomb (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tu_Duc&quot;&gt;Tu Duc&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)we didn&amp;#39;t enter, as we were told it was pretty much the same as the Minh Mang Tomb, and so we saved ourselves some money on the entry. Tom had an argument with a local, when he bought a coke and it took ages for the lady to give him change for what would have been about $50. I was pretty sure she was going to pretend that he never gave it to her, was quite amusing but concerning to watch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we visited the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Imperial_City,_Hu%E1%BA%BF&quot;&gt;Imperial City&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and then the Forbidden City within. It was sad to see how much had been destroyed in the war.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080229.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last stop was the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Thien_Mu_Pagoda&quot;&gt;Thien Mu Pagoda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The highlight of which for Tom and I was that they had the car from the famous image of the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Thich_Quang_Duc#Self-immolation&quot;&gt;Burning Man&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, as the monk had come from that temple.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080266.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we got a boat back down the Perfume River to Hue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hue&#x2F;P1080274.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, back at the hotel, Tom was talking to Lily and she asked us how our bike rides went. It was at this point that we realized that we had booked a bike tour for Hue, and that is why we didn&amp;#39;t have anything else planned. So we wasted about $25 and missed out on visiting some local villages. Oh well, the day was so hot we were thoroughly relieved that we hadn&amp;#39;t spent it riding pushbikes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hoi An</title>
        <published>2011-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2011-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hoi-an/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hoi-an/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/hoi-an/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;p1070814.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hoi An&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After flying from Saigon, we arrived in Danang International Airport. It was about the size of Rockhampton airport but super dodgy looking for an &amp;#39;international&amp;#39; airport.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1080057.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our driver took us to Hoi An, and on the way we picked up our tour guide (that we did not know that we had paid for). Our guide recommended a place to get some suits made, so we headed there first. We went to a tailor called Blue, and got fitted for our suits. I just wanted a suit, and didn&amp;#39;t much care or know what I wanted but the ladies at the shop wanted us to specify everything down to the tiniest detail, even asking us what angle we wanted our pockets to be at.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1080001.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we chose our materials and got measured up for our suits, we got taken to our resort, the Riverside Beach Resort. It was super impressive and had an awesome view of the river, and right near the beach.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1070738.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After checking in , we tried to find somewhere to have lunch, and went to a place across the road and got some tiger prawns. Notice the clothes shop within the restaurant. It was here we first discovered the awesome local beer that is Biere Larue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1070746.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some lunch we headed down to the beach.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1070752.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom decided in the afternoon that it was time to get food poisoning, so I chose something to read for the resort&amp;#39;s library of clearly pirated and photocopied books and enjoyed the view of the river.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, Tom was feeling a little bit better and we had an appointment back in the city for the first fitting of our suits, so we hired some push-bikes for the day (for $5) and went for a ride into town.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic was much calmer than in the city, but we still had to pay close attention to everyone around us, as there was the same disregard for the road rules. Riding bikes was super fun, and we got to see a lot more of the city.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we went for a ride out of town a bit, and had some local kids run after us on our bikes yelling &amp;quot;Hello&amp;quot; over and over. It was pretty special because they seemed genuinely excited to see us and talk to us in English.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one of the western restaurants we went to, we got Banana Pancakes. I&amp;#39;d never had them before but wanted to see what the fuss was about in the Jack Johnson song.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1070799.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had signed up for Red Bridge Cooking School, and part of the tour was to visit the local markets. I&amp;#39;m not sure if it&amp;#39;s a good thing seeing how unhygienic everything is, but at least we knew everything was fresh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1070833.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual cooking class was excellent. The chef was hilarious, everything was set-up and ready to go and the food tasted amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1070908.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our cooking class, our guide took us to a local pub, where he shouted us beers that cost about 15c a bottle. We also got to try some sea snail despite being ridiculously bloated from gorging on all the amazing food we cooked earlier.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1070986.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A French tour guide joined us for a drink as well, as it was his birthday. A good time was had.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the beach there was various jet-ski&amp;#39;s in the water that you could hire. It was pretty fun riding along, but they were slower than I expected. Tom said the one&amp;#39;s in Australia are much faster and more fun, as these one&amp;#39;s had clearly been thrashed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exploring the city on our last night, they had lanterns floating down the river, and the whole town seemed to be out and about. It was extremely beautiful.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;hoi-an&#x2F;P1070815.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hoi An was probably one of the highlights of our trip to Vietnam, it&amp;#39;s very touristy (especially Australians) but still an authentic and awesome beach town well worth a visit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Ho Chi Minh City (Saigon)</title>
        <published>2011-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2011-07-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/ho-chi-minh-city-saigon/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/ho-chi-minh-city-saigon/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/ho-chi-minh-city-saigon/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;ho-chi-minh-city-saigon&#x2F;p1070481.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Saigon&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Saigon to see our driver out the front of the airport with a sign with our names on it, which was a bit of a luxury. However, we had barely even read the sign before he waved at us and walked off, looking back every now and then to make sure we were following. Then he pointed at the taxi pick up zone and disappeared. We were still trying to remember what he looked like when he came back with the car and we got in - it was pretty funny watching Tom trying to make small talk with the guy, as he didn&amp;#39;t speak any English and had no idea what we were saying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traffic was exactly how we expected it, and yet it wasn&amp;#39;t. It&amp;#39;s just as busy as you see in videos, but somehow it all just works and for some insane reason I felt just as safe as in the traffic back home. The main difference is the sheer amount of motorbikes on the road, they were everywhere and heading in all directions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our hotel was well situated in the middle of the city, and had a pretty schmick lobby. Once we got out of the elevator on our floor, we were greeted by some truly stuffy air, it was probably the stalest air I have ever tasted, even staler then when we leave the beach house locked up and air-tight for a few months. In the room it was a bit better, and we had air-con that cooled us down. We had some complimentary water waiting for us, which was a good reminder that we couldn&amp;#39;t go trusting any tap water in Vietnam.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We dumped our bags and then went out to quickly explore the nearby &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;B%E1%BA%BFn_Th%C3%A0nh_Market&quot;&gt;Bến Thành Markets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which had all kinds of clothes and watches for super cheap prices. There was also some epic looking food, and we saw crab being cooked on a grill in the middle of the street. The night market was literally just people set up stalls in the middle of the street, and motorbikes weaved around us as we looked at all the stalls.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we decided to join a tour of the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;C%E1%BB%A7_Chi_tunnels&quot;&gt;Chu Chi Tunnels&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which was $12USD including the bus out there. On the way we stopped at a handicapped art factory, where disabled people made beautiful paintings and carvings out of duck shells and Halong Bay clams.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;ho-chi-minh-city-saigon&#x2F;P1070501.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual tunnels probably wouldn&amp;#39;t have been that exciting by themselves but when you are told the history it was incredible. The tunnels were tiny and yet the Vietcong lived underground in them for years. It would have been horrible. We saw a crater in the ground were a B52 bomb had hit, and got to crawl through the tunnels and see how small it all was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;ho-chi-minh-city-saigon&#x2F;P1070592.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we went off to see the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;War_Remnants_Museum_%28Ho_Chi_Minh_City%29&quot;&gt;American War Remnants Museum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This was pretty horrifying as well. It is full of photos from the war, but worst of all for me was the Agent Orange room, which had mutated foetuses in jars showing how a lot of the babies born in the years after the war were mutated. There was photos and photos of mutated people and it explained why there was so many handicap factories across the country. It had a very anti-American feel to the place, but seemed pretty justified. Below is a tiger cage, which apparently was used to keep up to 7 people in each cage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;ho-chi-minh-city-saigon&#x2F;P1070680.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went to the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Reunification_Palace&quot;&gt;Reunification Palace&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where the war was ended which was the old presidential palace. It had some pretty cool rooms, the war room in the basement was quite interesting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;ho-chi-minh-city-saigon&#x2F;P1070691.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our last night, we went to see a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Water_puppets&quot;&gt;Vietnamese Water Puppet Show&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It was much cooler than I expected. There was a live band that narrated the show - in Vietnamese, we had no idea what was going on but it was pretty impressive regardless.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;ho-chi-minh-city-saigon&#x2F;P1070725.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
