<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Alex Guinman - Fiji</title>
      <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au</link>
      <description>Personal blog</description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/fiji/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Fiji - Pacific Harbour</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-pacific-harbour/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-pacific-harbour/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-pacific-harbour/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-pacific-harbour&#x2F;p1110509.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Uprising Beach View&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-pacific-harbour&#x2F;p1110203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1110203&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday we got the bus to the Uprising Beach Resort in Pacific Harbour, where we stayed for 7 nights. We had lunch at the restaurant while we waited for check-in time and I had fish and chips (the fish was awesome) and Rachael had Kokoda (photo right) which was fish in a coconut shell with Cassava chips (sort of a cross between potato and cooking banana).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-pacific-harbour&#x2F;p1110208.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1110208&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our beachfront bure (pronounced like Boo-Ray) was quite awesome. Had really high ceilings and good air flow so was pretty cool (didn&amp;#39;t have air-con) and had a little verandah where you could look out at the beach. We were the closest to the pool and restaurant as well so we didn&amp;#39;t have to walk far for dinner each night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-pacific-harbour&#x2F;p1110244.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Outdoor Shower&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought one of the coolest things was our outdoor shower. There were plants in there as well and it was cool having a shower in nature, especially at night time you could look up and see the stars. Only negative to it I could think of was it would be cold in winter being outdoors. I thought of a another negative when I had a shower later in the week during a massive thunderstorm and there was lightning around.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we went in to the Arts Village in Pacific Harbour (about 10mins walk) to look around. There was some cool buildings and bridges, it was very touristy as there was a theatre area where they have native Fijian ceremony displays.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-pacific-harbour&#x2F;p1110231.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arts Village&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had lunch there and got fish burgers, but they weren&amp;#39;t particularly nice, as the fish wasn&amp;#39;t as fresh as the rest of the fish we ate in Fiji. We were told there would be a bon fire at the resort that night, but it rained so it was cancelled. Rachael was super excited for this bon fire each night but it would always rain in the afternoon and the wood would get wet. Finally on our last night it was dry, but at about 9:30 there was no signs of anything happening so we went back to the bure and went to bed, only to find it burned on the beach the next morning. Rachael was pretty annoyed. They must have lit it fairly late though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monday &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-pacific-harbour&#x2F;fiji-suva&quot;&gt;we went into Suva&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and then I got sick that afternoon. Tuesday we didn&amp;#39;t get up to much, as I was still feeling a bit average, although we did go for a kayak in the afternoon just off the beach.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday we went for a snorkel in the ocean out the front of our resort, it was just a short boat ride and I think it was &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;goo.gl&#x2F;maps&#x2F;5UPlc&quot;&gt;this reef&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The weather Tuesday had been brilliant, but it was overcast and rainy Wednesday morning when we went for the snorkel, which was a bit of a bummer as it made it harder to see. The coral was still super bright though, with a fair few baby fish swimming around. Rachael was worried about sharks eating us, but we didn&amp;#39;t even see baby sharks let alone the big &amp;quot;friendly&amp;quot; sharks of Fiji. You can go shark feeding in Fiji without a cage, because apparently all the sharks in Fiji are &amp;quot;friendly sharks&amp;quot; even though they are Bull and Tiger sharks that you feed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachael had the fish of the day Tuesday night and it tasted amazing, and for lunch on Wednesday I tried some freshly caught Walu fish which was equally amazing. Frozen stuff from the supermarket really doesn&amp;#39;t compare to freshly caught fish.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday we had planned to do a village visit and drink some Kava, but there wasn&amp;#39;t enough people so we booked white water rafting for Friday instead as that was the only tour that seemed good for the price. Thursday we didn&amp;#39;t get up to much, although we did play Volleyball with the locals and some of the resort staff in the afternoon. It was pretty fun until a storm started with really close lightning, and the beach volleyball court turned into a water polo court. The thunder during the storm was really impressive, it sounded different to back home. I think it was reverberating between Beqa Island and the main land because it was really drawn out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For lunch on Thursday we went for a walk up the road to a local looking restaurant we had seen on the bus to Suva. I got the duck curry special which was super spicy and full of bones but tasted great. It reminded of the chicken curry that Jayantha (a guy from work from Sri Lanka) made for us, which tasted incredible but was difficult to eat on account of all the random bones and whole pieces of herbs and the abundance of chilli powder. Despite tasting much better, I prefer the convenience of a normal Indian curry sans bones.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-pacific-harbour&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&quot;&gt;the rafting on Friday&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I got sick again. But this time Rachael got sick as well, so after a terrible nights sleep we were more than happy to check out Saturday morning and get the bus back to Nandi and head home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Fiji - Rafting Upper Navua River</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&#x2F;imgp8896.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fiji Rafting&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easily the highlight of the trip was white-water rafting down the &amp;quot;Grand Canyon of Fiji&amp;quot;. That is what the posters called it, but two American&amp;#39;s we met who had been there said it didn&amp;#39;t even compare. It was still magnificent though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got picked up from the hotel in a 4x4 again and taken to a nearby resort, The Pearl, same as we did for snorkelling. It&amp;#39;s kind of dodgy really, both cars were full of junk in the back and the seat belts in the back seat were stuck under the seat so you couldn&amp;#39;t use them. It was only a short drive so didn&amp;#39;t really matter but was expecting more for the money we paid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&#x2F;p1110513.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1110513&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there we got a bus and after a drive on the highway, headed off-road on some beautiful tracks into the rainforest. After a briefing about entering a national park and how we couldn&amp;#39;t leave anything behind (including poo - they told us they had special bags if we needed) and putting on our life jackets, we went for a short hike to the rafts. The really annoying thing about not leaving anything behind while in the conservation area, was at the end of the day as we were driving back, the staff had no problem throwing their rubbish out the window of the car (we saw them special times) once they were out of the conservation area.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&#x2F;p1110527.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1110527&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual rapids were only a class 2-3 and weren&amp;#39;t as fun as the one&amp;#39;s I did in Switzerland, but the scenery was stunning. Some of the canyon walls even had coral in them, from long ago when it was all under water.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&#x2F;imgp8834.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMGP8834&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&#x2F;imgp8837.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMGP8837&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&#x2F;imgp9138.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMGP9138&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&#x2F;imgp9052.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMGP9052&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conservation area ended with a massive waterfall, which we got to stop and stand under. The water was way more powerful than I was expecting and super cold. As we were getting close to the village where we were to hop out, there &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;goo.gl&#x2F;maps&#x2F;BVmRD&quot;&gt;was a spot where two rivers converged&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and like in Switzerland you could clearly see the two colours and determine which water come from which stream.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-rafting-upper-navua-river&#x2F;p1110602.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1110602&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rafting finished at the Wainadiro village, where there was the skinniest dog I had ever seen. It looked like it was about to fall over from starvation, it was pretty sad. From there we had another off-road drive back, but this time the bus got bogged when it tried to overtake the truck with the rafting gear in it. So we had a little more adventure at the end of the day waiting for them to get out the snatch strap and pull it out. Our shoes were absolutely soaked by the end of the day, and Rachael had old lady feet. Since it&amp;#39;s constantly raining in Fiji, all our clothes were still wet when had to pack them for the plane, so our luggage was pretty smelly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Fiji - Suva</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-suva/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-suva/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-suva/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-suva&#x2F;bus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fiji Bus&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a bus into Suva on Monday morning to check out the big city. The bus in was an adventure, we got a local bus, which was only $3.30 FJD to Suva from Uprising. The bus stopped for anyone on the way that waved it down, even in narrow sections of the highway at the top of hills, or in the middle of a turn off so that it was blocking traffic from turning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point we had to stop for petrol, so the bus pulled into a service station and we waited while the driver filled it up. We then had another wait at the main bus station while someone got on and counted the number of tickets sold. All up it took us over 2 hours to get to Suva, even though the return trip on the way back took about 1hour - since we paid $5 for the express bus.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-suva&#x2F;p1110283.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shark&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suva itself was a bit of a let down. First up we went to the museum, with various people stopping us on the way asking us where we were from and I assume trying to sell us things. The museum itself was pretty good. They had some rafts that were used to go between the island back in the day - impressive what can be made with just wood and vines. The picture to the right was pretty cool, one tribe used shark tooth swords and puffer fish helmets in combat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that was depressing was the conversion of all the locals from their local religion to Christianity. There old religion sounded much better to me, and it&amp;#39;s sad how the Europeans just came in and converted everyone. Hinduism and Islam are also popular there though, so at least there is some diversity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual town itself reminded me a bit of Vietnam, very dirty and busy streets with lots of small shops. The prices weren&amp;#39;t as impressive as Vietnam though, things were only slightly cheaper than Australia once you calculated for the currency difference. One thing that Rachael thought was pretty cool was the markets, again they reminded me of the markets we went to in Vietnam.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a few hours we got tired of walking around, so headed back to Pacific Harbour on the express bus, they bus even had a movie playing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Fiji - Nadi</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-nadi/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-nadi/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2013/fiji-nadi/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-nadi&#x2F;p1110188.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nadi Rainbow&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the flight over to Fiji, we flew over some other islands, which were probably New Caledonia. Those islands, and the reefs of Fiji itself looked awesome from the plane. As we are landing I also noticed a pretty cool temple, which a quick Google reveals it is called the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Sri_Siva_Subramaniya_temple&quot;&gt;Sri Siva Subramaniya temple&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We later saw it on the bus&#x2F;in and out of Nadi but didn&amp;#39;t visit it for a close look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nadi, pronounced Nandi with a silent &amp;#39;n&amp;#39; which the Fijian&amp;#39;s seem to enjoy (we later ordered a dish called Kokoda which was pronounced &amp;#39;Kakonda&amp;#39;, was the town&#x2F;city where we landed. Walking in the airport we were greeted by some guys on the ukelele and customs officials in Hawaiian shirts. They love their Hawaiian shirts in Fiji, but Rachael tells me they are more stylish then the one&amp;#39;s worn in Australia.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a taxi to the resort, which was a crappy old car painted yellow like a New York taxi and the engine sounded terrible. Our driver stalled it 3 times in a row at one stage when we had to stop for traffic at the top of a slight hill.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first impressions driving in was that it was a bit of a cross between Vietnam and Australia. A lot more unkempt and run-down then Australia (more like Vietnam) but fairly spacious and more ordered, with road signs that seemed to be mostly adhered to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-nadi&#x2F;p1110202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nadi Graves&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were to spend the first night at Nadi Bay Hotel Resort, before heading to Pacific Harbour, and were in a dorm with a nice guy from Nottingham. Interestingly there was graves next to our dorm, which were probably old resort staff. Apparently it&amp;#39;s okay to be buried in your own backyard in Fiji, as we saw graves at houses fairly often.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went for a walk to look around and saw a 3 car pileup with one car lodging itself underneath the rear end of a Hilux. We didn&amp;#39;t bother getting a taxi into town, and thought it was a fair walk to the beach (it wasn&amp;#39;t) so just went back to the hotel and had dinner. Food prices in Fiji are about the same as in Oz, except in Fijian dollars and so relative to our currency meals were about half price.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we waited for the Coral Sun bus to Pacific Harbour, and had our first experience with &amp;#39;Fiji Time&amp;#39; as it was about 20mins late, despite saying on the booking we had to wait 15mins early. The booking was a bit of a failure in general as when we called up to double check where we were getting picked up they didn&amp;#39;t have a record of our booking even though we could sent a confirmation email which we had printed out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2013&#x2F;fiji-nadi&#x2F;p1110707.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nadi Beach&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we came back from Pacific Harbour at the end of the trip, I had a chance to download offline maps of Nadi on my phone and we realised the beach wasn&amp;#39;t far at all. Upon going for a walk to check it out, we probably could have done without as it was covered in rubbish and not that appealing. We did have lunch at a cool Japanese restaurant the day before we left though, which &lt;em&gt;was&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; worth the very short walk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
