<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Alex Guinman - France</title>
      <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au</link>
      <description>Personal blog</description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/france/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Paris and Versailles</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/paris/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/paris/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/paris/">&lt;p&gt;After very little sleep on the bus, and leaving over an hour late, it meant we arrived late in Paris and so hit peak hour traffic, making us later still and stuck in traffic at a crawl. The bus actually went near our hostel and then we spent probably an hour in traffic after that getting to the bus stop on the other side of the city.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus depot itself was pretty terrible, essentially a giant car park near a metro station. Luckily we finished there and didn&#x27;t wait there as there was no toilets, no cover and no food. We got a train to the hostel to find out they actually charge by the hour for luggage storage. So we had planned to go into the city but instead paid for a couple of hours and went to get food until we could check-in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;melting_house.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Train%20station%20near%20hostel&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hostel had a booking desk, and the lady told us we could buy skip the line tickets from her for much cheaper due to a special deal and it also included audio-guides. It seemed to be good to be true but she was adamant. Turns out she was full of shit though, as we got there and they said no we had to line up (which took 2 hours) and then it didn&amp;#39;t even include an audioguide.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the same hostel we stayed at &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&quot;&gt;last time&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and we thought was great, except this time I have to give the opposite review. So at this point neither of us was in a particularly good mood, and Rachael was starting to get sick so was at a point where she just wanted to cancel the holiday and go home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we made it to the front of the line though, and the catacombs themselves were incredible and worth the wait. The first part was just miners tunnels which were pretty cool, but not what we waited 2 hours to see. And then you get to the bones, of which there was a mind-blowing amount and the tunnels just kept on going. It was hard to fathom that they were all people once and the sheer number of bodies dumped down there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;catacombs1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;catacombs2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;catacombs4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;catacombs5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;catacombs6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in a much better mood when we came out, and then went to visit the Luxembourg Gardens.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;luxembourg1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;luxembourg2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning we went to the Château de Versailles. Which we got there early but was still packed with tourists, which despite this was also incredible. It was like the Vatican with the amazing paintings on every surface except even grander. Unfortunately lots of the palace was closed for renovations which was annoying because it didn&amp;#39;t say this anywhere when we booked the tickets or even the tourist information they gave out once you got in. The audio guide would say to go one way and then someone would say sorry you can&amp;#39;t go down there it&amp;#39;s closed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;versailles.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;versailles1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was also interesting to see what was considered valuable then, as the grandest part was the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Hall_of_Mirrors&quot;&gt;Hall of Mirrors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which at the time showed incredible wealth as most people could not afford a mirror, let alone an entire hallway of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;versailles2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you get out of the palace itself, it was time to visit the gardens. They are also incredible in their scale, better then any other gardens we have been to and the fountains were all turned off that day, so I imagine it&amp;#39;s even better when they are on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;versailles3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;versailles4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was another whole grounds in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Hameau_de_la_Reine&quot;&gt;Marie Antoinette garden&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which was probably the highlight as there were heaps of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.google.com.au&#x2F;maps&#x2F;@48.8145288,2.109453,285a,35y,355.57h,39.38t&#x2F;data=!3m1!1e3&quot;&gt;different paths and styles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and we probably didn&amp;#39;t even see a quarter of the grounds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally we headed back into the city, and had some delicious Sri Lankan for dinner.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning Rachael was sick, so I went out myself to the see La Basilique du Sacré Cœur de Montmartre which has a great view of the city. I got there pretty early and there wasn&amp;#39;t many people around, just scam artists and some guy that wanted to sell me weed. It had a nice view but couldn&amp;#39;t really see any landmarks, and could only just see Eiffel Tower if you looked at the right angle. The church itself was pretty impressive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;basilica1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;basilica2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last time we stayed in Paris we thought it was great and wanted to stay longer, but this time we were mostly glad to leave. We were glad we came back for a second visit though, as the Catacombs and Versailles where well worth it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The airport seemed to have changed a lot since last time we were there, and was a much better experience then last time. It was a nice quick flight and crazy how small the English channel is from the air. Was cool seeing Dover after being there could just make out the white cliffs and the harbour and ships.
Paris seemed dirtier and not as nice as last time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;paris&#x2F;dover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Paris</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-paris/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-paris/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-paris/">&lt;p&gt;Coming in on the train in the morning we got to see some epic countryside. France was a lovely country and I want to go back again and see more of it one day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we got off our train we needed to catch the Metro to our Hostel. The ticket system sucks. There was only one ticket machine and about 40 people lined up to use it. After we finally got our ticket we were on our way, and despite being very crowded it was pretty convenient and cheap.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as we got there we knew that this Hostel was going to be awesome. And having stayed there I would say it was the best Hostel I have ever been to so far. Only problem is, it&#x27;s a long way from anything interesting, which isn&#x27;t a big deal if you use the Metro, but as we didn&#x27;t really no what we were doing and had a bus tour (but didn&#x27;t know the stops) we started walking to the Louvre and trying to find a bus stop on the way. There was several but they were really badly signed, and we didn&#x27;t find them until later when we had a brochure with all the stops. So we ended up walking to the Louvre.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a lovely walk, but Rachael wasn&#x27;t in a good mood (I think all the walking was starting to get to her) so I don&#x27;t think she enjoyed it. She was much happier once we finally got the Louvre. Well that&#x27;s not true, I said that we were at the Louvre as soon as I saw it but she wouldn&#x27;t beleive me until we walked all the way around to the front entrance which has the glass pyramid. Having talked to someone the next day, this is the worst entrance to go to because it means you have to line up for an hour or so instead of 5mins at a side entrance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;louvre1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;louvre2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So having waited in line, we got to go inside. The sheer enormity of the place is incredible. It is huge. I had been told by many people that you need several days to see it all, but we saw most things in 4 hours. And after 4 hours we had well and truly had enough and wanted to leave. Every room had something cool in it, but the place is so huge and there is so much to see I don&amp;#39;t think many people could handle longer than that without becoming exhausted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;louvre3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we left, and found our Hop-on Hop-off bus. We spent the rest of the day sitting on it as it slowly took us home. The wind up top was freezing so we had to go downstairs, which was shame because there was so many cool sights. We went up to the top again sometimes for the particularly interesting sections, like the Champs-Élysées and Eiffel Tower, but the cold was pretty offputting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The roundabout around the Arc de Triomphe was really crazy, you can understand why it&amp;#39;s not possible to get insurance there, it seemed like madness but there wasn&amp;#39;t any accidents so there must be a fairly good system in place. I am pretty sure that unlike a normal roundabout, people coming onto the roundabout have right-of-way rather than people on the roundabout because we were constantly stopping to let people on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Rome it had been great because everything was so close together, but the bus tour of Paris took forevor. By the time we finally got to stop near our Hostel we were freezing and starving. At the stop was a subway so we went in there. They have 15cm and 30cm subs. We were cut. How come Australia has to use the term &amp;quot;footlong&amp;quot; if they don&amp;#39;t. It was also interesting to see how different the food was even though it was the same meals. The chicken fillet looked nothing like our one, and it had vegies and stuff cooked into it as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the hostel we had a second dinner in the form of some Fish and Chips, and a few drinks before heading upstairs to get some sleep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On DAY 2 we waited at our hostel which was the starting point of the free walking tour. Like the Munich one, the tour was great and we learnt a lot about the city. On the river Seine we got to see some police going scuba diving looking for bodies. Our guide informed us that they were probably checking for suiciders as the bridge is a popular place for that sort of thing. We also got to see a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Invader_%28artist%29&quot;&gt;space invader mosiac&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I had seen a couple in Bern as well, but apperently Paris was the first place where they started appearing, because the guy that does it is French. His most famous one is on the Hollywood sign in America.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;spaceinvaders.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We crossed the Pont Neuf (New Bridge) which is the oldest bridge in Paris - it was new at the time of naming obviously. We were shown a spot from the Bourne Identity, and a place which is haunted. We also crossed another bridge later on that had more of the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Love_padlocks&quot;&gt;padlocks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on it. It&amp;#39;s kind of funny that the government comes through twice a year with bolt cutters to remove them all - kind of defeats the point for people doing it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we had been to the Louvre and some other places that I have probably forgotten, Jenny (our guide) led us to this random place too see some modern art. It was probably the first modern art I have seen that I actually found cool. We were told that the artist beleives that art should be something that you don&amp;#39;t have to pay for, you find unexpectedly and makes you have an oppinion about it (good or bad).... and it was definitetly that. It was called &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.telegraph.co.uk&#x2F;culture&#x2F;art&#x2F;4613494&#x2F;Public-art.html?image=1&quot;&gt;Les Deux Plateaux&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and stripey art dude I salute you for making it, I enjoyed it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;modernart.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we went through the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tuileries_Garden&quot;&gt;Tuileries Gardens&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and walked down towards the obelisk and then across the river again to a war museum where the body of Napoleon is kept. Then after the tour some of us went to a french cafe and had some &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Croque-monsieur&quot;&gt;Croquemonsieur&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and wine.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After our french cafe experience, Rachael and I left and went to see the Eiffel Tower up close, which was kind of cool except for all the guys with machine guns and the hundreds of dodgy guys selling mintature towers. Interestinly we found out there is a single bedroom apartment at the top of the eiffel tower that the designer had installed for himself that he could take &amp;quot;friends&amp;quot; to. It would be a pretty impressive pick-up line for sure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;eiffel1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;eiffel2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;eiffel-guns.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that we rode around on the bus a bit, went inside the Cathedral Notre Dame de Paris and watched some street dancers outside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;notredame1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;notredame2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then got the bus to the Champs-Élysées in order to climb to the top of the Arc de Triomph. There was more street dancers there as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 16563098 &amp;gt;}}&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view from the top at night was spectacular and I reccomend it to everyone. I&amp;#39;m sure it is great in the day but at night the lights of the city were spectacular.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;arc1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;arc2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;arc3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-paris&#x2F;arc4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time we got the metro home instead of the bus, which made the journey much quicker. That is once we worked out where to go, we got a little bit confused. The place is like a giant maze and most of the time we had no idea where we were or how far underground.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On DAY 3 we weren&amp;#39;t quite ready to leave Paris, it was a great city. Nonetheless, we had to check out and get a train to the airport. The whole day was basically wasted, because not only do you have to spend hours waiting at the airport, our plane sat on the tarmac for about another hour before we actually took off, I have no idea why. But eventually we were off and on our way to Prague....&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
