<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Alex Guinman - Switzerland</title>
    <subtitle>Personal blog</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/switzerland/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2011-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/switzerland/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Return to Oz</title>
        <published>2011-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2011-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/return-to-oz/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/return-to-oz/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/return-to-oz/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;return-to-oz&#x2F;p1060411.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Melted Snowman&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I figured that I should probably finish off the tale of my trip to Switzerland, for the sake of completeness, even though it is now ages ago and nobody will probably read this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Years Eve was a great night, and we had an amazing &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Raclette&quot;&gt;Raclette&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; dinner at the flat. After dinner we caught the train into Zürich to see the fireworks, but even before that there was some as the people in the flat next door were letting some small ones off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The train windows were all covered in paint too. It looked like it had gone past some out-of-control party. The city was packed but the fireworks display was a bit of a let down. The fireworks don&amp;#39;t start until 12.20 so the actually midnight celebration was fairly unspectacular, although we did do traditional Russian vodka shots with Nelly&amp;#39;s family. The fireworks were good, but not as impressive as the one&amp;#39;s I saw on my first weekend at Zürifäscht.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time we got home, me and one of the other house guests were not in a good state. The first time I threw up I thought it could have been the alcohol, but it didn&amp;#39;t take long to realise that we had caught the stomach bug that the rest of the guys had caught in Austria.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my 2nd last day in Switzerland was not great, consisting of being sick and packing. On January 2nd, my last day I was feeling a lot better and was ready to go. My snowman was still standing, but had lost his nose.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long journey home didn&amp;#39;t start well with the handle on my (freaking heavy) luggage not wanting to extend. This meant that I couldn&amp;#39;t roll it along and had to drag&#x2F;carry it. I was very happy to get to the airport and check it in. I got to catch the Heidi Train again to the terminal, and get on the plane. I sat next to a lovely German guy that worked in Luzern, and spent most of the 12hour flight sleeping and watching movies. I had a very sore neck and felt terrible at the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got a little concerned when I arrived at Hong Kong because they had a illness screening set up that checked you for high temperatures as you got off the plane. I still felt a bit sick but had got well enough that I got through okay.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a long wait at Hong Kong airport, then at long last I got to board the QANTAS flight back home. I was in the exit row and it was so much better. The extra leg room did wonders and was much more enjoyable than any of the previous flights. It was a window seat as well and during the night you could see stars out the window. Then in the morning as we flew in over Cairns and the Fitzroy Basin you could see how bad the flooding was. The pilot pointed out Rockhampton as we flew over but I was on the wrong side of the plane. There was a lot of floodwater upstream though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As much as I loved Switzerland, it felt great coming back through customs and finally being back in Australia. Even little things like having to change back to using Australian currency at the pay phone felt good. As Rockhampton was &amp;quot;an island&amp;quot; as the media called it, my flight home that afternoon was cancelled, so yet more travel awaited me and at that stage I wasn&amp;#39;t sure how or when I would be able to get home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Alpamare</title>
        <published>2010-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/alpamare/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/alpamare/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/alpamare/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;alpamare&#x2F;alpamare_winter_2012_3_224x180.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Alpamare_Winter_2012_3_224x180&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I went to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.alpamare.ch&#x2F;main&#x2F;p_id&#x2F;598&#x2F;obj&#x2F;67&#x2F;nav&#x2F;598&#x2F;nav2&#x2F;598&#x2F;lang&#x2F;5.html&quot;&gt;Alpamare&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with some people staying at our flat for New Year (family of Nelly). It is basically like Wet-n-Wild except mostly indoor, which is good considering there was snow in the outdoor parts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slides were incredible fun, I enjoyed it much more than Wet-n-Wild. One slide called the Thriller was completely pitch-black for the whole way which was kind of scary the first time as the turns and drops came out of nowhere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one&amp;#39;s that were outside were crazy. The Cresta Canyon was probably one the best and started inside, then went outside WHERE IT WAS FREEZING then came back inside again at the end. The outside parts had all the mist coming off the water as well due to the temperature loss which was cool looking. There was another one called Balla Balla that took around 45 seconds, which is a long time considering how fast it was.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the slides we went to the outdoor pool, which is a strange experience considering the water is warm and yet on the sides of the pool there is snow. And the whole time this mist comes off the water due to the heat and you can&amp;#39;t see much in front of you. Being at night it gave everything a cool eery look. There was also a pool that wasn&amp;#39;t heated, and was around 5°C. Next to it was an Iodine Brine Bath which was 36°C. Jumping in and out of the two was the strangest feeling. When I jumped into the cold pool my body felt like it had erupted into goose-bumps. And then when getting back into the heated pool the water burnt a little, like your feet sometimes do in a hot shower on a cold day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was certainly an interesting experience.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and there are no photos because one of the staff yelled at me for having a camera. Apparently you aren&amp;#39;t allowed to take photos on the premises, no idea why. Maybe it is to stop pedophiles or something.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>My First Snowman</title>
        <published>2010-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/my-first-snowman/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/my-first-snowman/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/my-first-snowman/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;my-first-snowman&#x2F;p1060354.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My First Snowman&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day I tried to make a snowman but the snow was glorious powder and didn&amp;#39;t want to stick together. Today it was (according to the Internet) 1°C and the snow was starting to melt a little bit. Now that it was a bit melted I used the last chance I had before it melts away completely to attempt to make one before I go home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a snowman is HARD WORK. The process was pretty simple, just make a ball to start with then roll it around, but once it gets a bit bigger it gets REALLY HEAVY. I wanted to make it life-size so just kept going until it was too heavy to push anymore. I was pretty happy with the base so then I made another for the next part.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had pushed it up to the base, I realised something. This thing was hard to push so it was going to be really hard to lift. Attempting to lift it achieved nothing. I tried a few different things but eventually got it up on a chair... well half of it. If you look at the photos you will see that when I lifted it up the ball broke in half. In any case it was up, and I was pretty happy and exhausted. From then on it was easy again, trying to re-attach the parts that fell off and make it more round looking. You can see in the photo above the final product.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snow was already starting to melt in the afternoon, so I don&amp;#39;t think it will make it through tomorrow. Now the sun is down it&amp;#39;s a bit colder again so it least it will make it through the night. If it starts to melt tomorrow I&amp;#39;m not sure if I should wait and see how long it can last or put it out of its misery and kick it&amp;#39;s head off. I&amp;#39;m not sure if that&amp;#39;s a common thing to do over here but when it was finished I pictured someone stomping on a sandcastle and wondered if they did the same thing with snowmen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Sankt Gallen</title>
        <published>2010-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/sankt-gallen/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/sankt-gallen/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/sankt-gallen/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;sankt-gallen&#x2F;p1060279.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sankt Gallen&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I went to see the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Abbey_library_of_St._Gallen&quot;&gt;Abbey library of St. Gallen&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. You aren&amp;#39;t allowed to take photos so you will have to follow that link to see what it looks like, I didn&amp;#39;t take any of my own. The photo shown is essentially the whole library, it is tiny and is much smaller than it looks in the photo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being much smaller than I was expecting, it looked incredible. They have different books open at any one time on the display tables depending on the theme, which was music this year. They had some older transcript styles that look nothing like the music pages of today. They also had the oldest book written in the German Language. I can&amp;#39;t remember exactly but I think it was from the year 590 and you could tell it was incredibly old. The pages were falling apart and had pieces missing and holes in them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to all the old books and music scripts, there was a replica of the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;de.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Datei:St._Galler_globus_view.jpg&quot;&gt;St. Galler Globus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the original is in Zürich. Despite being pretty inaccurate (Australia was a giant blob labelled New Guinea) it had all kinds of other things such as the constellations and a climate wheel, and I imagine would have been incredibly detailed for when it was made. Obviously I wasn&amp;#39;t allowed to spin it, but playing with all the dials and wheel things would have been crazy if it was allowed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underneath the library in the basement there was another room that was part of the ticket I got, but it wasn&amp;#39;t all that exciting. Lots of fragments of statues and stuff.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual church or Abbey (picture above), was one of the better one&amp;#39;s I have seen. The roof was the same as in the library only on a massive scale. Considering how many church&amp;#39;s I&amp;#39;ve seen now it&amp;#39;s getting harder to find impressive ones, but this one is up there as one of the better ones.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked around the rest of the town for a bit after that, but there wasn&amp;#39;t anything too exciting to do or see. I had planned to wait for my Gleis7 to kick in to avoid paying the 18sFr for the train home, but it started snowing and I had been everywhere so I left after only a few hours.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old town of St. Gallen was really pretty, but nothing I hadn&amp;#39;t seen already - but it was worth the train ride just to see the library.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Weihnachten in der Schweiz</title>
        <published>2010-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/weihnachten-in-der-schweiz/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/weihnachten-in-der-schweiz/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/weihnachten-in-der-schweiz/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;weihnachten-in-der-schweiz&#x2F;p1060216.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Christmas Sled&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christmas in Switzerland did not feel like Christmas at all to me. That is not to say it wasn&amp;#39;t a great day - just that I didn&amp;#39;t do anything particularly Christmas-y. Or more specifically without having a meal with the rellies it doesn&amp;#39;t feel like a real Christmas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I did have an interesting day. I went with Roderick to Mt. Rigi, near Luzern, to try Schlitteln (sledding) for the first time. The weather wasn&amp;#39;t great and there was hardly any visibility - but at least it was a white Christmas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sledding was quite scary at first. Neither of us were really sure how to turn or break, and combined with the fact that the track was both steep and windy had us slightly concerned. Eventually we decided the best way to stop and turn was to simply dig your feet into the snow. I was wearing just normal shoes and socks so am very surprised that my feet didn&amp;#39;t fall off. They were basically submerged in snow for the entire day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we stopped trying to lean to turn and used our feet, it was much more fun, although still difficult. The snow was perfect, fairly icy on the main track but glorious powder if you strayed just a little. It meant that it was possible to get some good speed but when I failed to turn and continued off the track, I landed in soft powder.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christmas lunch was a measly hamburger which I bought at the restaurant at the top of the mountain, but having a Glühwein did have some Christmas feeling to it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last run of the day I accidentally led us on to a ski run, which was incredible fun although at one stage we did have to traipse through metre deep powder. This wasn&amp;#39;t as fun as it sounds as there was zero visibility so we had no idea where we were going and my shoes filled up yet again with snow. Once we made it back onto some firmer snow the run was insane.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took some videos which I will put up probably once I have gotten back to Australia. All in all, it was a very different Christmas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;weihnachten-in-der-schweiz&#x2F;P1060221.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Swiss Food Prices</title>
        <published>2010-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/swiss-food-prices/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/swiss-food-prices/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/swiss-food-prices/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;swiss-food-prices&#x2F;p1030269.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;SPAR Turgi&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a while back while talking to mum I said that meat was really expensive. She asked me how much it was per kilo for mince and I gave her a number off the top of my head - which she decided wasn&amp;#39;t expensive at all. But since I have a horrible memory and probably was way off with the number, I have gathered here some prices of random stuff in Switzerland for comparative purposes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and in case you were wondering, 1sFr = $1.04AUD.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These Prices are from my local shop SPAR (IGA equivalent):&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banana&amp;#39;s 2.95sFr&#x2F;kg
Gala Apple&amp;#39;s 4.60sFr&#x2F;kg
Potato&amp;#39;s 4.20sFr&#x2F;kg&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pasta 1.15sFr for 1kg (Cheapest one - there are ones much more expensive than this)
Yogurt 1.95sFr for 500g
Eggs (Euro not Swiss) 2.50sFr for 10
Napoletana Pasta Sauce 3.20sFr for 400g
Home Brand Piccante Pasta Sauce 2.95sFr for 490g
Garlic Bread 1.70sFr
Home Brand Frozen Pizza (Ham &amp;amp; Mushroom) 3.90sFr for 375g
Home Brand Corn Flakes 1.75sFr for 500g
Milk 1.45sFr for 1L&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason the largest Milk you can get is 1L. They don&amp;#39;t have 3L bottles. Also they aren&amp;#39;t called &amp;quot;Full-Cream&amp;quot; or Lite or anything like that. They are named by the fat content, so you can get either 1.5, 2.5 or 3.5% milch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sausages 15-24sFr&#x2F;kg
Chicken Breast 34sFr&#x2F;kg
Chicken Nuggets 24.58sFr&#x2F;kg
Salami 36sFr&#x2F;kg&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are prices from the Coop in Baden (Woolworths&#x2F;Coles Equivalent)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banana&amp;#39;s 2.85sFr&#x2F;kg
Gala Apple&amp;#39;s 2.40sFr&#x2F;kg
Milk 1.40sFr for 1L&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coop Milch Chocolate 2.90sFr &#x2F; 400g
Coop Nuss Chocolate 3.80sFr &#x2F; 400g&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Home Brand chocolate from Migros and Coop are actually quite good. Toblerone and Lindt are just expensive here as in Australia and taste the same.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, prices for alcohol are surprisingly cheap:
15sFr for the cheapest scotch at Aldi (Muirhead&amp;#39;s Blue Seal - 700ml)
10fr for a 10-pack of Feldschlösschen (cheap beer)
And I remember seeing Jameson Whiskey (18 Year Old) for about 30sFr.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found another post that explains &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.onebigyodel.com&#x2F;2010&#x2F;10&#x2F;dear-frau-how-much-cheaper-are-prices.html&quot;&gt;How much cheaper are prices in Germany?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; compared to Switzerland.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These prices are all just random ones I wrote down, so I&amp;#39;m sure you can find things cheaper or dearer in other places. Also take-away stuff here is MUCH more expensive than at the supermarket. For example Switzerland is the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Big_Mac_Index#Figures&quot;&gt;3rd most expensive place to buy a Big Mac&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and I remember seeing in Baden that a 6-inch subway was about $10.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So take these numbers as you will, I just wanted to have them written down so that when I say &amp;quot;Food is so expensive&amp;quot; to someone and they ask &amp;quot;How expensive?&amp;quot; I can answer with something better than &amp;quot;really expensive&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Ski Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ski-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ski-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ski-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ski-weekend&#x2F;p1050930.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ski Weekend&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this weekend was the much-anticipated IAESTE Ski Weekend.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing work on Friday, I went to Karla&amp;#39;s Goodbye Apero for a little while and then had to get a train to Les Diablerets. The journey takes 3 hours and 40 minutes, and after each subsequent train change there were more and more IAESTE peeps. At about 10 we finally got to our destination, and upon arriving to the chalet we got some Glühwein, or rather Vin Chaud because we were in the French-speaking part. It tasted different to the one I had in Zürich but it was also really nice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday night I had not got much sleep because I went to the work Christmas party in Zürich, and Friday night we stayed up late as well, considering we had to get up early the next day. I think our room was one of the first to go to bed at about 1, and I could still hear music blaring when I went to sleep. The best thing about staying in a chalet and not a hostel like all the other weekends was that we were allowed to make us much noise as we wanted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday morning we split up, and those without their own gear had to go to the rental store. I was convinced into renting a helmet for the weekend by the fact that everyone else had one, unlike in Davos where Maciek and I went without.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to get a bus from the town up to the gondola, and then headed up to the glacier. I had a pretty horrible morning as the board felt weird for some reason and I was uncomfortable with the turns. After lunch I realised that my bindings were a bit loose, and thought that maybe it was that, but wasn&amp;#39;t really sure how to fix them or where to get the tools, so I soldiered on.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before lunch we had stayed close to the restaraunt. There was only one really short red (blue) run and to use another run you had to walk (or get lots of speed to get past the flat part) over to the T-bars. After lunch we walked across, but I did two more runs and decided that it wasn&amp;#39;t me that sucked and that it was definitely the bindings. So then I had to hike back again to the restaraunt and was able to find a table where they had tools and tighten my bindings. It was instantly better, and so I was pretty annoyed that the rental company was such a failure and didn&amp;#39;t tighten them properly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ski-weekend&#x2F;P1050977.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back over to the t-bar section again and did a long blue run which was insanely fun. The resort was fairly small and was basically all blue (green) runs because the black runs were closed. But even so, I found it much better than Davos as the snow was softer and the runs more interesting. There was a bank of fresh snow on the sides of this run which allowed you to get air and land in fresh powder. I landed some of my attempts at jumps and failed hard on others but only got to do one run before it was basically time to head back up to catch the Gondola.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the flat section where you needed to un-clip, they had dog sleds, and at the end of the day the dogs pulled the sled up this massively steep hill back up to the restaurant - which was pretty crazy to see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back at the chalet, we had Fondue for dinner. The punishment for dropping the bread into the cheese was that you had to go out into the snow and make a snow angel. But nobody did that, so either nobody dropped it (unlikely) or they didn&amp;#39;t follow the rules.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chalet had really small ceilings (as seems to be the case all over Switzerland) and I hit my head several times. But not as bad as Curran, who bumped his head so hard that he started bleeding and had to go to the doctor because he got a concussion. After that I was much more careful and didn&amp;#39;t hit my head once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After dinner we had a trivia night, with drinking games in-between rounds. I had not seen a few of the games before, so I can enlighten everyone when I return with lots of new games.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since my bindings were tight now, Sunday was probably my most enjoyable day on snowboarding to date. The weather was really good (for most of the day) and the snow was reasonably fresh and so pretty soft. I headed straight over to the slope from the afternoon before, and this time managed to &lt;em&gt;mostly&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; land a 180 air. I say mostly because I landed it but didn&amp;#39;t stay upright for long afterwards. It was a good thing that I rented a helmet because my second attempt ended even worse.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things got more adventurous from there and I went to the Terrain Park with an English guy called Pete. Unlike the previous run, the terrain park was not soft snow and hurt a fair bit when I fell. The jumps weren&amp;#39;t too scary though and I managed to get a fair bit of air off them although didn&amp;#39;t try any tricks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to have a go at the grind rail, and got about half way along before jumping off. On the 2nd run, I did a wider rail and was able to make it all the way to the end and do a jump off the end. This made me a bit too cocky though I think, as I tried the thin one again immediately after it and failed epicly. Again I was glad I had rented the helmet as I hit my head pretty hard on the ice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then later still, I did another epic stack. I hit the biggest jump with tonnes of speed and without meaning to attempted to do a backflip - or at least that&amp;#39;s what I was told it looked like by Pete. I basically landed on my back so it I landed pretty hard and got the wind knocked out of me a bit. After a short breather I was okay, see the video below for footage that I took directly after (in the middle of the video somewhere). I had planned on doing the rail again but didn&amp;#39;t want to try it with the camera in my hand. We went back one more time though and I successfully made it to the end of the grind rail again, again landing the jump off the end.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 17814190 &amp;gt;}}&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went back to the nice soft runs after that and tried doing Indie grabs. All and all it was an epic day, and was a much better ski resort than Davos. The one problem that I had was that the T-bars were so long and steep that it was really quite painful by the time you go to the top of them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ski-weekend&#x2F;P1050981.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day we went back to the chalet for some hot soup and then started the long train journey home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Saint Nicholas Day</title>
        <published>2010-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/saint-nicholas-day/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/saint-nicholas-day/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/saint-nicholas-day/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;saint-nicholas-day&#x2F;p1050907.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Christmas Bread&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So apparently today is &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Saint_Nicholas#Germany&quot;&gt;Saint Nicholas Day&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and so at work we all got given an edible version of him.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Neuhausen am Rheinfall</title>
        <published>2010-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/neuhausen-am-rheinfall/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/neuhausen-am-rheinfall/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/neuhausen-am-rheinfall/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;neuhausen-am-rheinfall&#x2F;p1050814.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Falls&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So last night I went to Asako&amp;#39;s Fondue party at her house in Neuhausen. We ate lots of cheese and drank lots of beer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bram had his &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;lists.ee.ethz.ch&#x2F;p&#x2F;02-Cantus.pdf&quot;&gt;Cantus&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; books from a Belgium Party he threw during the week, so we sang some songs and watched some youtube videos for a bit, but then we moved on to Beer Pong.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve seen Beer Pong several times in American movies, but never actually played it. It started out as a kind of fun game, but then we picked it up a notch and changed it to &amp;quot;Speed Beer Pong&amp;quot; and it became much more fun. All the while cranking some JJJ.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;neuhausen-am-rheinfall&#x2F;IMG_6954_corr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I went and checked out the Rheinfall. It was a pretty impressive sight. I would like to have seen it in the Summer when there was more water, but it was still raging fairly feircly. Also because of the snow, the observation deck was closed. Snow makes everything look cool, and waterfalls are no exception.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nearby town of Schaffhausen was also cool, and today they were having a Christmas Market. Santa was there with a hooded helper lady and his donkey, and I think he might have been handing out bread to kids. It seemed a bit strange, but it&amp;#39;s definitely better than just having someone sit in a shopping centre.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;neuhausen-am-rheinfall&#x2F;p1050845-resized.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Santa and his donkey?&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best part of Schaffhausen was the Munot. It was different to any of the other castle&amp;#39;s I have been to, and there was no touristy feel to it. They had some deer living outside the castle as well, one of which had a massive antler. Actually I forgot to mention that when we went to Davos we saw a massive deer with a huge antler walking across a field as we drove past.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;neuhausen-am-rheinfall&#x2F;P1050848.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a herb garden at the Münster which was covered in snow, so looked like all the other gardens. I think it must be cool in Summer though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;neuhausen-am-rheinfall&#x2F;p1050872-resized.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Herb Garden&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing too exciting to tell, but it was a lovely area and probably one of the best Swiss towns I&amp;#39;ve been to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>More Snow!</title>
        <published>2010-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/more-snow/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/more-snow/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/more-snow/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;more-snow&#x2F;p1050734.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;More Snow&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It started snowing again this afternoon, so I was able to take a few photos while the snow was still fresh &amp;amp; unmelted, and before it got too dark. It gets dark so quickly now - it&amp;#39;s like I&amp;#39;m living in a completely different town.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Jakobshorn</title>
        <published>2010-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/jakobshorn/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/jakobshorn/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/jakobshorn/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;jakobshorn&#x2F;skiing-022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Skiing 022&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday my housemates and I went on a roadtrip to Jakobshorn in Davos. When we got to Davos we went to the rental store and I got a brand spanking new Snowboard for the day. After we had our gear we headed up a cable car, up another cable car, and then finally we were at the top of Jakobshorn (2590m).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Switzerland is a bit different to Aus&#x2F;NZ - they have a different colour scheme. Blue is Leicht (easy), Red is Mittelschwer (Intermediate) and Black is Schwer (Difficult). They don&amp;#39;t use shapes either, just the colours. So there was no double black diamonds to be conquered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But everyone was fairly inexperienced (except the Americans on the skis) so we started on the blue run. This run was long but boring. Unlike Perisher and Queenstown, they don&amp;#39;t have any trees or anything along the path to make it exciting. Just snow, snow and more snow in all directions. The run was really icy too and very painful to fall on. I didn&amp;#39;t fall too much at the start but as I started to get tired in the afternoon I was subjected to more and more pain. Veering off the run (outside the markers) it suddenly turned to powder! Yay, except on a snowboard that means that unless you balance it right you stop moving and fall over. While this doesn&amp;#39;t hurt in powder, I soon got very tired of maneuvering out of the powder back to the main path and kept inside the markers from then on. The ice was less fun and more painful but I didn&amp;#39;t have enough energy to keep attempting the powder.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that was a huge improvement on past experiences though was the lifts. They had a windshield like plastic front that you can pull down which we dubbed &amp;quot;Climate Control&amp;quot;. It was much more enjoyable than being blasted by a freezing wind. They also had benches at the top that you could sit down on and strap in your boots.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After going down the blue a few times we were ready for something different, and did a red and then a black. I must say the black was pretty disappointing. You would expect a black run in the Swiss Alps to be crazy difficult, but as there was no trees anywhere it just means that it was steeper then the other runs. Also it was very icy and hurt a lot the one time that I fell. It is still very early in the season as well, so maybe that is why everything was so icy and painful - I&amp;#39;m still sore today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lifts closed quite early and so we got the last cable car back at 4:45 and drove home. It was a great day, but I must say I thought the runs in New Zealand and Perisher were more enjoyable. I am going to Les Diablerets for an IAESTE weekend and staying in a Chalet, so the Swiss Alps still have a chance to prove me wrong. It should be great, and now I&amp;#39;ve had a bit of a warm-up snowboard hopefully there will be less stacks.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;jakobshorn&#x2F;Skiing26.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Technorama</title>
        <published>2010-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/technorama/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/technorama/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/technorama/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;technorama&#x2F;technorama.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;technorama&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday I went to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.technorama.ch&quot;&gt;Technorama&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;plus.google.com&#x2F;105054703111621531697&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Winterthur&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on an IAESTE event. It was sort of like the Swiss version of Questacon. Check out the video below for some of the random things that I filmed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 17339544 &amp;gt;}}&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lightning display was a fairly big let-down for the most part (it went for about 30mins but the only cool bits were in that video). But the Tesla coils were definitely worth the wait. After Ode to Joy they also played Smoke on the Water - the frequency is changed by increasing how many times it arcs in a second.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Mindball&quot;&gt;Mindball&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; game had me really excited when I first saw it. It was pretty impressive. Until I won about 5 games in a row so we started testing the system to see how it works. Turns out the game still runs with nobody hooked up to it and the &amp;quot;brain waves&amp;quot; are just as random.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a transparent gearbox which was pretty cool to see how it physically worked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had a electic bike set-up similar to one we designed for a group project at uni. Except we never made ours and it wasn&amp;#39;t as good. They had several different applicances hooked up so you could see how fast you needed to pedal to produce enough power for them to work. The LCD TV was suprisingly easy to power, boiling water and powering some LED floodlights was much more difficult.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also had a table full of gas in which you could see particle collisions taking place, which were like little minature explosions, was pretty impressive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a an educational and interesting day. At the end of the day we had a bloody freezing walk to the train station, and froze on the platform waiting for a train. I can understand why people don&amp;#39;t like Winter here, but so far I still love the snow :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Zürich Christmas Markets</title>
        <published>2010-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurich-2/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurich-2/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurich-2/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;zurich-2&#x2F;p1050509.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Zurich Christmas Tree&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So my cousin Kate was in town, so I went in to Zürich to say hello on Wednesday.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the train station now they have a giant Swarovski Christmas tree and some markets were open. Besides this, Zürich was as dull as usual, but it was good to have a chat to Kate. When I came back into Turgi I saw they now have Christmas lights up in the main street, which was pretty cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday the 25th November marked one month until Christmas! They now have a Christmas tree at the restraunt at work and a big one at the train station in Turgi. And they have started playing Christmas songs on the radio at the Spar.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back into Zürich to see Kate again and the turning on of the Christmas lights in Zürich. The lights looked awesome. I didn&amp;#39;t actually see them get turned on, but Kate said there was a pretty underwhelming marching band and it wasn&amp;#39;t that exciting. The lights look awesome though. The Christmas Markets were open and they were selling all kinds of Christmas ornaments and other cool stuff. It was all really expensive though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the other times I&amp;#39;ve been to Zürich it has been pretty dull, but the white Chritmas vibe was incredible. There were people singing carols, Christmas trees and lights everywhere. We went to a stall and got some mulled wine with honey. I wasn&amp;#39;t expecting it to like it, and just wanted to give it a try, but it turned out to be really nice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to the IAESTE weekly meeting for a bit, then I had to go home and get some sleep before work the next day. As we were about to leave it got really cold and was starting to rain. By the time we got to the train station it got a bit colder still - enough for it to start to snow! By the time I got to Turgi it was snowing fairly heavily - although it was still a bit watery. It was by far the best walk home from the train station watching it snow with the Christmas lights all up in the street.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning everything was covered in snow. Not very good snow, it is very patchy and icy, but the walk to work was incredible. Everything looks cooler with snow on it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Snow!</title>
        <published>2010-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-11-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/snow/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/snow/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/snow/">&lt;p&gt;It snowed today! For about 5 minutes anyway. The weather had predicted snow for today, but when I woke up in the morning I was disappointed to see that there was none. Then at work I looked out the window at one stage in the morning, and noticed IT WAS SNOWING! After a few minutes when it stopped there was no indication that it had snowed at all :( Once the clouds cleared a bit you could see the trees on the very top of the hill were snow-capped, but about 15 minutes later that was gone too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is more snow predicted on Friday. It doesn&#x27;t matter that much though as I&#x27;ll probably go into the mountains this weekend with my housemates to go snowboarding. So lots more snow to come.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Luzern</title>
        <published>2010-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-luzern/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-luzern/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/euro-trip-luzern/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-luzern&#x2F;p1050200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Luzern&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our trip to Luzern marked Rachael&amp;#39;s first journey in a double-decker train, and we got to see some Swiss countryside on the way. I originally had planned for us to go the top of Mt. Pilatus, but when I checked the site in the morning it said the cable cars weren&amp;#39;t running, so we gave up on that idea. Also for some reason my bank card wasn&amp;#39;t working, so I couldn&amp;#39;t get out anymore money so we had to make do with the amount of cash I already had on me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rachael was blown away by the snow-capped mountains that surround the city, and I must say they were quiet awesome. Having been in Switzerland for 4 months now, they have lost some of their first impact, but I can still very much appreciate the view. On the train, there was kids with placards saying &amp;quot;Run Daddy, Run&amp;quot; and it turns out that there was another marathon taking place!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We watched the marathon for a bit, as it&amp;#39;s quite interesting just how diverse a range of people competed. There were old and young, couples and groups, even a blind guy and a guy in a roman outfit, complete with shield.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I text Petr, who lives in Luzern and he came down to give us a tour of the city. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Chapel_Bridge&quot;&gt;The Kapellbrücke&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is the most famous part of the town. What is most interesting was that there was a fire a few years ago, and so now the artwork up top is now just black.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My highlight of the trip was the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Lion_Monument&quot;&gt;Lion Monument&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This was a statue that was carved into the side of a cliff. Petr said it is the &amp;quot;saddest statue in the world&amp;quot; according to some actor that he had forgotten the name of. I think it was definitely the coolest statue I have seen so far, better by far then the ones in the Louvre.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;euro-trip-luzern&#x2F;P1050204.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After this we went up to the old city wall, where you can climb the towers. Inside the tower you can see the workings of the clock, which involved a massive rock tied to a pendulum. We just so happened to be in the tower at 2:00 when the bell went off, ensuring that we will now go deaf one year earlier. Even more impressive was that daylight savings had just kicked in, and as there was no electric parts on the clock we couldn&amp;#39;t work out how it knew how many times to ring. Somebody must have gone round to all the clocks that morning to put them all forward an hour.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then made our way back to the lake to buy some food and drinks and take in the view. Rachael is a hater of beer so I thought I would get her to try some of the very different tasting varieties available in Europe, which taste wildly different to any beer I have had in Australia, and so I thought she might enjoy them. But be it wheat or tequila, Rachael likes neither. At least she gave it a go.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This basically brings us to the end of the trip. The next day I showed Rachael around Turgi, where I live and work and we walked to the nearby town of Baden, where she got to pat a sheep. Then she had to leave and I had to go back to work. It is a little sad, but at least I still have snow to look forward to... it&amp;#39;s getting colder by the day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Ice Skating in Zürich</title>
        <published>2010-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/ice-skating-in-zurich/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/ice-skating-in-zurich/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/ice-skating-in-zurich/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;ice-skating-in-zurich&#x2F;p1050253.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ice Skating&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ll take a short break from the Euro Trip story to tell you about my first time ice skating.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went into Zürich last night with a few other guys from IAESTE to go ice skating at the Dolder Ice Rink. The rink itself was so much cooler that I was expecting. Not only is it an open rink, but in the centre they had a massive lit up Christmas tree. On one side there was an ice hockey game and on the other some curling was taking place. It was a very cool set-up considering it&amp;#39;s not even Winter yet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ice skating itself was surprisingly easy. If you know how to roller-blade, you know how to ice skate. I haven&amp;#39;t done rollerblading in a long time (since the Frenchville skate nights in primary school probably) so it took me a little while until I was confident again, and stopping is a little bit different. All and all though I found it fairly easy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually we got tired of skating round in laps, and played various versions of Ice-skating tiggy. This caused me to have my only stack of the night, trying to be tricky and evade the guy that was about to tag me. On the other hand I was quite proud of my evasion skills on many other occasions in which I was able to get away from seasoned skaters. In the last half an hour or so I tried doing some tricks like spinning and stuff and was starting to make some progress before we had to leave.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The location of the actual rink is an amazing one, it&amp;#39;s on a hill looking over Zürich and the lake, and was next to this fancy hotel&#x2F;apartment thing that we were told costs $16,000 a night. The bad thing about the rink, was it is a long way from Turgi when you are coming home at midnight on a work-night, so I think next time I will find one a little closer to home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also I should mention that this afternoon I bought some roasted nuts in Baden from one of the many stalls that have started to pop up in the last month or so. They were pretty expensive but I wanted to see what the fuss was about, as they seemed to be getting a lot of business. They were quite good, they tasted a bit like Macadamia nuts, so imagine them roasted a bit and that&amp;#39;s what they tasted like. I forget what the type of nut was called, something also starting with M. Still it&amp;#39;s a pretty cool idea, more interesting than a hotdog stand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A dissapointing trip in to Zürich</title>
        <published>2010-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/a-dissapointing-trip-in-to-zurich/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/a-dissapointing-trip-in-to-zurich/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/a-dissapointing-trip-in-to-zurich/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;a-dissapointing-trip-in-to-zurich&#x2F;church-gems.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;church gems&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I went to Zürich with Anthony to &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.sackmesserkult.ch&#x2F;veranstaltungen_e.html&quot;&gt;make my own pocketknife&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at the Landesmuseum, but when we got there they told us they were totally booked up for the whole day, so we couldn&amp;#39;t :(&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we walked around the city in the rain for a bit, but nothing too exciting. There really isn&amp;#39;t too much to see in Zürich in comparison to some of the other places around. And especially when it&amp;#39;s raining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;plus.google.com&#x2F;110750135298275838032&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Grossmünster&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; did have some cool stained-glass windows though (above). Rather than just using glass they had all these cool gemstone things. It said no photography allowed, but I took some photos anyway. The view from the top of the tower was okay as well, but climbing the tower at Bern and Basel were better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end the rain got to us, so we went home early, forgoing the option of free transport after 7 with the Gleis7 and paying to go home at around 2.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Australian Outback Bar</title>
        <published>2010-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/australian-outback-bar/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/australian-outback-bar/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/australian-outback-bar/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;australian-outback-bar&#x2F;p1040450.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1040450&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to the Australian Outback Bar in Zürich tonight for the IAESTE weekly Meeting. It was both cool and disappointing. Cool in that they didn&amp;#39;t just have Fosters, they had Bundy Rum, VB and Coopers. Not cool that it was like 8sFr for a VB and 15sFr for a Rum and Coke. Also their menu had prawns listed as shrimp ...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was XXXX signs as well, but they didn&amp;#39;t sell it, which is false advertising I reckon. Asako got a burger which looked reasonably Australian, despite having no beetroot. I asked her if it tasted like home, and she said that it did, so at least they can be proud of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of Kirsty&amp;#39;s British friends came as well, one of which was a Mumford, as in the cousin of the Mumford &amp;amp; Sons, which is pretty cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a map of Australia on the ceiling that had Rockhampton shown, so I got to show everyone where it was. They were pretty impressed that it got a mention, as they didn&amp;#39;t think it would be important enough to be on a map if it only has a population of 60,000 or so.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Prost</title>
        <published>2010-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/prost/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/prost/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/prost/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;prost&#x2F;p1040438.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1040438&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night we went to Germany for some drinks for Steven&amp;#39;s birthday and also because some people are going home soon. The bar in Waldshut that Steven and I found is even better than we first thought. Not only are beers only 2€, but if you start singing happy birthday then the bartender will come over with some free Jägermeister shots. Oh and rather than stealing the beer glass, Steven ASKED if he could keep it, and they even got him a clean one to take home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the best saying to learn in each language is &amp;quot;Cheers&amp;quot;. Two important ones for Switzerland are Prost (German) and Santé (French). I haven&amp;#39;t actually heard the Italian one yet, but apperntly it&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;Salute&amp;quot;. That&amp;#39;s according to this site: &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.omniglot.com&#x2F;language&#x2F;phrases&#x2F;cheers.htm&quot;&gt;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.omniglot.com&#x2F;language&#x2F;phrases&#x2F;cheers.htm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other cool one&amp;#39;s I have learnt from IAESTE people:
Na zdraví (Czech) Kippis (Finnish) Skål (Norwegian)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anthony told me the Irish one last night as well, but I already forgot it. Possibly it was Sláinte as it says on the site. Have a look at how many different sayings they have listed for Irish. It&amp;#39;s pretty clear it&amp;#39;s not just a stereotype that they like to drink.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Hiking Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-hiking-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-hiking-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-hiking-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;P1040232.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hiking weekend began with the steepest bus ride in Europe. It really was quite steep in places, made the bus ride up to the Remarkables in New Zealand tame in comparison. Because it was only one lane the bus driver was constantly hitting the horn to let cars know we were coming round the corner. The swiss post buses have a REALLY loud and long horn tune.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then began the hiking. The first stage was about on par with the Jura weekend hike. Quite steep and energy draining but a pleasant stroll in comparison to what came later.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;lowerhike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After about an hour hike we made it to a restaurant and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Transhumance#The_Alps&quot;&gt;alpine cheese factory&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We got to see how they made the cheese, and how it is aged. To be able to market as Alpine cheese, the cows have to live and the cheese has to be made at a certain altitude (I forget what). In the winter they move everything down into the valley though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;cheese.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got to try some. It tasted like cheese.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the hiking continued, this was the hardest part of the weekend. It was incredibly steep and in many places slippery. Incredible views though. Eventually we all made it to the top - well as high as you could go without climbing gear - to the cottage that we were staying at. The only was to get supplies there is by helicopter (or by carting it up the massive hike). We had some beers when we got there and it reminded me so much of beers in Lake Tekapo on the NZ Ski Trip last year. For Comparison (&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;picasaweb.google.com&#x2F;alexguinane&#x2F;SkiTrip09#5516776164870888626&quot;&gt;NZ&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;picasaweb.google.com&#x2F;alexguinane&#x2F;IAESTEHikingWeekend#5516411549420267634&quot;&gt;Schwiez&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) Then we went down for a bit of a walk on the glacier, which was
fun although quickly turned into everyone throwing chunks of ice at each other. There was an Aussie guy from Adelaide on the glacier that took a group photo for us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;P1040181.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;P1040203.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;finalstairs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;hut.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;groupshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed the night in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;plus.google.com&#x2F;110740992425167130852&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Blüemlisalphütte&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; alpine cottage. Our room had a top and bottom bunk, but they are all joined so it&amp;#39;s about 20 mattresses up the top and 20 down the bottom so you all sleep close together. As such we got to hear some nice snoring through the night. It wasn&amp;#39;t too bad though. Also you weren&amp;#39;t allowed hiking boots inside so you had to
wear sandals. The Swiss sure love socks and sandals. I should mention that even at work you see people wearing socks and sandals. Dinner was really nice, they do pretty well for somewhere so remote. Even the beer wasn&amp;#39;t too expensive (6.50CHF for 5dl). That&amp;#39;s another thing that is stange here. They don&amp;#39;t use mL. They use cL and dL. I have no idea
why, it seems to be a Europe thing but it doesn&amp;#39;t make much sense.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;beers1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;beers2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;clogs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunset was particularly amazing, the view of the various peaks of the alps was spectacular. Once it got dark, it got really cold. But I still ventured outside with a few other keen people and we did a bit of stargazing. There was no light pollution or clouds, so you could see everything perfect. It was also interesting to see all the different constellations of the northern hemisphere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we started the long hike down the other side to Oeschinen Lake and Kandersteg. Along the way Andreas found some Edelweiss, which is apparently a really rare flower. Also on a creek there was a salamander, which was quite cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;glacier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;hikedown1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;flower1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;flower2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;salamander.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;Oeschinensee.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;Oeschinensee2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having lunch by the lake we went tobogganing! YAY! It was quite lame I thought, was way too slow and much less fun than I was expecting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More hiking down to Kandersteg, by this stage the trail was mostly meadows, so I could finally take of the Swiss Army boots I had been wearing all weekend and get some relief from the many, many blisters that had formed. Although the boots were quite heavy to carry and I had to pay close attention to where I was walking so I didn&amp;#39;t stand in
sheep poo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those of us under 25 paid for a train to Bern and then walked around for a bit while we waited for the Gleis7 to kick in. Was a great weekend, but even today (2 days later) every step is difficult and walking up stairs is horrible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-hiking-weekend&#x2F;trainhome.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hiking&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Jura Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-jura-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-jura-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-jura-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;P1040064.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been very busy lately with assignments, German lessons and traveling, so haven&amp;#39;t had time to update this in a while. On the weekend before last, I went to the Jura region, which is in the French-speaking part of Switzerland.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up, we went to the underground mills in Le Locle. They were used in the 1800s to make flour, and used the water that flowed through the cave to turn the mill. But for some strange reason Le Locle was built in the way of the river and it would often flood during the spring when the snow melted. So they bought out the mill and closed it down
because they then redirected the river away from the town and it dried it up. The mill was then used as an abattoir and the owners dumped all of the animal waste down into the caves (don&amp;#39;t know how that was allowed...). Then about 30 years ago (I think) some crazy historians decided they would take all the dumped waste out and make a museum. I have already forgotten most of the facts the tour guide told us, as it was 2 weeks ago now. There is more info here -
&lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lesmoulins.ch&#x2F;&quot;&gt;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.lesmoulins.ch&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; - but it&amp;#39;s in french. It was a fairly interesting tour though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;mill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, we jumped on a train to ?somewhere? and visited an Absinthe factory. Well on the itinerary it said it was a factory, but it was more like some guy that made lots of it in his basement and sells it. The house alone was pretty cool. It used to be a drug store, and upstairs all the old chemicals and stuff were still there in this really cool, old cabinet. We found things like Cyanide and Chloroform, but the bottles of those two were empty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;museum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then downstairs there was boxes with the herbs he uses to make the Absinth. There was 10 herbs, and one secret one that we weren&amp;#39;t allowed to see. I didn&amp;#39;t realise there was an actual absinthe plant, but there is. Also there was a one plant that you could easily smell straight away that it is what they use to make liquorice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy had been making it for 30 years or something, but it has only been legal for the last 5. Apparently the region was renown for it&amp;#39;s underground Absinth brewers, and there are still lots of them around (I guess to avoid tax).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual brewing itself was done in this steamer thing (I think with basically pure ethanol), and the end product is 75% alcohol. It is then diluted down to 55%, and the name of the product is Absinthe 55degrees.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;boiler.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then had an apèro and got to try some. It was not what I was expecting having had it only as shots. They mix it with water, and it goes all cloudy. It then tastes a bit like liquorice and doesn&amp;#39;t burn as much. It is still very strong, but actually tasted like a drink rather than a shot.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;absinth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;cheers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and we were told that the green fairy is a myth. The only difference is food colouring. The stories of hallucinations came about because the company that made the green fairy had a bad batch of really bad quality that was causing people to go a bit crazy. But not in a good way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we went to the hostel by the lake, and had a bit of a BBQ before dinner. The dinner wasn&amp;#39;t all that great and the waitress seemed pretty angry that we didn&amp;#39;t know french. The french breakfast was pretty basic too, and they have portions that are way too small.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;dinner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday was the hike up to the Creux-du-Van which was a very steep hike, but an amazing view from the top. Photo&amp;#39;s will do a better job of explaining it, so look on the Picasa web album.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;IMG_5449_corr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;P1040033.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;IMG_5441_corr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hiked down to the other side where there was a gorge, and then walked along the creek&#x2F;river for a few hours to the train station and then went home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;gorge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jura&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw my first Swiss Person give the finger at the train station, as Michael decided to run across the tracks when there was a train coming instead of using the underpass. The train driver was not happy as you can imagine so it was undertanable. Still strange that none of us had seen anyone give the finger until now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also funnny was that there was some girls at the other side of the train station dancing, that didn&amp;#39;t realise we could see them. When they turned around I waved and they ran away embarrassed. Then they decided they liked the attention after all and came back and continued. I think Petr enjoyed it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught some more delayed trains on the way home, the reputation of always being on time has been wrong nearly every train this last month, SBB needs to pick up there game.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Shopping in Germany for Food &amp; Beer</title>
        <published>2010-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/food-beer/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/food-beer/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/food-beer/">&lt;p&gt;Was kind of like a custard slice, but cheese. Quarkkuchen I think it was called&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;food-beer&#x2F;P1030803.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the shops in Germany....&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;food-beer&#x2F;P1030829.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drinking a Czech beer at the Rhein&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;food-beer&#x2F;P1030831.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;food-beer&#x2F;P1030833.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;13 Euro for 24 bottles = $18.58 AUD
And they are usually 5% alcohol or more&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;food-beer&#x2F;P1030834.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meat for the grill...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;food-beer&#x2F;P1030848.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a Czech beer that Petr had brought, was quite nice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;food-beer&#x2F;P1030855.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Three Countries Corner</title>
        <published>2010-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/three-countries-in-one-afternoon/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/three-countries-in-one-afternoon/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/three-countries-in-one-afternoon/">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday (Saturday) I went to Basel for the day and met up with some IAESTE buddies, and we explored the city.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First up was the Rathaus, which was a beautiful building with lots of murals and statues.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;three-countries-in-one-afternoon&#x2F;rathaus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up, we went to the Basel Münster, where there was a church organ performance. We only got to hear the last song but it sounded really good. The church was very nice, although not as nice as the one in Bern. One thing that it did have though was a basement with all these tombs of past bishops. And upstairs they had like a museum thing (where you couldn&amp;#39;t take photos) with lots of old books, bibles, scrolls and stuff on display under glass cases. It was really cool to see books so old, most were from like the 1400&amp;#39;s so hand-written and in Latin. Also they had crazy artwork with like gold foil and stuff. Incredible cool for books that I couldn&amp;#39;t read.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;three-countries-in-one-afternoon&#x2F;tombs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We paid 4sFr to climb the tower, and there was a very nice view from the top. I hit my head several times though because people in the past must have been very short and all the doorways were tiny. There was a bell that we waited for 15min or so for it to ring, then realised it wasn&amp;#39;t in use and we waited and had waited for nothing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;three-countries-in-one-afternoon&#x2F;narrow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;three-countries-in-one-afternoon&#x2F;roof.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then to the supermarket to buy some lunch, then back to Anthony&amp;#39;s house to eat it. After some food, we went to France and Germany! There is a monument called Three Countries Corner where the three borders meet. Besides walking across the border, didn&amp;#39;t really go into France, but we headed to Germany to grab some beer and meat for a BBQ that night. Prices in Germany are much cheaper than Switzerland, even if it is only like 1km away.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;three-countries-in-one-afternoon&#x2F;flower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Basel Border&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After shopping and some Czech beers, we returned to Switzerland and set up Anthony&amp;#39;s BBQ by the River Rhein. An amazingly tasty BBQ ensued, and the meal tasted fantastic. The beer we brought back from Germany was a keg of Wheat Beer, which I thought I had tried before but apparently not because the taste was so different to any beer I&amp;#39;d had before. It was incredibly sweet and not at all what I expect beer to taste like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;three-countries-in-one-afternoon&#x2F;bbq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the BBQ had to make a quick dash back to the train station to catch the last train back home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Zermatt Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-zermatt-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-zermatt-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-zermatt-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;Saturday I got the train to Visp to begin the IAESTE Zermatt Weekend, which very unusally for a swiss train arrived about 5 mins late. From Visp we went on a cog train up to Zermatt, which was a lovely town at the foot of the Matterhorn.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;zermatt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a cable car up to the top of the Klein Matterhorn which must be an epic ski resort in winter because they had runs open in the middle of Summer and there was a fair few people up there skiing. The side of the Matterhorn visible from up the top was covered in cloud, so we couldn&amp;#39;t see it, which sucked. The snow up the top was somewhat fresh, so we were able to make snowballs and people started putting snow down everyone&amp;#39;s back. One really cool thing is that from the top you can ski across to Italy (but you need an international ski pass).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;ski.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;grouppicture.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the top we got an elevator back down into the mountain to the ice palace. It was pretty nice but not too impressive. One thing that was just crazy was they had a display about &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Glacier_flea&quot;&gt;glacial fleas&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and a microscope to see these fleas that can live in the ice. There was a part that looked like a slide exit, but we couldn&amp;#39;t find the start of the slide so we climbed up the ice slide and found like a service room where the power boards and such were. So obviously it wasn&amp;#39;t a slide, and it wasn&amp;#39;t as easy to slide down it as it looked.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;slide.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we got the cable down below the snow line and went into the gorge. It wasn&amp;#39;t particularly exciting although the wooden walkway along the gorge was quite cool, if a bit unsafe looking.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;gorge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Saturday afternoon there was like a choir singing in the street at Zermatt, and the next morning there was a band of 5 alpine horns players which was amazing to listen to. Also on the Saturday night there was fireworks. I&amp;#39;m not sure if there was a festival on or something or if they always have things like that for the tourists but there was some sort of fun run or marathon on the Sunday morning as well, so perhaps it had something to do with that. After the fireworks on the Saturday night, we went down into the city and went to a bar which was also quite busy and fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;matterhorn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday we got a train to Brig, then a cable car up the mountain to what was clearly another ski resort (in the winter). From here we split into three groups. Option 1 was a way too easy walk, Option 2 was a medium hike around the mountain&#x2F;glacier. Option 3 was to hike up the top of one mountain peak then hike to the next mountain peak, which is what I chose because I wanted to go to the top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Map of hiking trails:
http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eggishorn.ch&#x2F;jwa&#x2F;VFS-DFA-217653-Aletsch_Arena_DF.pdf&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first peak we climbed was awesome and the hike up was really fun. It was such a strange mountain in that it was essentially just a pile of lots of small rocks, but made hiking up it a very cool experience. From here we hiked down the mountain on the other side then across and up to the peak of the next mountain Eggishorn (2926m). From here there was a magnificent view of the glacier and of the Jungfrau.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;glacier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Glacier&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this stage we had taken about an hour longer than they (IAESTE organisers) had expected it to take, and we were supposed to have met group 2 at a lake down the bottom by 3:00, when it was now 4.00 and we were still at the top. We could try and catch them up, or walk back a little bit to a chair lift and beat them back, but miss the walk past the glacier. Thinking of the stories, we went down from this peak to the bottom at the lake, or at least were supposed to but it wasn&amp;#39;t actually a path so we spent ages descending down this mountain and didn&amp;#39;t get to the path at the bottom until about 5:20.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;notapath.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last gondalla down the mountain back to Fiesch was at 6:00 and we still had to walk what we were told was 4km past the lake, through a tunnel and then to the gondalla. With only 40mins until the last trip we needed to run to make it, so I ran most of the way, so didn&amp;#39;t get a great look at the glacier but the path was beatuifal so I did stop a few times to look.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-zermatt-weekend&#x2F;glacier-bottom.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running at such a high altitude was really hard and tiring. I got to the end of the tunnel at about 5:55 so thought I had made it in time, but the cable car was nowhere to be seen once I emerged from the tunnel, and after running around the bend in the track I realised I&amp;#39;d missed it so then gave up. The view from that side of the tunnel was nowhere near as good which was a bit of a bummer, because I could have taken my time more on the other side. So I waited for a few more people to catch up and we were resigned to the fact we would have to walk down the mountain and probably would be sleeping at a train station. We talked to a local lady who walked past, who had also not realised the last car was at 6:00 until it was too late (they changed the timetable that day).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our choices were to hike down the mountain, which would take about 1.5 hours according to the local lady, or she was going to walk along the path for another 1.5 hours to the next cable car station which was open until 10. So we waited for about 20mins for the rest of group to catch up, then continued to the gondolla station because there was 3 guys ahead of me that were probably waiting there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One guy actually made it there by 6.05 or something after running non-stop for the whole 40mins which is amazing. So he made the last gondolla. But the other 2 in front of me where waiting still, as didn&amp;#39;t make it to the cable car until 6:20. Luckily for us, the guy working there had agreed to take everyone down
with him when he finished, because as well as our group there was about 10 other people (including the lady we talked to) had not made it or not known that 6.00 was the last trip. So we were really lucky and happy that we didn&amp;#39;t have to hike down, and that we didn&amp;#39;t try before checking at the cable car station.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made it in time to catch trains home, and I arrived in Turgi at about 11:50, which wasn&amp;#39;t too bad considering we thought we wouldn&amp;#39;t make it back. Most the trains we got were late, and we had to run to make the next connection at each station. I don&amp;#39;t know why there were all so late yersterday, normally trains arrive on the dot in Switzerland.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite putting sunscreen on twice during the hike, I am massively burnt all over today, as it was a really hot day yesterday and the sun was really bright. I didn&amp;#39;t think it was possible to get burnt here, after spending a few days walking round cities in the sun with no suncreen and hat and not getting burnt at all, but now I know it definitely is. It was only something like 20SPF suncreen that I could find here, so that could have had something to do with it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, a great weekend, but I would have liked some more sleep.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>007 Bungee Jump - Verzasca Dam</title>
        <published>2010-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p10301091.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;p1030109&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday afternoon I did the 007 Bungee Jump off the Verzasca Dam.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We caught a train to Tenero then hiked up towards the Dam. When I first saw it way in the background I thought - that is huge. But once we got close the nerves dissapeared and I was just excited mostly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had to wait for a fair while before we could do our jump because there was a film crew filming for a German travel show. But at least we got to see someone do the jump before any of us did it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is 220m from the platform to the ground, and the actual jump is like 180m I was told. And it is the same jump as from &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=eBq8K-Y2B4g&quot;&gt;the opening scene&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the movie Goldeneye, hence the name.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was chatting to the guy at the top of the platform and he had been living in Noosa for a while. He asks everyone how they are feeling and when I told him I wasn&amp;#39;t nervous but felt like I should be, he told me it was his first day working there to try and help me out. I assume it was a joke but you never know, I suppose it always has to be your first day once.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a looooooong way to the bottom but it didn&amp;#39;t feel like it. When I jump at first I just felt shock at not touching anything, then a feeling sort of like you get from the Giant Drop, then by the time I started to enjoy the fact that I was free-falling it was over. I think the freefall is 4 seconds, and it&amp;#39;s over way too fast to fully appreciate it. Skydiving next time for sure.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jerk of the rope was quite a shock and not as smooth as I thought it would be, but doesn&amp;#39;t hurt. I then started to think &amp;quot;Oh it&amp;#39;s over...&amp;quot; before you bounce back up again and get to experience zero-gravity at the top of the bounce where it feels like you are floating. Definitely the coolest part of the jump in my opinion. The bounce back down again you feel all the blood rush to your head, and then it&amp;#39;s pretty much over because the next couple of bounces are way smaller.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the guys yell out to pull yourself up (it&amp;#39;s surprising how well you can hear them considering how far up they are). And you have to pull on a rope to flip yourself up the right way. That bit was a little bit scary trying to work out which is the right rope to pull while upside down.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then they lower down a winch cable, pull you up and it&amp;#39;s all over.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definitely an amazing experience, and I would go again. Although it wasn&amp;#39;t quite as exhilarating as I thought it would be, and the adrenalin didn&amp;#39;t last very long afterwards. After seeing how pumped Adrian still was a few hours after I was expecting it to last longer than 5mins or so, but that&amp;#39;s about all it lasted.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some photos below, but more photos and some videos that other people took on facebook as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5 Stars.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Everyone in Aus should watch the show Review, it started a new series a few weeks ago but I can&amp;#39;t watch it from here due to the ABC blocking out people from Switzerland).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030102.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Travel show filming and jump&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030105.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030111.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;IMG_4568_corr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030117.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;007-bungee-jump-verzasca-dam&#x2F;p1030123.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Ticino Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ticino-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ticino-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-ticino-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;We caught a train from Zurich to Airolo, which took a few hours. Along the way we played Chinese Whist (what we just called hearts at Ergon) whilst going though the Swiss Alps. Some of the views were pretty cool, but there was lots of tunnels, and tunnels are boring.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Airolo we got rental bikes and started a 40km (something like that) bike ride to Biasca. It was mostly downhill through the Swiss Alps but was still tiring by the end. At lunch we stopped at Faido and there was an awesome waterfall. Continued riding along the river and huge mountains, and then another stop later at the mining exhibit. They are building a train tunnel underneath the swiss alps, and had an exhibition showing all the mining equipment and how they blow the rock up and such. Then more riding until we got to Biasca and caught the train to Lugano.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;ride0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;ride1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;ride2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;faido1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;faido2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;faido3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Lugano we were staying at a very cool Hostel, which was also a Hotel so it had a pool and lots of palm trees and other nice stuff. We went to dinner at some restaurant next to the Hostel with Astin Martin car posters all over the wall and had what looked like Fish and Chips with Veggies, but was actually chicken.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went to the shop and bought a &amp;quot;Swiss Beer&amp;quot; then went down and explored the town and lake. Looking across the lake someone thought that Italy was on the other side, so we looked it up on google maps to find that it was indeed Italy.... but then it went back into Switzerland again. Have a look on a map and it&amp;#39;s quite strange. It&amp;#39;s called an &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Enclave_and_exclave&quot;&gt;enclave&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; apparently. See &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;maps.google.ch&#x2F;maps?q=lugano&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=&amp;amp;hnear=Lugano,+Ticino&amp;amp;gl=ch&amp;amp;ei=oZJZTIPUBpeHOPePrOAI&amp;amp;ved=0CBsQ8gEwAA&amp;amp;ll=45.973583,8.9748&amp;amp;spn=0.028871,0.084543&amp;amp;z=14&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on google maps to see what I&amp;#39;m on about.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;swiss_beer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday we went out on paddle boats on the lake. Not something I would have chosen to do normally but it ended up being really fun. At first we played pirates and hi-jacked each others boats. In the process of which I lost my sunglasses into the lake, and also Ben (from Canada) broke a seat of the boat trying to throw me overboard.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boat I ended up on (not my original boat) went for a 30min paddle to the other side of the lake (but not to Italy as we were told we weren&amp;#39;t allowed to) to try and paddle under a huge fountain... which we did. And it was cold. Also really fun.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where we were paddling they were also setting up the fireworks on a boat for that night&amp;#39;s firework show (as it was Swiss National Day).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lake5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ate lunch in the park then a few of us went for a walk along the lake to see how far it went around the headland, and saw some guys jumping off a bridge. One guy was crazy and jumped off a rock that was about 3m in from the water and had to dodge all these tree branches to get though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;lakehouse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we got the funicular (like a cable car train) to the top of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Monte_San_Salvatore&quot;&gt;Monte San Salvatore&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and got a 360 view of the area. There was a fairly (there was a plaque thing from the 1800&amp;#39;s on the wall) old church at the top, which is a long way to go if you live at the bottom of the mountain (there was no houses on the way up).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;funicular1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;funicular2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;monte1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;monte2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;monte3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then back down and to an Italian Pizzeria for dinner. The pizza I got was a Calzone something which was basically just salami and cheese, but tasted very nice. They had like 3 different types of cheeses in it and it worked well. Also because it was a Calzone it was like folded in half and cooked that way, which I&amp;#39;d never heard of but looked pretty cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then fireworks afterwards, we jumped the fence to the park which was locked and watched from in there, so got to sit down and have front row seats. Was very different to the fireworks in Zurich but still incredible. Afterwards one of the boats was on fire (probably the fireworks boat) so we watched the police boats try and put it out (took them a while).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;fireworks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when it was finished it was cool to watch the lake as hundreds of boats all left at once and  you could see all the lights. They were all honking there horns and letting of their own fireworks as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next day was bungee, then swimming in the Verzasca River afterwards, which reminded me of stoney creek but was much much prettier and also way colder. There was a 13m high &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Lavertezzo&quot;&gt;bridge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that people were jumping off but I was happy jumping off a rock next to it, that was probably only 7m high.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently the water was 10m deep just below the bridge, and as we were leaving some guys started scuba diving in the water, so it must have been. The water was so clear you could still see the bottom though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;verzasca.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;verzasca2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-ticino-weekend&#x2F;verzasca3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a bus to the bottom to the mountain, a train to some other town that had a huge castle on the hill that we didn&amp;#39;t have time to look at then back to Zurich and then Turgi by about 10.30 that night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Procrastinating Like A Boss</title>
        <published>2010-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/procrastinating-like-a-boss/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/procrastinating-like-a-boss/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/procrastinating-like-a-boss/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;procrastinating-like-a-boss&#x2F;P1020706.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bridge&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I had planned to do uni work this weekend, got next to nothing done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#39;s some of the photos that were taken in the name of procrastination.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went for a walk up the mountain on the opposite side of Turgi this time.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo of me standing over a sheer cliff below looks a bit lame
when you can&amp;#39;t see the cliff...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;procrastinating-like-a-boss&#x2F;P1020803.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;procrastinating-like-a-boss&#x2F;P1020822.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;procrastinating-like-a-boss&#x2F;P1020858.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;procrastinating-like-a-boss&#x2F;P1020889.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Zürich</title>
        <published>2010-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurich/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurich/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurich/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;zurich&#x2F;p1020663-7232401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lightbulbs&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Went out to some pubs in Zürich last night.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had a very expensive rum cocktail which was nothing on just normal plain rum, some relatively cheap beers, and found some Famous Grouss, but was talked into buying a rum and orange juice thing which was okay. But I took a photo of the grous for Mr Hooper and Tommy P. The drinks were real expensive but, even for clubs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pub where we got the beers was really cool, had lightbulbs everywhere on the roof, played good music (Little Yellow Spider for example) and had a cool vibe.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we experienced some Swiss culture (I was out with a german and swiss guy) and bought a cheeseburger from McDonalds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>IAESTE Rafting Weekend</title>
        <published>2010-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-rafting-weekend/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-rafting-weekend/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/iaeste-rafting-weekend/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;dsc_1714.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rafting&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whitewater rafting was really fun, but I must say it would have to be better in Australia purely because the river we rafted down consisted of 4 degree glacial water.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After wet-suiting up, we caught a bus up into the mountains where we were told about all the safety rules and told what to do for each of the commands from our guide. Our guide &amp;quot;Dougie&amp;quot; was from NZ and quite a funny lad.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water was absolutely freezing. Our hands all went numb within a minute or so. After a few minutes it wasn&amp;#39;t so bad as you could no longer feel anything.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first rapids were quite intense and lots of fun, and by the time we had to hop out (because there was a section that is Class 5) I was used to the water. The first section was down the Black Lütschine, and we had to hop out just after this river joined with the White Lütschine, which was just awesome when they met. Something to do with the rocks that the glaciers are on, one river is white(ish) and one is black(ish - more grey) but when they meet there is a distinct colour difference down the middle of the river until they slowly merge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first leg was Class 3, and the last section was Class 4, which was just insane fun. It didn&amp;#39;t last too long though and then the last bit was just cruising down the river towards the lake. Because the water level was so high we had to limbo under a few bridges which was cool, some were like 50cm between the bottom of the bridge and the water.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all hopped out for a bit for a swim, which was fun for like 2 seconds and then just like going for a swim in ice. But being pushed by rapids felt cool, but we all hopped back in the raft as quick as we could.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up coming out into one of the lakes, which is like 850m deep according to our guide. We put our hands in the water and you could feel an immediate change in temperature once we paddled out of the way of the river mouth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where we loaded the rafts back on there was a family of swans, with the parent swans trying to attack anyone that came too close. Was amazing to see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went back to the rafting place for a free beer and some cheese.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After rafting we went back to the hostel for dinner, then to the coop (like Woolworths or Coles) to buy beer (in single cans). It feels so weird being able to drink in the street, especially as one stage there was a big group of us walking past some police with beers in hand.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then went to some lobby&#x2F;bar thing that I&amp;#39;m not really sure what it was, and there was a St.Bernard at the front. There was also a dog inside at the bar that was walking around looking for pats. Was quite strange to see.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later on we heard some loud noise and everyone stopped talking to witness some random people walk in with giant cowbells - video on Facebook. We then realised that there was a wedding going on in one of the function rooms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day we got a train up into the mountains to see a waterfall. The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tr%C3%BCmmelbach_Falls&quot;&gt;Trümmelbach Gletscherwasserfälle&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was easily one of the coolest things I&amp;#39;ve seen in my life.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is where the water comes from for the white river that joined the river we rafted, and is 2 degrees, it comes from a glacier way up above although we couldn&amp;#39;t even see it from down the bottom. I think most of it comes from the &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Jungfrau&quot;&gt;Jungfrau&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;p1020522.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;cave.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;cave_outside.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the waterfall, we went up to Mürren via cable car, and then hiked back down. It was a very cool walking track with random waterfalls the whole way down, but had very sore knees by the time I got to the bottom. It was also weird that at the bottom of the mountain it was 25 degrees, and when we hopped out of the cable car at the top it was like 17 degrees - felt like walking into air-con but outside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;jump.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;forest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;valley.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-rafting-weekend&#x2F;valley2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Ruine Stein</title>
        <published>2010-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/ruine-stein/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/ruine-stein/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/ruine-stein/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;ruine-stein&#x2F;p1020439-7646211.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;p1020439-764621&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was in Baden and noticed a cool castle-y looking thing on the top of the hill near the train station. I think it&amp;#39;s the ruins of an old castle, or maybe just a lookout tower or something.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Radio Clocks</title>
        <published>2010-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/radio-clocks/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/radio-clocks/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/radio-clocks/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;radio-clocks&#x2F;swiss_clock.png&quot; alt=&quot;swiss_clock&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that is interesting (was to me anyway) that Trevor told me is that a lot of watches here are synchronized to a pulse transmitted over the radio. He bought one and was going to try and replicate it in Australia by generating a radio signal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the cool thing was that he claimed that the clocks at the train station have the second hand speed up for the last 5 seconds, then wait at the top of the minute until the pulse, before they move again. So essentially they clock stops until it gets the radio signal, so they are always synchronized.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I was at the train station I had a look and it&amp;#39;s true. Here&amp;#39;s a video if you weren&amp;#39;t bored by this already and stopped reading.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit: Changed to public YouTube link, as I took my video down.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=lJs2R0tX_Zk&quot;&gt;Video&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and that&amp;#39;s church bells you can hear in the background. They love them here, you hear them almost constantly. I actually paid attention yesterday and they were ringing from 7pm to 7.15pm like they are in that video, not just on the hour.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Trevor&#x27;s Farewell Party</title>
        <published>2010-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/trevors-farewell-party/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/trevors-farewell-party/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/trevors-farewell-party/">&lt;p&gt;When I was introduced to everyone around the office and told them I was from Australia, they all wanted to know if I knew Trevor, because he was from Australia too. He was the very first co-op from CQU to work at ABB in Turgi, and came back after graduating, having been here for the last 9 years. But he moves back to Australia next week to work for QR, so he had farewell drinks on Thursday night. I&#x27;d never met him but thought I would drop by quickly to say hello.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good night was had, as because I had to keep the Australian stereotype intact, I wasn&#x27;t permitted to leave until we had got through all the beer he had bought. It was quite good beer actually, Badener Gold, which is brewed in Baden nearby. They were 5.2% alcohol, but was told they weren&#x27;t full-strength and that that is what they consider a standard beer here. When talking about drinks here I even discovered that one Swiss guy had tried Bundy Rum, thanks to Blake Harvey bringing some over with him at one stage.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a great night and I met some cool people and heard some cool stories. Wasn&#x27;t particularly fun getting out of bed at 7 the next day to get ready for work, as we stayed up well into the night, but I went to a training course and got a free lunch, Swiss-Army Knife and laptop bag, so it was still a good day at work.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Wanderweg</title>
        <published>2010-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/wanderweg/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/wanderweg/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/wanderweg/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;wanderweg&#x2F;p1020293-7743501.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;p1020293-774350&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve seen enough signs since being here to work out that Wanderweg means that there is a walking path this way, or the yellow diamond painted on to a tree like in the next photo. Just used google translate and the word actually translates to &amp;quot;trail&amp;quot; but I got the idea.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;wanderweg&#x2F;diamond.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So next weekend I am doing a Rafting&#x2F;Hiking weekend and it said that you need to bring hiking shoes, so yesterday I went in to the closest big shopping centre in Spreitenbach to buy some. That&amp;#39;s actually the town I ended up at after walking home after Zurich Fest.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after I bought some I decided I go for a walk up the mountain behind Turgi, as I noticed a Wanderweg sign at the train station pointing that way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was actually a really hard climb, quite steep and a very narrow path. It was quite a hot day too, so it wasn&amp;#39;t easy going. The view from the top was quite good though, as you could see all of Turgi and Brugg and see the Limmat river.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;wanderweg&#x2F;view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also some weird rocks formation things along the way, with a really big one up the top that was like a cave. Here&amp;#39;s the pictures anyways so you can look for yourself.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;wanderweg&#x2F;rocks.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;wanderweg&#x2F;cave.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Working at ABB</title>
        <published>2010-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/working-at-abb/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/working-at-abb/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/working-at-abb/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;working-at-abb&#x2F;p1020234.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ABB&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So some people weren&amp;#39;t sure if I&amp;#39;d actually started work yet, so thought I would do a post about where I&amp;#39;m working. I started on Thursday 1 July and finish on the 31 December.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I have mostly been reading about Simulink and the project I will be working on and settling in. Tomorrow and Friday I am doing a training course.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work itself seems like it will be very interesting and should be fun. ABB&amp;#39;s official language is English, so most of the documentation and stuff is in English - but they have German keyboards with the z and y keys swapped around which keeps stuffing me up, and most of the signage and news and stuff up around the office is in German.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As English is the official language, everybody speaks it pretty well, although most people seem to talk in German when they can, but will speak in English when talking to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work in the third floor of this building (although I will be working in the lab later on).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;working-at-abb&#x2F;p1020232.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The office has &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; plants in it, not plastic ones like Ergon. And I&amp;#39;m promised that I will get some dual screen monitor action soon for my laptop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;working-at-abb&#x2F;p1020227.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;working-at-abb&#x2F;p1020229.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 12.30 everybody goes to lunch at the ABB restaurant. The menu is in German, but they have the meals on display so you can see what they look like. They have a different menu each day, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;aubruecke.sv-group.ch&#x2F;de.html&quot;&gt;and put it on the net&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far the meals have been pretty nice, there was one that was pretty average. At least I get to try a different meal each day, and they are different to what you would probably get in Australia. Meat over here is expensive as, so there isn&amp;#39;t much actual meat in the meals :(&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;working-at-abb&#x2F;p1020230.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Bern</title>
        <published>2010-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/bern/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/bern/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/bern/">&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, I got a train to Bern, which is the capital city of Switzerland.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took about an hour to get there, and cost 17.50CHF for a ticket. Although that was one way, and half price. That&#x27;s because I bought a Half-Fare card for 150CHF, which gives you 50% off train tickets, and
a Gleis7 card for 99CHF that gives people under 25 free trains after 7 at night. (So I waited until 7 to get a train back).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still much cheaper and faster than travelling to Canberra.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual city itself was really cool, lots of massive and old buildings. In particular the Berner Münster was really cool, will make a separate post for that. And I somehow walked into a natural history museum, which was also cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a reasonably hot day, and there was lots of people at the public swimming pool (which is free apparently), and swimming in the river. There was also tonnes of tourists like myself, I guess because
it was a weekend.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1010981.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This house had an elevator garage-thing, and they were waiting for it to drop down so they could drive the car on top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1010989.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1010997.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1010998.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1010999.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020008.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020010.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020011.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020012.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020015.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I seriously thought the people in the below photo were real for like half a second. In fact, most the houses and buildings around here have really cool murals and stuff painted on them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020020.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was steps like this all along the river, with handrails to get in and out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020022.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020023.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was lots of people at the swimming pool, and also in the river.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This apparently is the Einstein Museum. I have no idea what that means because it isn&amp;#39;t open Sundays.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020059.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020062.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam, in response to your comment on one of the other posts, I haven&amp;#39;t tried any real Swiss chocolate yet. I&amp;#39;ve only bought stuff from the shops. They have different brands to us (and some the same) but other than that they are about the same, although definitely a bigger range. The chocolate in this shop looked amazing, but it was closed. And also probably very expensive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020065.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group of tourists on a tour....&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020068.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guy had mad-skills, and was walking along this cable tied to the bridge. Then he did it backwards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020083.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020101.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020103.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent ages looking for some free water, and ended up buying some bottled water (for like the 2nd time in my life). I read briefly on the net that you could drink from these public fountains, but was dubious about it and didn&amp;#39;t see anyone else doing it. I looked it up on the net since though and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.isyours.com&#x2F;e&#x2F;guide&#x2F;basics&#x2F;water.html&quot;&gt; apparently&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; they are all okay to drink unless there is a sign saying otherwise.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020202.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;bern&#x2F;P1020205.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Berner Münster</title>
        <published>2010-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/berner-munster/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/berner-munster/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/berner-munster/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;berner-munster&#x2F;p1020108-7504553.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Berner Münster&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While in Bern, I went inside this amazing looking church, The &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;M%C3%BCnster_of_Bern&quot;&gt;Münster of Bern&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It really looked amazing inside, and was just so huge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;berner-munster&#x2F;stainglass.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stained Glass Windows&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took me a while to work out how to get up the tower - you had to pay 4CHF then there was a little tiny door that lead up a really skinny staircase that took you to the top - but there was an amazing view of the city from the top.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The staircase was really small, and it was quite high. They added a fair bit of bars on the windows and stuff for safety, but it would have been incredibly scary building the thing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;berner-munster&#x2F;stairs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stairs&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;berner-munster&#x2F;gothic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gargoyle&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;berner-munster&#x2F;view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photo&amp;#39;s don&amp;#39;t really give it justice but I&amp;#39;m sure you can imagine what it was like. There are clearer photo&amp;#39;s on the wiki page I linked above as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Brugg</title>
        <published>2010-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/brugg/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/brugg/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/brugg/">&lt;p&gt;Time to update this blog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my big night in Zurich, I stayed home most of Saturday, but went to the next town north in the afternoon (Brugg).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a lot bigger than I expected, certainly bigger than Turgi. Had a lot more shops and stuff, but nothing too exciting. There were some cool houses along the river.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;brugg&#x2F;P1010938.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;brugg&#x2F;P1010944.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;brugg&#x2F;P1010940.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;brugg&#x2F;P1010964.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Naturhistorisches Museum der Burgergemeinde Bern</title>
        <published>2010-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/naturhistorisches-museum/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/naturhistorisches-museum/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/naturhistorisches-museum/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;naturhistorisches-museum&#x2F;P1020029.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;p1020029-707529&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whilst aimlessly walking around the city, I saw in tiny writing on the door that one building was a museum, so had a mosey inside.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There wasn&amp;#39;t anything particularly special in it, but was definitely worth looking around. It was mostly filled with life-like animal displays, which looked like they were stuffed versions of the real thing, but I&amp;#39;m not sure if they all were. It also made it hard to understand what I was looking at sometimes, when all the information was in German.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a few cool displays though.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a few skeleton&amp;#39;s and fossil&amp;#39;s which were interesting...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;naturhistorisches-museum&#x2F;P1020034.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And they had a microscope set up which you could move around and look at these eggs up-close. A really cool idea, but I didn&amp;#39;t find them much more interesting when magnified.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;naturhistorisches-museum&#x2F;P1020037.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They also had a giant ant-farm. I saw 2 that were making a break for it and had escaped, but that&amp;#39;s still a pretty good design that only 2 had escaped when all the tops are open. You couldn&amp;#39;t really see too well in the nest, and couldn&amp;#39;t see any eggs or larvae or anything. There was cabinet underneath that was locked which I assume they can open up and you can look at it on tours or something.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;naturhistorisches-museum&#x2F;P1020039.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t know what this is, but it&amp;#39;s a freaking huge, scary-looking bug that could probably take a large chunk out of you.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;naturhistorisches-museum&#x2F;P1020042.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was corridor made out of mirrors that was incredibly trippy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;naturhistorisches-museum&#x2F;P1020052.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m assuming this represents blood diamonds? They had some really cool looking rocks, with some crazy formations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;naturhistorisches-museum&#x2F;P1020054.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;naturhistorisches-museum&#x2F;P1020055.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Baden</title>
        <published>2010-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/baden/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/baden/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/baden/">&lt;p&gt;So after work on Friday I thought I would see what the closest town (Baden) is like.
It is much bigger than Turgi, with a lot of shops and stuff, it even had a McDonalds and Burger King. The buildings there are all look amazing though, and all the streets are cobblestone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;baden&#x2F;mcdonalds.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;McDonalds&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;baden&#x2F;church.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Church&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;baden&#x2F;clocktower.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clocktower&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;baden&#x2F;street-pano.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Street&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The river passes through here as well, and there was three guys jumping into it then swimming across into a calm section (before being taken away by the current). It looked really fun.
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;baden&#x2F;swimming.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swimming&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;baden&#x2F;P1010854.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Me&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Zürifäscht 2010</title>
        <published>2010-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2010-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurifascht-2010/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurifascht-2010/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2010/zurifascht-2010/">&lt;p&gt;After Baden, I headed into Zürich for Zürifäscht, which I had no idea what it was but was something to do. Basically it was like Fire in the Sky in Rockhampton, but much, much better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard about it through IAESTE (International Association for the Exchange of Students for Technical Experience ) who organised my visa, and put on trips and stuff for everyone over here on a placement.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the train I met three people in IAESTE by chance, one guy from England had even done German lessons with Quinny back when he was over here. So followed them into town and met up with some more IAESTE people, and hung out with them for the night, they were all fairly rad. Most of them are doing electrical engineering as well, so it&#x27;s sort of like a multinational EUS.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another crazy thing I didn&#x27;t realise about Switzerland is there is no law against drinking in public, so people were cracking 6-packs on the train left right and center, and everyone was drinking in the streets. Didn&#x27;t seem to cause any issues though, and even though there was millions of people in the streets everyone seemed to be having a good
time and I didn&#x27;t see any fights or anyone acting like a dickhead, which is amazing. Zürich is a beautiful city, as I&#x27;m sure you can tell from the photos below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;zurifascht-2010&#x2F;P1010902.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1010902&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;zurifascht-2010&#x2F;P1010885.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;P1010885&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more thing that is taking some getting used to is how long the daylight lasts. Being summer, I think the days lasts for 15 hours or something ridiculous. Basically I hadn&amp;#39;t seen night time here until last night. I woke up at 6 and the sun was up and it didn&amp;#39;t get dark until about 10 at night. Most of the photos below were taken after 9pm and it still felt like late afternoon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual fireworks themselves were so much better than anything I had seen in the past. Unlike in Australia, they didn&amp;#39;t just set them off randomly, it went for 30mins and was synched to music. I&amp;#39;ll try and put up a video soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;zurifascht-2010&#x2F;p1010928.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fireworks&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a massive walk through crowded streets back to the train station, there was two choices for a train that I could make out. A commuter train at 1.24 or an express train to Baden at 2.06. I didn&amp;#39;t really want to wait around for an hour for the express train, so got the commuter train, not knowing at night time they don&amp;#39;t go all the way along the line. So the train I got stopped about half way to Turgi, at Otelfinen, which was the last train of the night until 6am the next day, so I was stuck there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty tired and didn&amp;#39;t want to have to wait till morning, so started walking to Baden, hoping I would get there in time to get another train. Without really knowing where I was going, I headed in the general direction along some Swiss Countryside. At one stage I was walking past all these crops and saw two foxes run across the road. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;maps.google.com.au&#x2F;maps?f=d&amp;amp;source=s_d&amp;amp;saddr=Otelfingen+Station,+Switzerland&amp;amp;daddr=Killwangen-Spreitenbach&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=FeMa1AIds_t_ACmj1aP9TA2QRzHqIVV9SdyVdQ%3BFXzG0wIdknl_ACmrz6dzmhKQRzGICdZA82QOdw&amp;amp;mra=mr&amp;amp;dirflg=w&amp;amp;sll=47.444285,8.38068&amp;amp;sspn=0.02705,0.084543&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=47.446897,8.390808&amp;amp;spn=0.054098,0.169086&amp;amp;z=13&quot;&gt;This&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is where I actually ended up walking, which would have taken me 52mins according to google. Then luckily at the station I ended up at randomly there was a train to Turgi leaving about 2mins after I rocked up so I caught that home.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
