<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Alex Guinman - Iceland</title>
    <subtitle>Personal blog</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/iceland/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2017-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/iceland/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Final day in Iceland</title>
        <published>2017-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2017-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland/">&lt;p&gt;For our last day in Iceland we went to the Blue Lagoon Geothermal Spa. It stinks of sulphur as you come in but you get used to it after a bit. I wasn&#x27;t expecting to like it that much as it&#x27;s more Rachael&#x27;s thing, but was pretty fun.
They had a steam bath which was intense as you walk in as it&#x27;s dark and the steam is so thick you can hardly breathe. It was pretty overwhelming so we didn&#x27;t like it, but I tried it again later and it was more enjoyable. It was nice standing out in the freezing cold breeze and then going in. The main reason I liked it though was that it was in the middle of the lava fields so was a nice view from the pool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland&#x2F;bluelagoon1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Blue%20Lagoon&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland&#x2F;bluelagoon2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Blue%20Lagoon&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spa is actually next to a geothermal power station, which was cool to see with steam just pouring out of it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland&#x2F;geothermal.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Svartsengi%20Geothermal%20Power%20Station&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we just walked around the city. There was some nice parks and a lake.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland&#x2F;lake_statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went to a place for dinner that had hot soups in a cob loaf, and it was delicious.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland&#x2F;soup_bread.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Soup%20Bread&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that night, there was a jazz band at the hostel who were pretty good. Although, we didn&amp;#39;t stay too long as we had to get up really early for our flight the next morning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland&#x2F;kex_jazz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Iceland Silfra and Northern Lights</title>
        <published>2017-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2017-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland-silfra/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland-silfra/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland-silfra/">&lt;p&gt;Monday we had much nicer weather, and it was the day Rachael was most looking forward to. I showed her this &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;5adC3nc0MHI?t=2m36s&quot;&gt;Smarter Everyday Video&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; when we were planning our trip and since then snorkeling at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Silfra&quot;&gt;Silfra&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was what she was most looking forward to.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s actually part of the Þingvellir fields, so we got the bus back again. The drive and views were so much better with the sun out. We then put on our drysuits, which were pretty much like putting on a wetsuit. Rachael really struggled to get hers on, but she hadn&#x27;t used a wetsuit before either. The water actually felt really warm when you got in, the suits do an amazing job of keeping the water out (one guy in our group didn&#x27;t have a good seal and got a bit wet and had to go back to fix it though). We also bumped into Lauren and her work friends, who were diving after us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;drysuit-alex.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Drysuit&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;drysuit-rachael.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Drysuit&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snorkel was incredible, the water was incredibly clear and there was a slight current from the glacial melt that pushed you along. The water was the most vivid blue, and you could see tiny algae floating in the water.
Towards the end the cold really started to seep in, my feet, hands and face eventually went numb from the cold.
At the end of the snorkel was a small open sandy bit with ducks swimming around with us.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;dive1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;dive2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;dive3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It hurt to walk back to the car park because my toes felt like they were about to fall off.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got a joint package to also go see a lava cave. We weren&amp;#39;t expecting much I thought it would be a bit touristy, but it was in the middle of nowhere at &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;goo.gl&#x2F;maps&#x2F;fxEiqh7T9qS2&quot;&gt;Lavacave Leiđarendi&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Even from above the cave was incredible views, just lava as far as you could see in one direction and snow capped mountains behind us in the other.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;lavacave3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Lavacave%20Track&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cave tour was more adventurous then I was expecting too, with some narrow places where you had to crawl.
At one point Rachael thought she saw a finger and freaked out, but it was just a rock. The tour guide said that she  will now be part of the stories that he tells other visitors. We turned off all our lights at one point to experience the absolute darkness which was also a cool experience. There was also heaps of giant icicles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;lavacave1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Lavacave%20Entrance&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;lavacave2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Lavacave&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;lavacave-icicles.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Icicles&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far we had an absolutely incredible day, and I looked up the aurora forecast which said there would be activity that night so we booked a Northern Lights tour as well. The tour itself was a bit of a rort, the bus picked us up at 7 and then we waited just 5mins down the road for about an hour for it to get dark. They then took us about 20mins out of town but there was still a fair bit of light pollution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Issues with the tour didn&amp;#39;t matter too much because as soon as you hopped off the bus, you could see the lights faintly. Because you can&amp;#39;t see colours well at night, they don&amp;#39;t look like the photos. It just looked like a normal thin greyish cloud, but the way it danced across the sky was what made it impressive. I got a photo on my phone that captured pretty well what it looked like to the naked eye. It&amp;#39;s actually one time where it&amp;#39;s better to look through your camera...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;aurora-realistic.jpg&quot; title=&quot;What%20the%20Aurora%20looked%20like&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point early on, it came over really bright and vivid for about 60 seconds. I could actually make out pink and green colours and the way it moved across the sky looked incredible. It was extremely impressive and the guide so it was the best that it had been in about a month. It wasn&amp;#39;t as good for the rest of the night but still visible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Lauren was also in Iceland that night, they text us to say they could see it from the hottub of their AirBnB. If we&amp;#39;d had a car we would have gone further from the city and it would have been way better, but we were still pretty lucky to see it as good as we did in the short time we had in the country.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got some better photos with the camera using a long exposure (didn&amp;#39;t have a tripod so not great).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-silfra&#x2F;aurora-exposure.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Aurora%20long%20exposure&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was an excellent day, probably the best of our trip.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Iceland Golden Circle</title>
        <published>2017-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2017-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Alex Guinman
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland-golden-circle/"/>
        <id>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland-golden-circle/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/iceland-golden-circle/">&lt;p&gt;We flew in to Iceland in the afternoon and the area just looked bleak, with no trees in sight.
When we originally booked, we thought the airport was in Reykjavík itself (there is a domestic one), but Keflavik International Airport is actually about an hour bus trip from the city. The bus trip was pretty unreal, it was just a dead straight well-maintained highway with no trees and barely any other cars. Once you get closer to Reykjavík there starts to be buildings and trees, but the first part is just the middle of nowhere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed at KEX Hostel, which has a cool bar area and there was band playing when we arrived. The food in Iceland is crazy expensive and so we just bought some snacks for dinner at an expensive convenience store. We booked a Golden Circle bus tour for the next day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First stop on the tour was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;%C3%9Eingvellir&quot;&gt;Þingvellir&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; where you can see the tectonic places. It wasn&#x27;t much of a tour as they didn&#x27;t tell you that much, pretty much dropped you off and said be back on the bus in an hour (they did give a tiny bit of backstory on the drive to each stop). It was a pretty cool area but was freezing cold and starting to rain. It&#x27;s a rift valley and you can see where the tectonic plates have been pushed up out of the ground. Some scenes from Game of Thrones were filmed there also.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;Pingvellir2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;%C3%9Eingvellir&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;Pingvellir1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;%C3%9Eingvellir&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next stop was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Gullfoss&quot;&gt;Gullfloss Waterfall&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which reminded me of
&lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;neuhausen-am-rheinfall&quot;&gt;Rheinfall&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Switzerland. The weather was absolutely terrible, with icy cold wind and rain. So we had a very quick look then went into the restaurant, and got what was probably the most expensive toasted ham and cheese sandwich in the world. After warming up we went out again for another quick look. If the weather had been better I&amp;#39;m sure I would have enjoyed it a lot more.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;Gullfoss1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Gullfoss&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;Gullfoss2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Gullfoss&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last stop on the &amp;quot;circle&amp;quot;, we went to see &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Geysir&quot;&gt;Geysir&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; which is the geyser that geysers are named after. We didn&amp;#39;t see Geysir errupt, but the Strokkur geysir errupted pretty regularly. There was also a couple of small one&amp;#39;s that bubbled away that were cool. The whole place smelled of sulphur of course, and it was still raining off and on and freezing cold. Again, would have been much better if the weather was better, although it did start to clear up a bit at the end before we had to leave.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;Geysir.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Geysir&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;Strokkur.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Strokkur&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;small-geyser.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Small%20Geyser&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course once we had seen all the main sites, the sun came out and the weather became lovely. Pretty annoying, but it did make for an epic bus trip back and the views were incredible (couldn&amp;#39;t see anything on the way there really due to the rain). We also stopped at an &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.south.is&#x2F;en&#x2F;services&#x2F;the-quake-2008&quot;&gt;earthquake exhibit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at a Shopping Centre in Hveragerði which was pretty cool, the ground had literally split in half at the shopping centre in 2008, so they made a tourist attraction out of it. It also gave us a chance to buy some food at a supermarket as they have really short opening hours in Iceland and would have been closed by the time we got back.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we got back to Reykjavík we went for a walk around the city and went to the see the church on the top of the hill (Hallgrímskirkja).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;church1.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Hallgr%C3%ADmskirkja&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;church2.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Hallgr%C3%ADmskirkja&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found a place that had hot soup noodles for dinner, they didn&amp;#39;t have any tables free, so we got takeaway and ate them on the oceanfront. Was still pretty cold, but was nice with the sky cleared up and the noodles were boiling hot and tasty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;iceland-golden-circle&#x2F;dinner.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Noodles&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
