<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Alex Guinman - Young Endeavour</title>
      <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au</link>
      <description>Personal blog</description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/young-endeavour/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Final Day</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-final-day/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-final-day/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-final-day/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-final-day&#x2F;ye_groupshot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;YE_Groupshot&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning we did some harbour furls (neatly rolled up the square sails), then briefly headed out to sea so that we could come back again for all the family members on shore. We stayed up on the yards for the berthing, and fired cannon blasts as is tradition. The tradition being that by having everyone up on the yards, there is nobody to reload the cannons - and since they have already been fired the ship poses no threat.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mayor of Eden was there to great us, and we were all given certificates and posed for another group photo (above).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That afternoon was the Eden Whale Festival, which was not as exciting as I was expecting to be but gave something to do to pass the time until my bus ride home the next morning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they say, it really was an experience of a lifetime and I had a phenomenal time. I had high expectations going in but I did not to expect it to be as rewarding or enjoyable as it was. The staff were infectiously happy and I got to see a whole new part of Australia and gain a small appreciation for life on the sea. I highly recommend that everyone who has an opportunity to apply do so.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The captain put up &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youngendeavour.gov.au&#x2F;captains-log&#x2F;sydney&quot;&gt;a daily log&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well, and I found a blog post by another youth crew, &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;jesscooper.net&#x2F;2011&#x2F;11&#x2F;06&#x2F;young-endeavour&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Jess&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11  - Day 10</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-10/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-10/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-10/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day-10&#x2F;ye_photobook.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;YE_Photobook&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On our last full day, we had a half day sail with local people with disabilities. It was very rewarding, although we went out past the heads so they could see some whales (we saw several) which caused a lot of them to get seasick.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was part of the Youth Crew Theatre Crew, and we dressed up in the ship costumes and performed our nursery rhyme style shanties for the guests.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night we were tasked with creating a poster for our watch to go in the ship logs. I spent ages going through the past posters throughout the journey but couldn&amp;#39;t find Rachael, David or Katherine&amp;#39;s photos.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also got to write letters to our future selves, which will be posted to us 6 months later. Since I have been so slack with updating this blog, that letter should be only 3 months away now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 9</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day9/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day9/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day9/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day9&#x2F;pa270812.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Young Endeavour&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, every morning the staff held a morning brief. One of our command day tasks was to host our own. Rick was our Nanna, Ash gave the long winded Nav talk, and I was Salty Seadog with the help of my assistant Emma.
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day9&#x2F;morningbrief.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To show of our newly learned knot-tying skills - one task was to build a Hammock that could support the entire youth crew:
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day9&#x2F;PA270826.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When our 24 hours were up, the crew assessed how we had met each task. They deemed all tasks completed - even navigation was awarded since the wind dropped and made it pretty much impossible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a debrief of command day, and went ashore with our watch leaders to discuss whether we had met all the goals we had set ourselves at the start of the journey.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Bec&amp;#39;s 21st the day after we berthed, so we decided to throw her an early party so she could say she had a birthday party on a multimillion dollar yacht. Emma bought decorations from the IGA while we were ashore.
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day9&#x2F;P1090045.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 8</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-8/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-8/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-8/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day-8&#x2F;ye_dinner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;YE_dinner&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Day 8 was command day - the day when control of the ship was handed over to us youth crew for 24 hours. At the handover we were given a list of various tasks to complete. From easy ones (don&amp;#39;t get sunburnt) to hard one&amp;#39;s (our navigation challenge).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of our first tasks was to get a photo taken with all crew members aloft. I am on the topsail yard (middle), second from the left - next to the other Alex.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the tasks assigned was chef. Amy, Scott and Tammy did an excellent job in the galley and lived up to the expectations Squiz had set for an excellent meal. Even the staff were impressed, and said that often the command day meals are less than amazing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our major task was our navigation challenge. We were given 4 checkpoints that we had to pass through. We had a start&#x2F;finish line and had a set time frame (I think it was like 14 hours or something) to pass through all the checkpoints and return to the Twofold Bay finish line. We started out in the afternoon heading for the northern-most checkpoint - but the wind was not on our side and we had to keep tacking the ship to avoid sailing into the mainland. As nighttime fell, we realized people needed sleep and so we would have to change our course to something that required less tacking. That and being able to see the lights on the mainland getting closer and closer while you wait for everyone to get ready to tack is a bit concerning.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My watch, &amp;quot;Munchy Watch&amp;quot;, was on first watch and so everyone went down below to bed after we had changed our course for the bottom checkpoint, doing the course in reverse. As watch officer, I was in charge of letting the person on the helm know which bearing to steer and updating our position on the map (below) to ensure we were heading in the right direction (and updating our bearing accordingly if we weren&amp;#39;t).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see on the map below, we made good progress at first but had to start steering inland (away from the checkpoint) as we got closer as there was a fishing ship in our path. One of our objectives was to keep 1 knot away from all obstacles, and it got pretty hairy with the fishing ship while still trying to maintain an roughly accurate course.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of our watch the wind dropped off completely and was very erratic, making it even more difficult. When we handed over to the next watch, we did a two-watch tack and turned the ship northwards and towards the checkpoint. From there they could continue sailing north to the next two checkpoint before turning back home in the morning to meet our deadline.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were pretty confident that we would be nearing the finish line when we woke up with a job well done. As you can see on the map though the next two watches didn&amp;#39;t go to plan. They just continued sailing south basically due to bad weather and wind.
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day-8&#x2F;MEMO0003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kylie on the bridge for morning watch:
&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day-8&#x2F;PA270780.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;
The red light ensures you don&amp;#39;t lose your night vision but can still read the map.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did made it back to the bay the next morning before the deadline... with only 2&#x2F;4 checkpoints completed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 7</title>
          <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-7/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-7/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-7/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day-7&#x2F;ye_fellin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;YE Fell In&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weather was slightly improved once we got to the mainland, and were protected by Twofold Bay. We went ashore at Eden and went to visit the Eden Whale Museum, where they keep the skeleton of &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Old_Tom_%28killer_whale%29&quot;&gt;Old Tom&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a killer whale that helped the fishermen lure in other whales and would share in the kill - eating the tongue and leaving the rest for the fishermen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Somehow at the Dock waiting to get taken back to the ship I fell in the harbour, causing much amusement for everyone present.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That afternoon we had elections for Command Day - the 24 hours in which the youth crew is given full control over the ship. We got everyone to nominate for the positions they wanted, had a silent vote for each position. I was elected watch officer for &amp;quot;Munchy Watch&amp;quot;. Munchy being the nickname of Captain Damien before he was the captain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the elections we had a movie night, and we were shown a black and white video about sailing that was truly incredible footage. Probably we had more respect for what we were seeing as we were on a tall ship at the time, but it truly was some incredible footage and insane weather that they sailed through. At one point the captain (who narrates it) mentions two of the guys on screen that were lost overboard a few days later, and moves on like it was nothing. I will probably track it down in a few years to watch again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irving Johnson (film); &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Peking_%28ship%29&quot;&gt;Around Cape Horn&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 6</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day6/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day6/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day6/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day6&#x2F;p1080981.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Storm Cloud Rolling In&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a pretty chilled morning sailing on the sea, with a descent speed and good weather. After dinner this awesome looking cloud came.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out awesome looking clouds like that mean there is a storm coming and we got smashed by some pretty intense weather and had to bring a lot of our sails down.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;{{&amp;lt; vimeo 31721183 &amp;gt;}}&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that taking that video I got to climb to the topgallant yard to tie the gaskets (fold up the square sails), and while up there saw what was either a sun fish or manta ray come up next to the ship. It was huge but you wouldn&amp;#39;t have been able to see it on deck. Climbing during the storm was not as scary as I originally thought it would be, and if fact was a lot of fun. Despite being the highest, the topgallant is actually a fairly small sail so Matt and I had no trouble doing the sea furl, but the guys working on the topsail really struggled and took ages to get it tied up.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the poor weather we changed course and headed in towards Eden so that we could Anchor again, but we were still a fair way out at sea. We (white watch) had morning shift, so we went to bed pretty early and it was quite hard to get to sleep due to the massive rocking of the ship. During our watch we got pounded by waves and the wind had picked up to 40 knots. I got to take the helm for about an hour and it was quite an experience steering the ship during a storm and the intense weather. In the early morning we did a one-watch wear and while I was up at the bow of the ship heaving in the tacking lines it was an intense experience because the waves were breaking over the deck. I had to clip in and got absolutely and repeatedly drenched as the waves smashed over the ship.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was probably one of the highlights of the trip for me, and despite the weather being rough as guts and making it almost impossible to sleep due to the rocking of the ships it was immense fun. I was especially impressed by Kristy who was our staff watch officer for the night, who remained cheery for our entire watch, even though she went off every now and then to spew over the side of the ship.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 5</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-5/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-5/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-5/">&lt;p&gt;The previous night we had an anchor watch instead of our normal 4-hour shift in which only 3 people were on watch, and only for an hour so as to keep an eye on the boat and perform rounds.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we had sail theory, and were told the purpose of each of the sails and how they affect the ship&#x27;s movement. We spent the afternoon sailing around the bay, whilst watching all the nearby humpback whales. They were lots of them and they were all pretty eager to flips and slap the water, we didn&#x27;t get close to impressiveness as the whale in Sydney but was still an excellent afternoon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we weighed anchor (or &quot;wanker&quot; as the staff called it, much like they shorten topsail to &quot;tpsol&quot; but funnier) and set sail back out to sea. This time the seasickness barely effected me at all, although not everyone was as lucky and there was still a few people that started throwing up again. Mostly though everyone had finally got their &quot;sea legs&quot;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night on watch we had a team building exercise and had to put up the storm sail without instructions from Paul (we were allowed to ask 3 questions). I&#x27;m not sure how the other teams went, but I think we did pretty poorly. In the end we did get it set, and funnily enough a storm looked to be approaching as we were doing the task and the wind picked up a great deal.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 4</title>
          <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day4/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day4/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day4/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day4&#x2F;p1080943.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Jervis Bay&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the guts shift from 12-4 in the morning. It is difficult to navigate at night when there is no land in sight and lights just come out of nowhere. When you are on watch you have a watch officer (Dion from the staff crew was ours), someone on the helm, lookouts looking for lights&#x2F;hazards and the rest of the watch is just there in case something needs to happen with the sails. Every hour someone does rounds, checking the ship, recording weather details and going down below to check the generators in the engine room and the fridges.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During our watch we spotted a light in the distance, and so we learned how to tell what kind of ship it was from the lights that they display, and you can also determine which way they are facing to get an idea of their direction. As it got closer we were able to make out more lights and worked out that it was a cargo ship, which we could confirm on the ship&amp;#39;s radar.   The radar also informed us we were on a collision course, so we altered our course to avoid them. Dion called them up on the ship radio as well, as they decided that they would change course to avoid us as well, moving back into our path.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was incredible just how quick it went from being a single speck of light in the distance to a massive ship in front of us, and a real eye opener to how dangerous it would be if you didn&amp;#39;t have watches running and people looking out for dangers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After we handed over the watch, we went back to bed, waking up in the morning as we were coming in to Jervis Bay. &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Jervis_Bay_Territory&quot;&gt;Jervis Bay Territory&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a navy training area, and not actually part of NSW. I was not aware that there was another territory besides ACT and NT. The beaches were beautiful with island-white sand that makes that horrible squeaking noise when you walk. We went ashore so that people could &amp;quot;hug a tree&amp;quot;, which we were informed was the only proven cure for sea sickness besides death.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rick was in charge of hosting beach activities, and we had a few games of dodge ball and a round of beach flags. There was another Alex on the boat besides myself, referred to as &amp;quot;Hippy Alex&amp;quot; who showed some incredible moves in the final round of beach flags to get both flags and take out everyone else in the race.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lesson for today was &amp;quot;rules of the road&amp;quot; and Dion went into some more detail about who has right of way and what the various lights mean on boats, and explained why we had a &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Port_and_starboard#Right-of-way_for_other_vessels&quot;&gt;red light on the port side and a green on the starboard&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we anchored on the other side of the bay, and the crew declared &amp;quot;the pool was open&amp;quot;, which meant we were able to use the boat&amp;#39;s rope swing and go swimming. Red Watch Leader Guv demonstrated how to do a back-flip off the rope, and I had a failed attempt that was photographed below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day4&#x2F;PA230384.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were told it was much easier to do a normal back-flip just off a flat platform, so I had a go off the bowsprit and nailed it first go after some more pointers from Guv. The trick we were told is to tilt your head back, like you are looking into the sky and continue looking back, which will cause your body to flip automatically as you go. Mick had a go later on where he looked over his shoulder instead, which resulted in a sort of back-flip with a twist, but didn&amp;#39;t really work so well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night we had a BBQ on the deck for dinner followed by a performance of our 3-way chats. In the morning we were given 2 other crew to team up with and learn various facts about and that night we had to do an introduction of one of the two in the first person, as well as act out charades for their favourite movie. I was with Jake and Kylie, and learned that Jake has broken bones on 8 different occasions and played for the Australian water polo team, and that Kylie wants to chase the endless winter and move to Canada to teach snowboarding. Some people really surprised me in that they gave quite hilarious and entertaining performances when in normal conversations they were completely different people. Other people just had terrible memories.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 3</title>
          <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-3/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-3/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-3/">&lt;p&gt;We were on morning watch and everyone was still pretty depressed and sick. I had another go on the helm and found it much easier second time round. Those of us that felt up to it (Elke, Rob and I - Scott despite being fine the night before was probably the sickest in the morning) climbed up with Paul to watch the sunrise.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after our watch we changed course, heading south towards Jervis Bay and instantly I felt better as we were no longer working against the swell and the rocking wasn&#x27;t as severe. I was able to go down below and have lunch and unlike the previous meals most people ate. There was still a few people that were pretty sick but most people had there sea legs by this stage and were cheery again.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we had a lecture from our Nav Matt about navigation skills.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After dinner, those of us from White Watch went pretty much straight to bed as tonight we had &quot;The Guts&quot; which is the watch from 12 -4.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 2</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-2/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-2/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day-2/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day-2&#x2F;ye_sydneyship.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;YE_sydneyship&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First thing every morning we were woken by a song being played over the loudspeaker. On most days we had to come up on deck and do laps of the ship until everyone was up. Then every morning there is a morning brief.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At morning brief we heard the plan for the day from our Sailmaster Kristy, a quote from Captain Damien, an always long talk from the Navigator Matt about our current position and where we were going, as well as a visit from Nanna (Mick the Engineer in a dress and wig)  who raided the berths for clothes&#x2F;stuff left on the floor (and not neatly put away in our lockers like they are meant to be) to be shown off to everyone.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rick was from the navy and on a suitability test, which is pretty much the greatest job interview ever. He started the first half of the journey as a youth crew like us, then about half way switched to a staff role and started running events. Every day nanna would somehow find something of his, even though he made sure it was all put away and even went as far as keeping it hidden in another room (in which case they brought up his Thomas the Tank Engine pillowcase up instead.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Salty Seadog (Watch Office Dion) would then tell us the story behind one of the nautical terms used on the ship and finish with a pirate saying. The explanations from Salty became more and more ellaborate each day, with the rest of the staff dressing up and acting out the stories. The term for the first brief was &amp;quot;SHIT&amp;quot;. Swearing was not permitted on board, with the exception of shit, which salty explained why. It was an old nautical term that stood for Store High In Transit, and was used on crates of fertilizer to ensure that they weren&amp;#39;t stored below deck where the fumes would make it difficult for people to breathe. Like most of the stories Salty told us, this &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Shit#Etymology&quot;&gt;isn&amp;#39;t actually true&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After morning brief, nanna would teach us all a new shanty which we would have to copy. Despite being sea-themed they were essentially just nursery rhymes with different words.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning we learnt line skills, and how to handle lines and sheets (ropes) safely and put turns on to the pins and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Cleat_(nautical)&quot;&gt;cleats&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Learning the nautical terms for everything on the ship was also something we practiced, so we could beat the other watches at the upcoming rope races.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon we did some mainies in the harbour, as we learned how to set and furl the sails and &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Tack_(sailing)&quot;&gt;tack&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the ship. One of the youth crew was feeling sick so we waited around for her to go ashore and see a doctor before she was came back okay and we finally got to leave the harbour.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we left the heads it immediately got rougher and some of the girls started to get seasick. As we were preparing to tack the ship someone spotted a whale and so we all stopped what we were doing. Then nobody could see it so we got ready again and just as we were about to heave we saw it again and it did a massive flip right next to the ship. Talking to the crew afterwards they said that they had never seen one do a full 360 degree rotation, nor a whale get so close to the ship, so we were pretty lucky.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up on deck I had no signs of sea-sickness although I was finding it difficult to walk straight with the rocking of the ship, the lean of the ship was much more than I was expecting it to be (by the end of the trip we found out that the conditions on that first day were excellent and it was nothing). White watch was first up for dinner so we went down below to eat some nachos.  By the time I had got my harness of I was starting to feel a bit nauseous and lining up for food I realised that might not be the best idea and headed back up deck before I spewed. As I stepped off the ladder and the breeze hit my face I felt better instantly.  I didn&amp;#39;t much fancy heading back down below so settled on a banana for dinner. Bananas and apples were kept up on deck in lockers and this was at a point where bananas were $18&#x2F;kg or so so it was pretty lavish. We were told bananas were good to eat when you are seasick, because unlike most foods they taste the same coming up as they do going down. Eating the banana made me sick even though I was up on deck.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first watch was that afternoon&amp;#39;s dog watch and so we learnt how to steer the ship. Or at least Scott, Elke and I did, the rest of our watch was busy clipped on to the side of the ship being sick.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being on the helm (steering) was surprisingly difficult. Because the ship is so large and heavy, there is a large delay in turning the wheel and the ship actually turning. There is also a whole new set of nautical speak to learn when working out where to steer, relative to the wind (full-and-by) or on a compass course.  I got to see my first sunset over sea, as eventually we got out far enough that there was nothing else in sight, just water in all directions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night was a horrible night&amp;#39;s sleep, with the rocking of the boat meaning and the seasickness meaning I didn&amp;#39;t really sleep at all. Paul told us the trick to sleeping with seasickness was getting ready for bed as quick as possible and shutting your eyes so you don&amp;#39;t become disoriented. This worked as far as I felt much better but the rocking was still to new for me to be able to actually sleep, especially with the changes of watch every few hours. We were on morning watch and so scheduled to be woken at 4am.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>V18&#x2F;11 - Day 1</title>
          <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day1/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day1/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2011/v1811-day1/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day1&#x2F;2011-10-19-13-07-14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;First look at the Young Endeavour&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent the morning exploring Sydney, but after getting very fed up caring a 12kg backpack around decided to head towards the Gardens Point Navy Base early, which was our point of departure. My first impression of the boat was that it was a lot smaller than I was expecting.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I was a few hours early, I spent some boring time waiting and eventually ran into Lauren who was also on the youth crew. She ended up traveling to Canberra as well, and so was funnily enough the last person I saw as well as the first.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually more and more people arrived and then we were allowed on board. We were shown where to put our bags down below and then came back up on deck for some speeches by the staff and a farewell to the family watching. Two of the youth crew worked for and had been sponsored by Hungry Jacks and so &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Jack_Cowin&quot;&gt;the owner&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was on board as well - he would be a very rich man.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was quite late by the time we actually set sail, or rather left with the ship&amp;#39;s engines. We didn&amp;#39;t get far though as we were staying in the bay overnight, and so had a magnificent view of the sunset over the Sydney Harbour as we anchored across from Taronga Zoo.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2011&#x2F;v1811-day1&#x2F;P1080929.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the journey we were split up into 3 watches (Red, White and Blue) and I was in White Watch. We spent the evening getting to know the other members of our watch, and talking to our Watch Leader Paul about our expectations for the journey and what we wanted to get out of it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had dinner as prepared by the ship chef Squiz and it was pretty amazing. The food for the whole trip was excellent and there was usually a few choices as to what meals were on offer each day.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night we went through the safety for climbing aloft, put on our harnesses and got to climb to the Topgallant &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Yard_(sailing)&quot;&gt;Yard&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; while the ship wasn&amp;#39;t moving (the highest one - 33m above the water). As I was one of the first to go, we were sitting on the yard for a fair while waiting for the rest of the watch to climb up, which despite the incredible view wasn&amp;#39;t the most relaxing position. Despite finding the climb easy, I was not looking forward to doing it while the ship was moving (although by the time I climbed in rough seas it wasn&amp;#39;t an issue).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
