<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Alex Guinman - Northern Ireland</title>
      <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au</link>
      <description>Personal blog</description>
      <generator>Zola</generator>
      <language>en</language>
      <atom:link href="https://alex.guinman.id.au/tags/northern-ireland/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
      <item>
          <title>Last Day in Ireland</title>
          <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/channel/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/channel/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/channel/">&lt;p&gt;So we left Dublin early in the morning to avoid the traffic and made our way up north again to visit Slane.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were told by Matt and Angela to visit a hill with a view of the countryside and was a perfect sunny day so the views were spectacular.
There was a freezing cold wind though, so we didn&#x27;t stay long.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;channel&#x2F;slane-hill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;channel&#x2F;cows.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went past Slane Castle but it was closed for renovations.
Nearby is the site of Newgrange, but we got there really early and it didn&amp;#39;t open until 9:30 so we just looked over the hedge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;channel&#x2F;newgrange.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a quick detour to drive along the ocean and then we were back across the Northern Ireland border.
There is no real signage other then the speed limits suddenly change from km&#x2F;h to miles&#x2F;h.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still had a few hours with the car before we had to return it, so we went up to look at Cavehill which is a mountain that inspired Gullivers Travels as apparently it looks like a giant and people hiking up its face inspired the author. Belfast Castle is up the top, so we stopped there for lunch.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;channel&#x2F;belfast-castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We then hiked up the giant&amp;#39;s face and there was a great view of Belfast harbour. It was crazy windy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;channel&#x2F;cavehill2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;channel&#x2F;cavehill3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We returned the car then went to our AirBnB. The next morning we got the ferry across the channel.
It was more like a cruise ship then a ferry, with several restaurants, games rooms and a cinema. But it was only a short trip so we just read and went on top to look at Scotland as we came in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;channel&#x2F;cruise2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;channel&#x2F;cruise.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Irish Coast</title>
          <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/northern-ireland/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/northern-ireland/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/northern-ireland/">&lt;p&gt;So we picked up a car and headed north to drive along the coast, which was great.
There wasn&#x27;t many cars and heaps of awesome scenery. We didn&#x27;t go to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.discovernorthernireland.com&#x2F;The-Dark-Hedges-Armoy-Ballymoney-P27502&quot;&gt;The Dark Hedges&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; but saw some cool roads like it in the area.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first tourist stop was Carrick-a-Rede Rope Bridge. The rope bridge itself was pretty tame and unexciting (the lady crossing behind us was freaking out), but the coastal scenery was pretty epic. The water was super clear and blue and we had great weather.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;bridge1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;bridge2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next stop was the Giant&amp;#39;s Causeway which was also great. The rocks reminded me of the rocks along the Tabletop Mountain hike back home. The name seemed a bit silly at first as I couldn&amp;#39;t really picture how it was a causeway but we hiked up the hill at the end and it did look like a caved in bridge across the channel.
Apparently there is a similar site on the other side in Scotland, formed when the islands were together millions of years ago.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;causeway1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;causeway2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We booked a random airBnB in the town of Sligo as it was on the way south.
The next drive was also incredible, especially the last bit with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Benbulbin&quot;&gt;a big mountain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; shrouded in cloud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sligo town looked fun, we went in for a dinner at a pub recommended by our host, The Swagman. We were a bit slow in working out it was an Australian theme pub but eventually cottoned on to why the menu had so many foods we liked, and they had VB cans on the wall. I had a really tasty steak sandwhich.
The house we stayed at was beatiful and in a nice neighbourhood, we didn&amp;#39;t actually want to leave the next morning and wished we weren&amp;#39;t just passing through.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More driving south, this time through some lava fields called &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;The_Burren&quot;&gt;the Burren&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and some nice seaside towns.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;burren.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cliffs of Moher were incredible. Reminded me of &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2010&#x2F;iaeste-jura-weekend&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Jura&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in Switzerland but with ocean at the bottom.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;moher5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;moher6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;moher2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;moher1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could leave the tourist centre and walk up further past farmland where there was no fence.
It was a really great walk and views, Rachael really didn&amp;#39;t like that there was no fence though and kept freaking out it would give way.
She wouldn&amp;#39;t even take a photo of me anywhere near the edge, but at least I didn&amp;#39;t put my legs over it like some people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;moher3.jpg&quot; title=&quot;no%20fence&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;moher4.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Rachael%20keeping%20well%20away%20from%20the%20edge%20-%20where%20the%20photo%20was%20taken&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then yet more driving, but this time we went on the highway rather then the scenic way which was a lot faster.
We stopped at a castle on the way but too expensive so didn&amp;#39;t go in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;northern-ireland&#x2F;bunratty.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drove through Limerick and there was a soccer game on, so there was lots of traffic and people out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the amount of driving we did, it&amp;#39;s a pretty small country and before we knew it where at Dublin!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
      <item>
          <title>Belfast</title>
          <pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
          <author>Alex Guinman</author>
          <link>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/belfast/</link>
          <guid>https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/belfast/</guid>
          <description xml:base="https://alex.guinman.id.au/posts/2017/belfast/">&lt;p&gt;We flew into Belfast and got a bus in to the city and then to check into our hostel. Everywhere was really booked out in Belfast, and we were only able to book a 10 person dorm at &lt;a href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.vagabondsbelfast.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Vagabonds&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We found an awesome burrito place for lunch that was a cross between subway and GyG. It was good being back in an English speaking country again, although Rachael still really struggled to understand what we were ordering with the accent which was pretty funny.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hostel was really cool, but hopefully we never have to book a 10 bed dorm again. Luckily we went to bed pretty early before everyone else got back, because apparently one guy was snoring so loud that one of the other girls didn&#x27;t sleep (and told us at breakfast she wanted to murder him). I woke up in the morning and heard him, and probably wouldn&#x27;t have been able to sleep hearing it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;belfast&#x2F;hostel.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Hostel%20breakfast%20area&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The living area was really cool, and we spoke to some other people in the hostel about where to visit while we were in Ireland. We didn&amp;#39;t think we would have time to get to the Cliffs of Moher but were persuaded it was worth the drive.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My phone plan had expired, but since we were back in the UK we could head into the city to renew it. The shopping centre had a really cool viewing platform where you could see the city, although the weather wasn&amp;#39;t great for visibility.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did a free walking tour later on in the morning, starting at City Hall. They had a display of all the people who died on the titanic, including two people that were under stolen identities. I didn&amp;#39;t actually realise the Titanic was built there and they also had a whole &amp;#39;Titanic Experience&amp;#39; which is a apparently great visit (similar to the Vasa Museum I guess) but we didn&amp;#39;t have time to visit.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next on the tour, we went to the Europa hotel, which was bombed repeatedly by the IRA. It was opposite a really fancy bar, which joined on to another bar called Fibber&amp;#39;s McGee (like in Toowoomba).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Albert_Memorial_Clock,_Belfast&quot;&gt;leaning clock&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Salmon_of_Knowledge&quot;&gt;wise salmon&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and I think four &amp;#39;oldest bar in Belfast&amp;#39;. There was a really cool part of town with lots of pubs and restaurants that was a bit hipster with lots of cool graffiti.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;belfast&#x2F;alley.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Alley&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a really good tour, and Belfast was a surprisingly cool city and a shame we didn&amp;#39;t more time there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For lunch we had some amazing burgers, they like their make your own takeaway and this was like a Grill&amp;#39;d crossed with subway. They tasted amazing and were really cheap.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a free Ulster museum and botanical gardens near(ish) our hostel so we went there in the afternoon. The museum had a display of the period table with all the actual elements (stable ones at least). And we learnt a bit about &amp;#39;the troubles&amp;#39; and the IRA as this wasn&amp;#39;t covered in the tour we did. The gardens were nice too.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;belfast&#x2F;greenhouse.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Botanical%20Gardens%20Greenhouse&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the pubs in town had cool names, like Filthy McNasty and The Dirty Onion. Our tour guide talked up going to see some Irish Music at Fitzy&amp;#39;s, and there was a local duo of girls playing that were really good, but it was more American&#x2F;Pop&#x2F;Country then Irish.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;alex.guinman.id.au&#x2F;posts&#x2F;2017&#x2F;belfast&#x2F;fitzys.jpg&quot; title=&quot;Fitzy&amp;#x27;s&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning we picked up a hire car to explore the country side.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</description>
      </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
